DM: [sighs] So,
DM: I can start with mirrors.
DM: I don't know who's departing the ship first of the four of you.
Unknown: Where's everybody going?
Wellby: Let's set the scene. Maybe we're in, uh,
Wellby: in-
DM: Port Ventray
Wellby: ... Ventray.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: [coughs] Inside the room that you built.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Like, do a few mirrors first, and then do the-
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: The ding.
DM: 'Cause there's mirrors, like, while you're-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... still protecting the rangers in Isengai and stuff.
Seeker: Oh, can you grab all of our [mumbles] things?
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: I mean, the first, the only mirror I was really-
DM: Is the Ash Queen.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But I'm sure there's others, but I just don't have any in my head other than that.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: That's, that's Kenzo with-
Wellby: That may have to stay outside the room [laughs].
Kenzo: Yeah. That's Kenzo with the ladder and, uh, Seeker Six.
Unknown: Seven.
Wellby: Seven. [laughs] Ah, no, I'll come join you
Unknown: guys.
Delwath: Kenzo's putting staff down.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Ken- Kenzo's gonna put his staff down.
Seeker: That can become the, the ship's tree.
DM: Right.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: And there's docks and staff in the tree.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's like the same size as this boy.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo will come inside, and he'll take his flaming fist out, too.
Kenzo: We're, we're not coming in anymore. We're just hanging out.
Unknown: Yeah, no. I think we're good, though.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Yeah, Delwath's sword can come inside, too.
Kenzo: Oh, it's so cute. There's pl- there's a pie and pumpkins in there.
Unknown: I know.
Unknown: What, what a, what a lovely little...
Unknown: That's so lovely.
DM: Delwath made a little feast.
DM: So while you're helping the rangers get the perimeter established around Isengai as the ash has stopped falling,
DM: one evening you take a moment to pull the mirror of the past out of your porthole,
DM: and
DM: take the pile of ash that Kenzo or Seeker, I forget who,
DM: grabbed from the decaying elemental as you killed her in the plane of Limbo, and hold it up to the mirror.
DM: And as you do, you see
DM: an image.
DM: For, for a minute, it's hard to track.
DM: It's,
DM: uh...
DM: Too many things are changing at once.
DM: But as you watch, it seems to be recognizably a
DM: land of some sort.
DM: Like, there's...
DM: It's not, it's clearly not Limbo.
DM: It's like a, a place where there is a sky and a ground, but the ground is constantly shifting.
DM: And you can see the same person, the, the Queen of Ash, um, running along a,
DM: like up a slope with
DM: beside her
DM: the sta- the, the dark fire guy with the scimitar, who you only saw in statue form.
Unknown: The scimitar we should bring down here.
DM: And the scimitar might not tell you much different than what you're, what currently seeing.
Delwath: Um, but we could do the bag.
Wellby: Should identify it, too.
DM: You could do the bag. Um-
Seeker: We should also identify the scimitar.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [coughs] The...
DM: So they're running up a hill, um, and as they run, the, the hill is sort of folding behind them and starting to form into this giant wave of earth.
DM: And
DM: the land shifts as they go, and it crashes into a
DM: what seems like it's maybe a city made out of metal.
DM: Um-
Wellby: Ooh
DM: ... there's like walls of metal, uh, forming a, a, a perimeter, but there's not much else you can see because the earth crashes into it and tumbles through it and
DM: mixes it up, up- upturning and overturning the wall itself.
DM: And the two figures running, the ash and the flame, stand for a moment in the center of what once was a city.
DM: The
DM: flame creature, uh, blazes, is dark fire, but blazes to light for a moment as he holds up the scimitar and makes a few slashing motions.
DM: And as he does, the air opens up in a gap.
DM: And the world folds, and the remains of the city, like, tumble through the gap, and all that's left here is
DM: a
DM: valley of ash.
Unknown: Whoa.
DM: And the scene shifts, and you see now, uh, the two of them running along a, running from something, running down,
DM: following the path of a river, which seems much more stable.
DM: And behind them is a light
DM: that's moving incredibly fast.
DM: Like, it's almost like the afterimage of an explosion that's rushing along this river, catching up to them.
DM: And as it moves on the river, it's actually sort of shaping and forming the river in a strange inversion of cause and effect.
DM: You can see the river ahead of them before it's formed, but the light is forming the river once it gets to them.
DM: And then they get grabbed and tumbled.
DM: The,
DM: uh, scattered, the flame,
DM: dark flame, and the Ash Queen of Frozen Lightning
DM: suddenly [whooshes]
DM: ... fragmented into 10,000 fragments scattered across
DM: what now seems to be Limbo.
DM: And for a long time the mirror is dark.
DM: You see, like, the, an occasional flicker of,
DM: uh, frozen lightning or
DM: sh- you know, cold ash freezing into a sculpture.
DM: [coughs] And then this, the fli- flickers and the pulses get longer.
DM: You're clearly in Limbo now as you see from a s- a twisted perspective looking like at a 45-degree angle down at what seems to be
DM: a massive line of a thundercloud just drifting across space.
DM: And as it does, everywhere it passes,
DM: uh, lightning flashes, and as it flashes things freeze
DM: or burst into flames or turn into a wave of sound that blows across as a discordant note until this thundercloud
DM: passes across something you can't see because it's beneath the wave of ash.
DM: But as it passes across something it immediately solidifies back into a person,
DM: The Queen of Ash,
DM: and that's where the mirror vision ends.
Unknown: We should go to Mack Innis.
Unknown: What's that?
Delwath: We should go to Mack Innis.
Seeker: So did she come from there? Is that the implication?
Delwath: No, I think the implication is she came...
Delwath: Before time she was in a war with Mack Innis that she lost.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: And then she was in Limbo, and then the Relic of Order...
Delwath: She... Remember we already knew that
Delwath: she, that the Relic of Order
Delwath: would be possessed by some being of Limbo when they crossed paths randomly.
Delwath: So, like, this Relic that she, that we used
Kenzo: The orb thing?
Unknown: The orb thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Recreated her when it crossed paths with her.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: So she was just like a random storm front in Limbo with no mind or consciousness until she hit-
Delwath: Right, 'cause she lost the war. The Relic-
Delwath: She, she was destroyed at the end of the war basically.
Delwath: Whatever the war was.
Delwath: It didn't seem like a real one, I mean, like a weird cause and effect war that's taking place without linear time.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: [coughs]
Wellby: That suggests she's back to just being a random-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... storm front in Limbo again.
Delwath: Yeah. I think we, we ran away from the storm front in Limbo that she became.
Unknown: Oh, sure. Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: I like that, not created or destroyed, we just sort of transformed her.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Back into chaos.
DM: But the v- the gloss is that the storm fronts have no...
DM: It's like they have no will, they have no purpose, they're just like random chaos, so they, there's, they'd never, like, think to invade the material plane or anything.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: They just drift across chaos as sort of random events, and it's only when they're solidified into a consciousness that they can have a goal.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: And so The Queen of Ash was trying to break into the material plane.
DM: Yeah, that's what Ry and her were fighting about for 30 years.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: And the...
Unknown: Why was she doing that?
DM: Uh, maybe she w- sh- maybe she didn't realize it was the material plane.
DM: She thought she was gonna, like, go back and refight this war or something.
Delwath: Although, wait, she wasn't...
Delwath: It's unclear what she was before.
Delwath: So that implies Limbo was created during the Rivening.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Was created what?
Delwath: During the Rivening, the, like, the time again.
DM: The event that created...
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: [coughs]
DM: It's metaphysically, metaphysically interesting.
DM: Yes. [laughs]
Seeker: So wait, the thing that turned her from a storm into was the Relic.
DM: Was the Relic.
Unknown: The Relic.
Unknown: The thing that we just destroyed?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: The thing Seeker used to-
DM: The thing Seeker used to move the planes and in the process destroyed it.
Unknown: Oh, that Relic.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: We should probably like go back to Limbo at some point and maybe try and f- I guess
Delwath: there's probably other ones of these drifting around.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Sort of like a Sisyphean task probably trying to clear Limbo of whatever's a Relic.
Wellby: Maybe that's all that Limbo is.
Wellby: I mean, maybe there isn't a Limbo apart from just, like, the chaos of random storms that-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... could potentially coalesce into consciousnesses, but.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Does anybody else have a mirror?
Kenzo: Uh, well, I was, I said one earlier that I just forgot.
Kenzo: You guys remember what I just said, like, over at the table?
Unknown: I was like
Seeker: Well, we should identify the other...
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Let's identify these.
DM: So the scimitar is a Scimitar of Dark Flame.
DM: It's a plus two weapon.
DM: Uh, it does, hmm, I forget, some number of extra, uh, fire damage, and then once per short or long rest you can immolate
DM: yourself. You take 6d6 fire damage but you get an extra action.
Unknown: What?
DM: [laughs] So it's pretty strong if you are immune to fire damage.
Unknown: [coughs]
Delwath: Um, that's inter- Like, is that you get one extra action?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Not a continual 6d6.
DM: No, no, just the turn you immolate yourself.
Unknown: Just that, that one time.
Unknown: So we should bring that to Plane of Fire.
Unknown: We should bring that to Plane of Fire.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Oh my God, we should bring that to Plane of Fire for sure, yeah.
Seeker: Um, somebody needed it.
DM: [coughs] Cool.
Seeker: And I have these elemental rings so I could...
Kenzo: That's just resistance though, right?
Unknown: Uh, so-
DM: Yeah, so you'd be-
Unknown: Like-
DM: You'd take half of 6d6.
Unknown: If.
Unknown: Which is not a crazy amount.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I was considering swapping for Tasha's maybe before the Frank encounter.
DM: Oh, if you were immune to fire then it would be pretty strong actually
Kenzo: Wait, there was a... I, I just said something that I was like, oh, we should-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... we should-
Unknown: I remember you saying something
DM: Well, you said the Heartroot, but you already looked at the Heartroot.
Unknown: Oh, the cistern.
DM: The cistern.
Unknown: The cistern.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Thank you. Yeah, let's do that.
Kenzo: Let- let's learn about the history of the cistern.
Seeker: Well, it was created for the Heartroot, right?
DM: Mm.
Kenzo: Yeah, they said it, it, it seemed like it could have been before the...
Unknown: Oh, no, not before the Heartroot.
Delwath: No, it predated Isengay-
Unknown: P-
Unknown: ... the city.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Ooh.
Unknown: So,
DM: uh, you've seen this story of the Heartroot, and so now you, again, before you leave Isengay, you take the, the mirror down to the cistern below the city.
DM: And actually, the, it's, the rangers have been doing a lot of work, like clearing things out while you've been sort of guarding the perimeter.
Unknown: But also,
DM: as you go down there, Kenzo, some of the stone now is embedded with these, like, filaments of the Heartroot.
DM: Like, it's growing new pillars up-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... to the ceiling.
Unknown: Oh, and by the way-
DM: We should-
Kenzo: ... the whole time that the...
Kenzo: As soon as... Like, when Kenzo first, like, puts the Heartroot into the cistern, and it's like-
Unknown: Ah
Kenzo: ... Kenzo basically, unless there's like other essential duties or things happening, is just hanging out in the...
Kenzo: Like, just hanging out-
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... with the Heartroot and just sort of like
Kenzo: observing, helping if nece- and is just, like, all vibes with the Heartroot, and just, you know.
Delwath: You should ask it for a key when we leave.
Kenzo: I already have a key from it.
Unknown: Oh, you already have a key.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: No, but I, this, I want this also to be my lair.
Kenzo: Like, anytime I come back here I can come and,
Unknown: you know-
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: You know
DM: Anywhere the Heartroot is-
Unknown: My, my lair
DM: ... is your lair.
Kenzo: Yeah, my lair.
DM: Yes. Um, so the first thing you see in the mirror when you hold it up to the cistern is a small sort of green shoot of a root crawling through some dirt,
DM: and water rushing along behind it, um, reaching around, sort of grabbing, grasping.
DM: And then more roots spring out, um, like the little glowing filamentous, um, kind of...
DM: The Heart, right, the Heartroot has like regular roots and then it has those like glowing filamentous,
DM: you know, the fungal part.
DM: So it's like a little root reaches through and then more
DM: of these things go, and then they start
DM: touching the dirt and pushing it away, and more water begins to flood in and flood in.
DM: And the dirt begins to, um,
DM: grow and compact and shift.
DM: And you watch in the mirror over, it's like a sped up version of time as water begins to flow again, sort of eroding, slowly beginning to erode
DM: out a chamber.
DM: And then
DM: being channeled, being pushed, like every time one of these little filamentous roots reaches out, water flows along behind it, following it to form a channel.
DM: And over the course of,
DM: it's hard to say how much time, decades, centuries, probably not millennia, as you watch in the mirror, like the Heartroot itself slowly begins to excavate
DM: this cavern.
DM: And then once there's this big clear area, you see first just a, a lake, like an underground lake like 400 feet across,
DM: filled with this perfectly clear, still, greenish-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... water. Like, not a, not like an algal bloom green, like a clear, pure green.
DM: And then slowly you see columns of stone begin to grow up out from the center of the water-
Unknown: Ooh
DM: ... forming these twisting spirals.
DM: And then roots grow along the ceiling, and more roots grow up from the, from the columns of stone and begin to sprout out through the soil above it.
DM: And you watch over the course of another few centuries as the Heartroot grows itself a lair.
Kenzo: Whoa. Is it biomineralizing or something?
DM: It's biomineralizing.
DM: It's like your, it's like your bioconcrete.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Wow.
DM: That's where I got the idea.
Unknown: Really?
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: No way.
Unknown: That's awesome.
Kenzo: That's going, that's on my PhD student.
Unknown: She's gonna love that.
DM: The Heartroot was like all Ken's, uh, Kong research vibes, 'cause it-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Like you are the one who got me into the, like, trees talking to the, each other.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Oh, that's sick.
DM: And I was like it, it has to have created something under Isengay.
DM: What should have created? Oh, bioconcrete.
Unknown: Oh, that's cool.
Unknown: Awesome.
Unknown: I love it. I love it.
Kenzo: Just trying to figure out how to thematically connect the Heartroot to the Orchard Keeper.
Kenzo: That's gonna be part of it. Now Ken's gotta figure that out.
Unknown: Anyways, something like that.
DM: So the Heartroot, I mean, this was long before Isengay.
DM: It grew itself a lair, and then
DM: people discovered it and it helped them.
DM: But this was its original home, like along the bank of the Isthros River,
DM: where it just created a structure it thought was beautiful.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: And now it's beginning the slow process of repair.
Kenzo: And the, the whole thing that happened with Limbo that happened here, why did it happen here?
DM: 'Cause Shemhat,
DM: Isengay was a central piece of the m- of the arm- of the defense against Shemhat-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... and he dropped the plague there.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: So the plague was all Limbo magic-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... 'cause Shemhat was the
Delwath: He was trying to d- Like we were organizing, I think,
Unknown: like-
DM: It's all 'cause it was Barrel's home
Delwath: ... Barrel came from Isengay.
DM: Yeah.
DM: It was like the heart of the ranger organization.
Unknown: Ooh.
Delwath: And I don't, I mean, I don't know, remember in high school, but you could imagine Shemhat dropping it as an attack and then-
DM: Well, it was, in high school it was supposed to cut off
DM: what was then Rohan and Sambara-
Unknown: Sambara, right
DM: ... because the Dunmari armies were-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... coming to try and relieve the Sambaran armies
DM: And dropping the plague in between them or cut them off.
Delwath: I remember the plague in high school vaguely.
Delwath: Like, I remember being panicked about it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We like... Bro, we like...
Delwath: There was like skeleton. There was all kinds of mad stuff.
DM: Yeah, yeah. You try, 'cause you were trying to get-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... from Chardin to Sambara.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And you rode through Dunmar, and you rode through the plague.
DM: But that's... So that's what...
DM: So Shemut dropped the plague in Isengai.
DM: Then when Shemut died, the places that...
DM: That was where most of Shemut's magic was actually concentrated.
DM: Not where Shemut was, but maintaining the plague.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And so that's where the wound wrecked.
Kenzo: Got it, and that was also what started corrupting the Heartwood?
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, presumably the Heartwood was being corrupted even before Shemut died- Yeah ...
Kenzo: from the plague. Yeah, yeah. But-
Kenzo: Just because of the plague, yeah
DM: ... but that's, so that was- That was six month, I mean- Right ...
DM: plague or whatever ... but then the rangers realized what was happening.
DM: W- when the plague struck, some of them managed to escape with a fragment of the Heartwood.
Kenzo: And take some of the Heartwood with them.
Kenzo: Got it.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Got it. Got it.
DM: And then the rest of the Heartwood eventually got corrupted into the ooze when,
Unknown: when-
Unknown: When the-
DM: ... when Rye knocked more of Limbo back into the material plane.
Unknown: Got it. Damn.
Kenzo: Crazy. [sighs] It's a pretty crazy plot.
Unknown: Cool.
Kenzo: Anything else we want to look at in the mirror?
Kenzo: Do you want to look at the, uh, deck of cards or the, the game in the-
DM: Bag? Sure, why not?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So the, the, the bag, you can't...
Unknown: You can just-
Unknown: No, just the bag
DM: ... you can't pick something out of it without it, it affecting things.
DM: [coughs] So you probably don't want to actually establish stuff, but you can look at the bag itself.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Let's do that.
DM: The, uh, the bag,
Unknown: uh,
Unknown: uh... Hmm.
DM: I'm actually not sure where the bag comes from.
Kenzo: It's okay. We can come, we can-
Delwath: We can come back to it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You can think about it. Well, I know where the things in the bag come from.
DM: Uh-huh. Trying to figure out how the bag fits in, though.
Kenzo: We can decide later.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Is there anything else we want to show it?
Unknown: Anything historically?
Wellby: Is there anything left in party treasure that we haven't...
Delwath: I mean, there's tons of stuff that we- Which was- ...
DM: like, were interested in a year ago, but we don't know how- Right [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Delwath: ... much it matters at this point.
Delwath: Some of like Agato's random things and, like...
Kenzo: We're gonna be hoarders soon.
Unknown: We are. [laughs] Soon?
Unknown: We're already hoarders.
DM: You can always come back to mirror stuff.
DM: We can always do a mirror thing at the beginning of other stuff, so...
DM: But I don't think there's anything in the mirror that you haven't
DM: [coughs] left that would reveal anything interesting about
DM: plot lines that have been resolved.
DM: I think there's just, like, random bits of history mostly.
Kenzo: What about the efreet?
Delwath: I mean, we never, like... We had, like, these plans to, like, look at all this car and treasure.
DM: Right. There's all the treasure from Frankendous as well.
Unknown: But that seems...
Delwath: I'd rather, like, does... That seems s- Like, that would be better to, like, have a little bit more runway to make up than- Yeah, yeah ...
Unknown: like, I don't want to, like-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Unknown: ... I don't want to, like-
Wellby: If we go do a car thing, like-
Delwath: ... recreate all the stuff from her car.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: There's no point. Similarly, I sort of feel like the efreet, like, let's just- Let's leave it ...
Wellby: keep in the bank, and if- Yeah, yeah ...
DM: we go after Frank car, we can get it back. Oh, the efreet I actually have notes on.
DM: Yeah. I need to get my computer if you look at that, but...
Delwath: I'm, I, I'm more interested in NPCs than I are other stuff.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. And I'm actually really interested in what Kenzo-
Delwath: Is gonna do ... is gonna do as now basically...
Delwath: Are you gonna recreate the Mockers? I mean, Kenzo is, like, the geopolitical master of Talgar now.
Delwath: [laughs] You have, like, Chardin.
Delwath: You have Isengai.
Delwath: You kind of have Dunmar.
Kenzo: I had not thought about that. I had not thought about that.
Kenzo: I, I was mostly, like, kind of mostly...
Kenzo: Now I'm mostly excited about, uh, being, uh, the orp- the Orchard Keeper's apprentice.
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: So that's kind of-
Delwath: ... I actually think from a, if we want to run a sequel in 1750 Talgar, having Kenzo not be the puppet master of everything- Right.
Unknown: Makes sense ... is probably better.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So, so-
Kenzo: Well, Kenzo will be the Orchard Keeper. He's gonna be the Orchard Keeper.
DM: Well, we'll intersperse NPCs, but who leaves the ship first?
Unknown: Well, should we have, should we have a-
Unknown: Maybe, maybe you're talking.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You can role play a, as you're leaving the,
Unknown: uh,
DM: Karawa after having left the monks of Bishma there.
Kenzo: It's where it all started.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: How long has it been? 18 months?
DM: So it's... By this point, it's gonna be, like, November 1749, and we started in
DM: March 1747.
Unknown: So it's been what?
Unknown: No, 17...
DM: No, March 1748.
DM: So it's been- 18 months ... 18 months.
Kenzo: Dude, all of this happened in 18 months.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: We've been playing this campaign for five years real time, and it's been 18 months of play.
Delwath: Yeah. But, but we only played three hours of every two weeks.
Delwath: Yeah. So, like, in terms of actual hours, it's been- Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... yeah. It's like 138 sessions.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: So
DM: that's still like, like 400 h- at least 400 hours.
DM: Damn. 'Cause some of those sessions are, like, five hour ones like this.
DM: Yeah. Yeah. Actually 139 if I count the e- epilogue as a separate session.
Wellby: Karawa's where the mesa is with the temple inside.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. It's been-
Wellby: So maybe we should go back to, like, that inn that we first started at.
Unknown: Ikrum's. Ikrum's.
Unknown: Ikrum's.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Sitting around the table at Ikrum's.
Delwath: Yeah. Let's do that. Except, except for the flying castle part, though.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: Well, and also, we don't need to get dropped off anywhere.
Kenzo: Um, Trekking, uh, Seeker will just teleport us wherever we want to go.
Unknown: That's true.
Kenzo: There's no need to be dropped off
Wellby: Who we had to bring the monster?
Unknown: Well, we might want-
Wellby: Huh? We had to bring the monster.
Unknown: We had to bring the monster.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. But now that we're here.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know, so I'm just saying, we c-
Seeker: We can, and we can take our time with it, you know?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Actually, now that we are here, Kenzo would go and visit the,
Kenzo: the, the, that temple place that's inside the, the mesa.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: More like the mesa. Isn't the mesa...
Unknown: The mesa's like-
DM: The mesa's like the body of Shakun.
Kenzo: Yeah. The me- mesa's like some sentient thing.
Kenzo: Anyways, not... You and I almost, you almost became like a Bish- Bishma dude, or, or a thing.
Unknown: We all-
Unknown: Or Shakun
Delwath: ... got attuned to Shakun, but then-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... three of the... All of us forgot it except you.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. But you, you went all the way to the end, but then d- chose not to die.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Of Bishma.
Unknown: For Bishma.
Unknown: Over Bishma.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Okay. But not at Shakun.
Delwath: No, Shakun we, like, we were all connected to, right?
Delwath: 'Cause we, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... we, like, the shadow people followed us in and, like, killed all the Shakun Nystai, like half of them.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Delwath: There was a lot of bad stuff there.
Seeker: And the temple of Shakun was older than the mesa that it's carved out of.
DM: Yeah, because the mesa was the body of a goddess and keeps renewing itself.
Seeker: That was the answer to that puzzle, which I never figured out.
Unknown: So the temple was
Unknown: fixed in form.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And the mesa itself kept-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... growing new stone every year.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Oh. Should we, uh, should we, like, role-play in character, like, inside the inn?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Ah.
Wellby: Where to now for each of us?
Unknown: I never liked it. It was...
Unknown: I'm glad to be done with that.
Seeker: I always thought I'd be like my old friend,
Unknown: Ulfgar.
Unknown: You know, the,
Unknown: the one, uh-
Kenzo: In Chortan
Unknown: ... always,
Seeker: always studying and writing, giving lectures.
Unknown: I thought maybe I'd
Seeker: attain some modest renown someday, perhaps begin writing volumes of my great treatise, but now I'm not so sure.
Kenzo: Philos- Philosopher's Guild?
Unknown: With what I've seen,
Unknown: there's something about
Seeker: the university setting that just doesn't quite satisfy.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Those people haven't been where I've been.
Seeker: They haven't seen things the way I have, but the Philosopher's Guild
Seeker: might have access to places and ideas that
Seeker: are not available elsewhere.
Wellby: They seem like they're kind of weird.
Unknown: They seem interesting and weird.
Wellby: You know, just no offense.
Wellby: In- interesting, that's right.
Wellby: Interesting.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Meta game, um, if they are really dragons, you now have been a dragon, so.
Unknown: That's right.
Unknown: It'll buy them,
Unknown: so pretty good.
Wellby: To Tolan then for you?
Unknown: I think so.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Not the Circle Island?
Seeker: Perhaps through the Philosopher's Guild I could,
Unknown: uh,
Seeker: raise some funds for a project.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
Seeker: Because the, the forge there...
DM: I mean, that's how you make Vindasharna fly through planes-
Unknown: Mm
Unknown: ... is the forge-
Unknown: Should we, um-
DM: ... on the circular island
Delwath: ... should we visit Dimitar before we, uh...
DM: And you have, like, dozens of weird, rare metals from that forge.
DM: You just have to figure out how to use them.
Delwath: I mean, also, like-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... wouldn't Dimitar give us some of his 100 billion gold coins?
Delwath: We have like-
Wellby: Would he?
Unknown: Maybe.
Wellby: Dimitar, Dimitar would charge us to see him.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] No, Dimitar's not giving you...
DM: He's a... Dimitar is immortal now.
Wellby: That's true.
DM: You're not getting any money from him.
Wellby: We told-
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Because an immortal being will have an infinite need for wealth.
Unknown: Exactly.
Delwath: [laughs] We did take a fairly significant chunk of wealth from
Unknown: The Horde, though.
DM: Literally exactly his logic.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: So does, does Seeker wanna use the resources of the Philosopher's Guild to help with this massive project of fitting the sky ship for interplanetary travel, or should we go
Unknown: do that first?
Seeker: Does he think he can do... Does he think he can do it on his own?
Kenzo: With Phadrig's help.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, [coughs] you, you've seen the structure of the multiverse in perfect detail now.
Unknown: So true.
Unknown: It shouldn't be that hard to...
DM: I mean, this would be Seeker's opinion.
Unknown: It shouldn't be that hard to figure out how to-
Kenzo: It's, uh, Seeker's supremely overconfident about very specific things.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: So it's like the idea of, like, making a multiverse, like, ship, like, should be done by next Tuesday, right?
DM: But, like, you've, you've, you've, like, moved planes.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: So it's a simpler problem to move Vindasharna through planes.
Unknown: That's right.
Unknown: Well, in that case,
Seeker: before I enter the guild, or I should say submit my application-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: ... there's one last thing to do.
Seeker: Refit the ship and go find my brother.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: How long will it take to refit the ship, do you think?
Unknown: I mean, it's, uh-
Unknown: Several months
Unknown: probably.
Unknown: I would...
DM: Seeker might optimistically estimate it as several months, but in your heart you know it's probably at least a year.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Several months
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Yeah, we, we all understand what that means, Seeker.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Hmm. Did we want to do NPCs too, or should we, should we-
DM: Yeah.
DM: I-
Unknown: I mean, we can do this first and then do it.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: We can do it first. Sorry.
DM: Do this first. Do your...
DM: Do... I don't want to interrupt your conversation.
DM: I've got a, I've got a few NPCs that are important for various reasons, and then whoever you want to hear about.
Seeker: Okay. What do you think you'll do, Kenzo?
Unknown: [sighs] Well,
Kenzo: I made some promises, so I gotta go fulfill those.
Kenzo: Yeah, first things first, I wanna take a little break.
Kenzo: We all need a little vacation, so,
Kenzo: uh, now that we've seen so much of the world,
Kenzo: definitely don't wanna go back to Chardin quite yet, but, uh...
Kenzo: Where, where was the place? 'Cause I promised I would go-
Unknown: Monk in Ephyoria
DM: The, the monk was in Ephyoria.
Unknown: The Stoneborn.
Unknown: The water-
Unknown: Stoneborn monk.
DM: Is in Ephyoria.
Unknown: By the ocean.
DM: By the ocean, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. And I told him I'd build him a monastery, right?
DM: You told him you'd help him find an apprentice and help build the monastery.
Unknown: Cool. Cool.
Kenzo: Yeah, I think I'll, I think I'll go there first just for a little R&R.
Kenzo: I think I need a little time alone just to kind of reset.
Kenzo: That place was really beautiful.
Kenzo: I liked that a lot and, you know, kind of see if I can pick up the thread there
Kenzo: on the apprentice and, you know, I made a promise, so
Kenzo: just see what's going on out there.
Kenzo: I can't go for too long though, 'cause,
Kenzo: you know, Chardin's a shit show.
Kenzo: Uh, I definitely don't want to stay in Chardin, but I feel like, uh,
Kenzo: I'm gonna have to spend some time there.
Kenzo: Hopefully not too long, too, too much time.
Unknown: But,
Kenzo: uh, you know, I need to make sure that the
Unknown: Emperor, right?
Unknown: Magistress.
DM: Magistress.
Kenzo: Need to make sure that the Magistress lives up to their word.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: you know, seeing all the things that we've seen,
Kenzo: like human politics, you know what I mean?
Kenzo: But, uh, gotta, gotta, you know,
Kenzo: try to be a, try to be a man of integrity, so
Kenzo: definitely gonna spend some time in Chardin.
Kenzo: And then after that, you know, we'll kind of see.
Kenzo: We'll kind of see after that, you know?
Kenzo: I definitely feel like, uh,
Kenzo: I'll definitely be traveling back here to the...
Kenzo: Or traveling back to the Heartroot.
Kenzo: I feel like a real special connection to that place and,
Kenzo: you know, that's some place I'll go
Kenzo: periodically. Oh, I have a big up...
Kenzo: I have a big to-do list actually now that I think about it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Man, you know, I've been capturing and recording all of these stories.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And I feel like the, uh, the Bishwa monks as well,
Kenzo: I owe, I owe it to them to keep the storytelling tradition alive, and I think I'll spend some time
Kenzo: just sh- telling the stories of everything that's happened the past...
Kenzo: Can't believe it's only been a year and a half, but...
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: You know, Kenzo kind of looks at his staff where he'd, he's been, you know-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... writing these stories.
Kenzo: And also Vindasharna itself has got like a bunch of, you know, merrily places where he's been when he's had time.
Kenzo: Oh, and he's had his own, um, he's had his own, um-
Unknown: Apprentice
Kenzo: ... apprentices also.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Like a-
Unknown: Amal's your apprentice.
Kenzo: Yeah. Amal, and he's still there.
Unknown: He'll, uh, still be-
Unknown: He's in Vin-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... he's on Vindasharna, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. He'll, he'll stay with Vindasharna, but he, he's been like kind of dutifully like, like Kenzo will, will like, you know, kind of share different things and he'll try to do different transcriptions and stuff.
Unknown: So,
Kenzo: so yeah. So I think we'll... I'll definitely,
Kenzo: you know, just spend some time telling the stories of, of what's happened and making sure the stories of those that we've
Kenzo: been with and have fought with and died with, that their stories stay alive.
Kenzo: Um, you know, and we'll see what happens.
Kenzo: I mean, I will say, uh,
Kenzo: that last trip to Limbo, that was,
Kenzo: that was something else.
Unknown: I-
Unknown: Wonderful, isn't it?
Kenzo: I'm not sure if wonderful is the adjective, but it was definitely-
Unknown: It was, um...
Kenzo: Yeah, it was definitely something.
Kenzo: I, I will, I will say that
Kenzo: that visit to the Orchard Keeper, that-
Unknown: [coughs]
Kenzo: I, I was able to...
Kenzo: You know, in my own practice, I've done this a little bit with each of you, but in my own practice,
Kenzo: I try to go to a place of true emptiness and true
Kenzo: spaciousness, and I thought that I understood that.
Kenzo: I thought that I'd understood what that was, and I feel like so much of-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... different ways in which I've been able to manifest from that nothingness into
Kenzo: force and sensing
Unknown: was
Kenzo: pretty good, you know? I felt...
Kenzo: I've been feeling pretty powerful in some ways or just capable, but there's something about that space and what I thought was nothingness
Kenzo: was way more something than nothing compared to what that Orchard Keeper had, so.
Unknown: You were humbled by him.
Kenzo: Very much so.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: So there's something I think that, that draws me to that place when it's all said and done.
Seeker: No faces and no names.
Unknown: What's that?
Kenzo: No faces, no names, no nothing.
Unknown: So I don't know.
Kenzo: We'll see what happens, but I feel like that's, uh...
Kenzo: Part of my calling is there, for sure.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: How about you, Delwath?
Delwath: [sighs] Delwath kind of looks around.
Delwath: I... [clears throat] It's kind of hard leaving
Kenzo: s- sort of familiar place.
Delwath: ... a, a home I never thought I'd find.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: But he kind of takes out the, um, the fruit, the sisla fruit he took from the-
Unknown: Mm, mm
Unknown: ... um,
Unknown: komio tree.
Kenzo: Which he never really said what was in it.
Delwath: Maybe hinted a little bit, but he's not actually cut it open yet.
Delwath: Um, but I,
Unknown: I think
Unknown: it might be time to
Delwath: go find
Unknown: my people.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: I've been wondering
Delwath: if I really want to do that,
Delwath: or if it'll bring up too many, uh...
Delwath: I don't even know if they want to be found.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: But I think if, um,
Delwath: if everybody is, uh,
Delwath: departing on their own ways, maybe it's destiny telling me it's time to
Unknown: seek them out.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Sort of
Delwath: takes a knife from the table.
Unknown: Cuts open the fruit.
Unknown: Whoa.
Delwath: [laughs] If you don't know what's in it, it's okay.
DM: I don't know what's in it. [coughs]
Seeker: He just, he looks at it by himself.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: There you go.
Unknown: Somehow.
Kenzo: It's, it's like the, it's like the golden chest in Pulp Fiction.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It, like, glows.
Seeker: And Delwath shows a mysterious emotion.
Delwath: But I will say, um... [coughs] I did not find Limbo, what was the word you used?
Unknown: Wonderful.
Wellby: Wonderful.
Unknown: Not wonderful.
Wellby: So much as an unending nightmare.
Unknown: But not that either.
Delwath: There was something
Unknown: about
Unknown: questing, about
Delwath: freeing that place.
Delwath: It was very, um,
Unknown: worthwhile
Unknown: what we did.
Wellby: Meaningful.
Unknown: Meaningful.
Kenzo: I think there must be others like your brother and the elves who are lost amongst the planes.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Well, having gone through that yourself...
Kenzo: It would be, I think, worthwhile to seek them out.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: I agree with that.
Kenzo: That's a noble-
Wellby: Hmm
Kenzo: ... that is a noble mission.
DM: It's like endless, [coughs] endless level 21 shots of that one.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Super happy to help.
Delwath: I'll certainly stay in touch.
Wellby: Do.
Unknown: What about you, Wellby?
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: How's your map coming?
Wellby: [laughs] Being on other planes definitely complicates the layout.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: It's difficult to find the right projection.
Delwath: Hmm. Maybe you could figure that out, Seeker, the correct plane or projection for mapping the planes.
Wellby: You know, it's funny you should mention.
Wellby: I can imagine
Wellby: working on that for centuries.
Seeker: It's likely that would be the bulk of my work as a,
Seeker: a member of the Philosophers Guild.
Wellby: Of all the maps, though, what I wonder about the most of all isn't all of the planes and their relations, but
Wellby: that there hasn't even been one good map of the Feywild made yet.
Wellby: Someone ought to do that.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: I think there might be a reason there's never been a good map
Unknown: made.
Wellby: Hmm.
Seeker: The field work is not straightforward.
Wellby: But before all that,
Wellby: uh,
Wellby: you know, I left because the life that I was in seemed monotonous.
Wellby: It seemed like it was the same thing over and over, and
Wellby: what I wanted was something new and different.
Wellby: Maybe not as different as Limbo, although it's a good story.
Delwath: Certainly not monotonous.
Wellby: But most of all,
Wellby: I feel like it's time to go back to my people again and find,
Wellby: and find the newness inside that place.
Wellby: The elders always used to say that
Wellby: we're the song that the world sings back to itself again,
Wellby: and that sounded really good, and now I'm not sure I know what that means.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: But it feels like it's time to find out,
Wellby: and to add my own pieces back into that story.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Baxter's saddled up outside.
Wellby: This seems like the place to head back home from again.
Wellby: I'll take the road north,
Wellby: find my family, find the elders, find
Wellby: the next gathering and
Wellby: figure out what it means to help
Wellby: make that song.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Are you allowed to, uh, invite outsiders to some of these parties?
Wellby: Absolutely not.
Unknown: Okay. That's unfortunate.
Wellby: But I'll tell you how it goes.
Unknown: Shape change.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: As I said, we do YTV halfway.
Wellby: Look, I'll ask.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I'll see if I get a plus one.
Wellby: If I get a plus one, you're the first on the list.
Kenzo: A note for guest list.
Wellby: Yes.
Kenzo: See, try what you can do. Do what you can do.
Wellby: Maybe we can, like, initiate you as a halfling or something.
Unknown: I would love that.
Wellby: Right?
Kenzo: I'm good at initiations.
Wellby: Yeah. You're collecting one of every initiation.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, that's, that's my thing.
Unknown: Well, if
Seeker: assembling the stories of your people into a song, or bringing the people of Chardin together under a shared cause, or questing for those lost among the
Seeker: plains, if in any of those pursuits you ever need
Seeker: to answer the unanswerable or see the unseeably ancient
Unknown: or
Seeker: have help otherwise exploring the arcane, you know where to...
Unknown: you know who to call.
Delwath: Will you give us discounts when you're in the Philosopher's Guild?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Can we, can we give you your magic item back then?
Unknown: [laughs] In the same spirit.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Anything you need. [laughs]
Unknown: Helpful fists.
Unknown: A sturdy staff.
Kenzo: You know where to call.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Kenzo: But only some of the time.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: 'Cause I've got a lot on my calendar.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Can't do completing your quest sometime next February.
Wellby: Absolutely. And if you ever need a guide or need something found and I'm not off
Wellby: singing at a private party [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Hit me up.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: And we wouldn't let you go off for Francar on your own.
Kenzo: Ah, that's for sure, yeah.
Unknown: No?
Wellby: No. Come on.
Kenzo: Well, this is, uh, this is Delwath's, uh, raison d'être now, is finding, finding lost
Kenzo: souls, so
Unknown: qua ce fa.
Unknown: That's right.
Delwath: I mean, what are we doing with Vindasharna?
Wellby: Plus, he would never make it without us.
Delwath: That's also true.
Unknown: Also true.
Kenzo: We would get totally distracted.
Seeker: I suppose that might be true.
Delwath: But even...
Delwath: You need some people around you to take all the damage.
Unknown: I, I-
Wellby: Who's gonna die in your place if not us?
Kenzo: Seeker, though, you know, your, your courage and your bravery ha- You know, when you, when you were, when you were that lavathan-
Wellby: It truly is with measure. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: It's measurable. Your courage and bravery is measurable.
Kenzo: We, we saw, we saw it grow.
Kenzo: We saw it grow.
Unknown: That's right.
Unknown: Yeah. It really did.
Unknown: It really did.
Unknown: It's-
Wellby: It was remarkable.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I thank you for that.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: We've all
Unknown: changed and grown.
Unknown: Wait, has Seeker ever died?
Unknown: Definitely.
Delwath: Like, actually died died?
Unknown: I don't think so. No.
Delwath: You think only Wellby, Ken- But Kenzo died died, right?
Unknown: Like...
Wellby: Like failed three death saves?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Well, I've died ceremonially.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: A couple times.
Wellby: But Kenzo died ceremonially.
Unknown: You said died ceremonially.
Wellby: Have you ever died unceremoniously?
Unknown: I don't think any-
DM: Wellby was killed by Grosh.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Delwath was killed by Apollyon.
Delwath: Delwath... Apollyon spoke his magic word and Delwath just fell dead.
Delwath: Rizwin resurrected him.
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Rizwin resurrected Wellby too.
Delwath: We were a lot less worried about dying when we had Rizwin.
Wellby: Really we need to do a Rizwin.
Unknown: Shout out to Rizwin. Yeah.
Delwath: Where's Rizwin at right now?
Wellby: We're pouring one out for Rizwin.
Unknown: I'll text her and see if she's up.
Seeker: Does anybody know what's happening with Rizwin these days?
Wellby: Pour one out for Rizwin.
Delwath: She's, she's, uh... Oh, actually do you have an update on her quest to free the orcs?
Unknown: We owe her a great deal.
Seeker: And we probably inadvertently left her in some situation that she could really use our help but we just forgot about.
Wellby: We probably don't owe her, like, a share-
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: ... of the gold, though.
Unknown: I mean...
Wellby: Like when you say a great deal, you mean that, like, metaphorically.
Delwath: Also, I mean she, she did take the Crown of Infinite Power.
Seeker: Oh, she still has...
Unknown: She's still attuned to the crown.
Wellby: Why, why did you not destroy that piece...
Wellby: No, no, no, I'm letting it go, I'm letting it go.
Unknown: Bless you.
Wellby: I'm going to my faceless place.
Seeker: That has nothing to do with the reason I'm going to the Philosopher's Guild.
Delwath: We, we could, we could try and destroy it.
Kenzo: Oh, we totally forgot about that.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Delwath: Some of us forgot about it.
Unknown: It's another to-do.
Delwath: Others of us were well aware of it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Well, others of us gave it away and made it all complicated when it was all fucking perfectly set up.
Kenzo: No, let's use it for good, they said.
Seeker: Yeah, the Philosopher's Guild will use it for, for ill.
Unknown: No, no.
Wellby: Oh my God.
Delwath: Although, although if we gave the Philosopher's Guild...
Kenzo: Ah, heck, if we traded that for the Philosopher's Guild, would they tell us who they were?
DM: You'll have to reacquire the crown and take it to them and ask.
Wellby: But they could tell us who they were and then they would reshape reality so we don't exist, like...
Delwath: I'm not sure it's a good idea. I'm just saying.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Kayt has her phone silent so I think she might have already gone to bed.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That crown, huh?
Unknown: Do we want to destroy that crown?
Wellby: Yes.
Wellby: Will we be able to anymore?
Kenzo: I would like to hear how the orcs...
Unknown: How Rizwin and, uh,
Unknown: and, um...
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, I don't want to learn
Unknown: Delwath's fate.
DM: He's got it. He's got it all in.
Kenzo: Yeah, I'd also like to hear about how the, uh, Dunmael civil war played out.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Where did that all land?
Wellby: Did we ever find out who ordered Sura imprisoned?
Unknown: I thought we did, but I can't remember.
Wellby: I don't know that we did.
Unknown: No, it was just Agata.
Wellby: Acting on her own?
DM: Yeah, 'cause she wanted to start a civil war.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Yeah. She did a good job with that.
Kenzo: You know, you know, we, we pro- before...
Kenzo: We probably should do a little check in on her at some point.
Delwath: Although actually remember with Agata that Kalal...
Unknown: Kalas was-
Unknown: Guarding
Delwath: ... Ka- Chaos, the, the NPC I played actually stayed to guard her.
Kenzo: Yeah, I remember that. Yeah.
Wellby: I'm just remembering there's like 11 ways, like it was never really her in the first place.
Wellby: It, like...
Unknown: I mean, I'm not saying-
Unknown: But also the Cloud Spirit is back
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: That's true
Delwath: We freed the Cloud Spinner. The Cloud Spinner can obviously...
Unknown: can
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... hover.
Unknown: Clouds can carry him. Yeah, that's true.
Kenzo: That's true. I mean, not right now, but at some point we should just do a little swing by and see.
Unknown: We've really, like
Wellby: She's definitely free, right?
Kenzo: ... fixed all the problems
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: All the, like, bad things that were going on in the world, we've, like, we've fixed Isengay, we fixed the Cloud Spinner.
Delwath: I forgot we fixed the Cloud Spinner.
Delwath: We fixed Chardin.
Seeker: There's still, still some issues in some places.
Seeker: I think we've cr- created everlasting peace.
Unknown: [laughs] I think we have too.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: That's why we're here, and that's why I'm gonna go quest on other planes.
Seeker: Like, this one's all fixed.
Wellby: What ever happened to Krogarr?
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Krogarr.
DM: He became a cloud.
Unknown: He's a storm cloud.
Delwath: He's a free... He's a happy cloud, flying through the storm.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm. I still have Storm ga- Storm Giant Key.
Delwath: But didn't he, like, agree to, like...
DM: Kenzo can contact him with Storm Giant Key.
DM: Yeah. Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: But then-
Delwath: Do, do you, like, get a special reward if you collect, like, 24 different key?
Unknown: No.
Kenzo: Actually, uh, uh, contacting Krogarr kind of sucks, 'cause after I finish it, I, like, have to make a bunch of saves and get...
Kenzo: prevent my brain getting turned to lightning and stuff.
DM: No, no, no. It's, it's in order to regenerate the key you have to take a bunch of lightning damage.
Kenzo: Oh, to regenerate the key. Okay.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: Once... You use it, and then it's gone, and when you get it back, if you get electrocuted.
Unknown: Oh, gotcha.
Unknown: Got it.
Wellby: Go stand on a high hill-
Unknown: But, but-
Wellby: ... in the storm [laughs]
DM: Right.
Delwath: But, but you can also become resistant to all damage.
DM: But, but at this point, what difference does it make?
Delwath: You could just be like, "Oh, I'm electrocuted."
Unknown: So true.
DM: Oh, who cares?
Unknown: Such is the way of things.
DM: It was a, it was a serious cost when you were, like, 11th level.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: But now it's not a serious cost.
Kenzo: I should learn how to use that scimitar.
Seeker: Well, what about the actual centaurs?
Wellby: Not the...
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Weirdos
Unknown: We're just out there-
Wellby: Not the limbal ones
Wellby: ... out there roaming on the plains.
Wellby: Dude.
Kenzo: I mean, there's also, um, Delweth's love interest.
Kenzo: The centaur love interest.
DM: There was Kenzo's love interest.
Kenzo: Ken- Well, that was... I think that, that-
DM: That was a short kind of fling
Kenzo: ... Yeah, that, that was just like a...
Unknown: you know
Wellby: Mm
Kenzo: ... more of a fling.
Wellby: Just a fling.
Kenzo: Yeah. But Delweth, you and that centaur, I mean, that was-
DM: That's just... That's just
Unknown: ... that was, that was
DM: I don't even remember the centaur's name.
Unknown: I... That's...
Unknown: Oh, oh. [laughs]
Unknown: That, that is...
Unknown: Whoa.
Kenzo: That is exactly-
Unknown: That is why you had such a hard time
Wellby: ... purely physical.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] What kind of elf are you, Delweth?
Unknown: Regular.
Unknown: [laughs] Oh.
Unknown: Classic elf there.
Delwath: So what go going in your head, Kenzo, that's not going on in the world?
Unknown: Nothing.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Huh.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Oh, I think of every so often is that
Wellby: guy who got turned into stone by a cockatrice in the...
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: He's okay.
Unknown: There on the mountain.
Unknown: Right at the beginning.
Wellby: Not far from here.
DM: Still stone.
Unknown: Not far from here.
Unknown: Right at the start.
Wellby: We should, we should meet him in Vendrasharna.
Delwath: Why don't we free him? It wasn't his fault.
Kenzo: He's a treasure hunter.
DM: I mean, he could've been one of the cleansed.
Delwath: But we... Then we could free him from being cleansed.
Delwath: It wasn't his fault that he was cleansed.
DM: Well, no. Some of them were alive.
Wellby: I would agree. We should move him somewhere radically different, and then, and then un-
DM: You also still have, uh
Wellby: ... un- cleanse him
DM: ... Antonia trapped in the mirror who you saved.
Delwath: Yeah. But she didn't wanna be let free for, like, five years.
DM: Yeah, yeah, a few years after things settle.
Wellby: Mm.
Wellby: We saw the hub goblin, uh...
Unknown: Oh, shit
Delwath: Oh, we never let her out. We kind of betrayed her a little bit, didn't we, by...
DM: Well, she was immediately gonna teleport off-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... and betray you.
Wellby: Yeah. It was...
DM: [laughs] That was g- That would've been an interesting little twist there.
Wellby: That's a good one to keep as a future problem.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, we could just, we could just kill her.
Kenzo: Ah, just... Let's... Eternal imprisonment is...
Wellby: This is the sort of thing when someone breaks into the ruins of Vendrasharna 500 years from now-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... and says, "What's this mirror? What does this word mean?"
Kenzo: That, that, that's, that's exactly right.
DM: It's actually less trivial to kill her than it seems, because the first thing she does is cast Teleport.
Unknown: Counterspell.
Kenzo: That's a good, that's a good, uh, adventure for, like, some of these kids.
Kenzo: You'd have to make the... You'd have to make... They get two Counterspell shots.
Kenzo: Yeah, go into the ruins of Vendrasharna.
Unknown: I mean, it is tricky because-
Unknown: Find the hub goblin queen. Yeah
Delwath: ... the two Counterspells, and then she could keep try- Well, no, she probably has one spell a slot.
DM: You only have one spell a slot, but...
DM: But even Dimension Door, it's a far...
DM: relatively far away from you.
Delwath: Right. But we could chase her with Dimension Door.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: But yes, harder to kill then.
DM: Oh, you still have a mage, a Urskan mage trapped in there, too.
Delwath: Oh, yeah. Uh, we, like, screwed things up in Ursk.
Delwath: We, like, started a whole war in Ursk too.
Unknown: Yeah, Ursk is not...
Unknown: Eh.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: 'Cause we, like-
Wellby: Interesting place
Delwath: ... upsetted the whole, upset the whole...
Wellby: We picked one faction over another, basically.
DM: Well, you picked the faction that didn't want to side with the vampire-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... over the faction that did.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: We chose right. We, we were good.
Delwath: But actually, I wonder what's going on in Ursk these days.
Wellby: I wonder where that beat Fey went to.
Wellby: 'Cause they were gone by the time the castle came apart.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Probably somewhere in the Feywild.
Wellby: Or Ursk.
Delwath: Or somewhere in Ursk. Or somewhere in...
Delwath: Maybe they're screwing with the Bar Ghooly.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Wellby checks under the table quickly.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: So... [coughs]
Kenzo: Should we learn about some NPCs?
DM: Yeah.
DM: So does Kenzo want to... I mean, does Delweth want...
DM: Or sorry, Wellby want to ride off into the sunset?
Unknown: No, I think We-
Wellby: I think W- I think Wellby's gonna leave from-
DM: Here
Wellby: ... from
Wellby: here.
DM: [coughs]
Wellby: It makes sense for him.
Kenzo: But aren't we gonna learn about the NPC stuff while Well-
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. We'll learn about it first.
DM: Yeah. Okay. So we start,
DM: uh, about a year ago.
Unknown: A year ago?
DM: In a bar in Chardin, the Salty Squid.
DM: The bartender,
DM: uh,
DM: unusually good of hearing.
Unknown: Oh, boy.
Delwath: Wait, when were we... Were we at the Salty Squid?
Wellby: When were we there?
DM: Uh, the first time you went to Chardin, the place you stopped to regroup after getting off the halfling ship
Unknown: Oh boy
DM: ... sits tending bar-
DM: ... as several adventurers,
DM: uh,
DM: quietly talking,
DM: silently in a way that could not be overheard by a normal person.
DM: Hears mention of Ry's hand-
Unknown: Oh, boy.
Wellby: Awesome
DM: ... and becomes curious.
Unknown: Oh, boy.
DM: Listens a little and the adventurers leave.
Wellby: [coughs]
DM: The next day the bartender doesn't show up for work.
DM: Instead,
DM: he sprouts wings
DM: and leaps into the sky and begins to fly east
DM: as a kenku,
DM: slightly curious what these people mentioning Ry might be doing,
DM: but also continuing to,
DM: you know,
DM: walk the world as one does when you are a secret god of a secretive race.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: [coughs]
DM: However, rumors come to him,
DM: and a few months later,
DM: uh,
DM: I forget exactly what it was, um,
DM: a flying castle
DM: arrives in Tolen.
DM: And on the flying castle are these same people who are talking about Ry,
DM: uh, looking for
DM: scouts
DM: to help them
DM: explore the northern wilderness.
Delwath: This is Aaron the kenku scout?
Wellby: Oh. [laughs]
DM: So what better time to learn what they might be up to?
DM: It's easy to be any kenku one wants to be when you are the god of kenku.
Wellby: Ooh.
DM: So how about Katja,
DM: a young kenku scout, a wanderer, curious-
Wellby: Awesome
DM: ... who might travel for a time with a skyship before heading east to ch- check in on those of his people who were never enslaved.
DM: He spends a while listening to them talk when they think nobody can hear them.
DM: Thinks, "Yeah, they'll probably do.
DM: I'll leave them be."
DM: And so he flies off,
DM: uh,
DM: curious to see what Faldric does after encouraging him to go on adventures.
DM: They always go on side quests, why don't you?
DM: And decides to take to the skies,
DM: landing back into the eastern isles, where
DM: our story loses track of him for a time.
DM: Till who knows when.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: Uh,
DM: you already sort of, I mean, the Dunmar Civil War, you already,
DM: didn't you al- when you were in Chardin, you heard the whole resolution of-
Unknown: Yeah, I think so, yeah
DM: ...
DM: like, Darva,
DM: the na- the Chardonian Navy neg- basically claimed Darva, and now that there's chilite m- mines in the mountains, it's like the-
Wellby: Like a client state of Chardin
DM: ... it's a client state of Chardin.
DM: The
DM: part of Dunmar
DM: north and east of Darva, so Tokra, the central plains, Songara, Carawa,
DM: is remains the kingdom of Dunmar or Eastern Dunmar.
DM: It's not,
DM: in the grand tradition of
DM: West Frankia, East Frankia, and Middle Frankia, it's probably just East Dunmar now.
DM: Um,
DM: ruled by Sura. Well, the part south and
DM: south of Darva, so the flood plains, the nine flood plains of the
DM: west of the Ivanti Mountains, where you never really went,
DM: um-
Wellby: [coughs]
DM: ... remain ruled by Caranas.
DM: And so the kingdom splits.
DM: Darva, you know, is c-
DM: a port, but the Dunmari were never big ocean-going traders.
DM: There's no real Dunmari ships, and it is
DM: likely to grow significantly as a major chilite exporting port because it's much cheaper to ship the chilite down the mountains and send it over seas
DM: than it is to carry it over land.
DM: Um,
DM: who else?
Wellby: Has the, uh-
Unknown: The what?
Wellby: ... uh, hub, yeah, the, the orc city
DM: So Rizvan came-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... uh, gathered some folks, and then vanished into
DM: some other plane.
DM: Is currently doing stuff.
DM: It's only, it's not been that long.
DM: It's only been-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... s- six months, seven months since you
DM: separated. It's not, she's not gonna be able to
DM: do whatever she does to Dhark in
DM: six months, so.
DM: But the orcs are fi- I mean, they're fine.
DM: The city is thriving.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, there is the possibility now of trade connections to Izange should they wish to reveal themselves, 'cause the orc kingdom is not that far from Izange.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: It's only, like,
DM: 100 miles or whatever.
Wellby: Right down the river, right?
DM: Yeah, just downriver.
DM: Um,
DM: the King Lubash's,
DM: you know- There's lots of statues to Rizvan all everywhere in the Orc Kingdom.
Unknown: [laughs] Nice.
DM: Um-
Wellby: Occasional statues to, uh, ladders.
Unknown: The boulder ladder.
DM: Well, there's just the... I mean, there's-
Unknown: There's one monument, yeah
DM: ... the, the monument.
Unknown: Oh, the [laughs]
DM: The, the site of the boulder lad- the actual boulder ladder itself is like a monu- has grown up and become like a whole monument to the battle.
DM: It's like the monument...
DM: It's outside the city, and it's become like a little plaza and memorial to the honor the-
Kenzo: The more time passes, there's like a square, gift shops.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Memorabilia.
DM: Little, like-
Unknown: Little ladders [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah, people selling little ladders.
DM: Little ladders.
Kenzo: And the kids are in the-
Wellby: Ladder Cola.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: What about the ladder?
Unknown: Oh my God,
Kenzo: the ultimate question. What is in the future of the ladder?
Delwath: No, I'm, I'm polymorphing the ladder into a...
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: The ladder is permanently animate.
DM: Oh my God.
Unknown: Does the ladder get permanently animate?
Unknown: Uh, yes, it definitely does.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Oh, my God.
Kenzo: Yeah, well, permanently animated as a permanent animate thing.
Unknown: Well, it always has like...
Seeker: There's this moment, you know, at, in the 59th minute of regret each time.
Seeker: It just wants to go live its life and be a ladder.
DM: Has it, has it ever been dismissed?
DM: Doesn't it always die?
Wellby: What, what it most wants is just to hang in one place.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um-
Kenzo: Does it just wanna be climbed and to be in service, or what's, what's it wanna do?
Wellby: It goes and becomes a playground.
Seeker: Well, let's talk to it. It can't say anything back to us, but we can, we can talk to it.
Wellby: It can pantomime, though.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: We thank you for your service to our many causes,
Unknown: heroic ladder.
Wellby: I pin a little medal onto part of it.
Unknown: One of its rungs.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: You've done a great service and many deeds and many, made many sacrifices,
Seeker: and today we set you free to seek your own destiny.
Unknown: We climbed
Unknown: so that you may... No.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: We climbed so that we may...
Unknown: No.
Wellby: We... In the end, we climbed so that you may rise.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: But, but be careful, spellcasters, 'cause-
DM: Yeah, they can dispel it
Delwath: ... you can be dispelled.
Wellby: Probably best just to seek honest work.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: You, you may wish either,
Unknown: depending on your preference,
Seeker: to find an ordinary orchard
Unknown: and
Seeker: h- help human children climb up to pick apples, or-
Unknown: Or
Seeker: ... avoid the company of all sentient creatures and climb yourself as high as you might into the mountains.
Kenzo: Or, if in some later time you seek some company and don't wanna be around,
Kenzo: uh, other sentient beings on this plane, you can be a ladder in limbo with Kenzo.
DM: Hmm. I don't think the ladder wants to go to limbo.
Kenzo: When he retires, maybe.
Unknown: I don't know.
Seeker: And there will always be a place for you in a well-appointed utility closet-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: ... deep in the bowels of the Philosopher Guild, the Philosophers Guild's secret facilities if you vi- visit us in Tolet.
Wellby: I packed for you this bag of spare bits of rope and needles.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: If you're ever hurt, use it to repair yourself.
DM: It sort of wiggles, indicating it has no hands.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I tie it on nonetheless.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Get, get someone to do it for you.
DM: Kind of looks over at Seeker.
Wellby: Oh, yeah, hang on.
Wellby: I pull out a sheet of paper, and on the paper I write, "Hello.
Wellby: I'm a friendly and helpful sentient ladder."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [coughs]
Wellby: "If you find me, treat me with kindness and respect, and I will do the same."
Kenzo: I am very brave. [laughs]
Wellby: I am very brave. I've saved a life and possibly even the multiverse itself.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: I tuck it into the bag with the rope.
Unknown: Now
Seeker: go, ladder, and seek your own destiny with our blessing.
Wellby: Do not look back,
Wellby: for you have no eyes.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
DM: Well, it can, it can perceive, I think, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, it can attack things, so yeah-
Unknown: Yeah, it can attack things
Kenzo: ... it probably has some kinda perception abilities.
Delwath: And if, um,
Delwath: if you ever, uh...
Delwath: We'll check in on you occasionally.
Delwath: If you ever, if you ever feel, if you ever feel a little, uh-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... a sense like something's trying to watch you,
Delwath: just let it happen. That's me checking in on you.
Wellby: Can we give it one of the eye things so we see where it goes?
DM: Oh my gosh. Oh yeah, you totally can.
Delwath: Well, yeah, and if you ever fall,
Delwath: do not worry.
Delwath: We will find you and bring you to life again.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: But don't take unnecessary risks.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: There's a lot of instructions for the ladder, I'm not sure.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like-
Wellby: Above all, beware of sisters
DM: ... it doesn't seem in danger.
DM: No, dragon's the only thing it's afraid of.
DM: Dragons are the only things that have ever killed it.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: No, it's died like 56 times.
DM: No, it hasn't.
Unknown: It has died a lot of times, actually.
DM: No, it really hasn't.
Unknown: No?
Unknown: It's died a lot.
Kenzo: Feel like it's died a lot.
Unknown: It died in limbo, didn't it?
Unknown: It died in limbo.
DM: It did die in limbo, which is why it didn't go to limbo, but it, the ladder actually almost never dies.
Unknown: Really?
DM: Yeah. The only ladders that have died...
DM: The ladder-
Delwath: The boulder ladder died.
DM: The boulder ladder died heroically-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... destroying the-
Delwath: See, I thought we were up to, like, ladder 10 or something.
Unknown: It's not.
DM: No, no, no. There's only...
DM: The, the ladder died against the green dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: One.
DM: That was ladder one.
DM: Um, boulder ladder died.
DM: Ladder two died...
DM: Ladder three died against, um, Ragam Jos.
Unknown: That was it, right?
Wellby: This is ladder four?
DM: And ladder four died in limbo
Delwath: Ladder five. This is ladder five
Wellby: Five.
Seeker: Which saved me from the thousand foot fall.
DM: Yes.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Oh, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
DM: Uh,
DM: the fourth, the ladder, then the ladder died.
DM: Sorry, I forgot the fourth ladder died.
DM: Okay. The 15 foot ro- rope...
DM: I have notes on this.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: The 15 foot rope ladder originally from the lair in the Fraternity of the Empty Moon,
DM: fought valiantly against many enemies
DM: until bravely dying in battle against Grimkaskall the Dream Dragon to allow the rest of the party to escape in episode 51.
DM: The boulder ladder, the hero of the Battle of Uzghakar who died while smashing a massive trebuchet to pieces.
DM: The new ladder who finally got to destroy a mirror in Cloudstrider's prison before bravely dying in battle against R- Gemdross.
DM: Slowly the ear ladders are beginning to feel that fighting dragons might be dangerous.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Then the fourth ladder who died destroying the charlight ma- mirror powering the lightning tower-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... and the charlight death ray.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: But it's always worth the sacrifice to destroy mirrors.
Wellby: Correct. [laughs] It's, it's great rival for our affections.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Exactly.
Unknown: [laughs] That's right.
DM: And then the fifth ladder-
Delwath: There can be only one type of ladder
Wellby: Died chaos. [laughs]
DM: Died in limbo.
Delwath: So sixth... This is ladder six.
DM: So this is the sixth ladder.
Kenzo: A lot of ladders have-
Wellby: We, we actually like in-
Unknown: ... died
DM: A lot, yeah
Wellby: ... in one of the hallways on Vindrasharna we have, like, a painting of each ladder.
DM: Totally.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Wellby: And across the hall, a painting of each Seeker that's just identical.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah. [coughs] But this, the Simrakoms die way faster than the ladders.
Unknown: That's true.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: That's funny, yeah. Well, 'cause they-
DM: Well, the ladders have more hit points, but also they're usually less threatening, so-
Unknown: Right. Yeah, we've-
DM: ... enemies are less likely to attack them
Delwath: I guess it's the construct that dies a lot.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. That's true.
Unknown: But that's not really-
DM: The construct does a ton of damage
Delwath: ... it's not really a person, doesn't have the same-
DM: Right. [laughs] So the sixth ladder-
Unknown: Wow, what a game
DM: ... that ladder died
Wellby: So off goes the ladder.
Delwath: So the ladders are the first ones to leave.
DM: This ladder. Yeah. The sixth ladder set free by true poly.
Seeker: We salute you, ladder. That was a great idea.
Wellby: The true poly.
Unknown: [sighs]
Wellby: How about Milo and company?
Delwath: Yeah. Oh yeah, Milo.
DM: Uh...
Unknown: Who we have-
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: ... I think we still have eyes on
DM: We have eyes on, yep. Um,
DM: uh,
DM: Milo at this point, um, is
DM: in port in a strange city
DM: with gold domes shining on a tropical island.
Unknown: What the fuck?
Wellby: The golden city.
Unknown: Possibly.
DM: [coughs] What?
Unknown: Mir town.
DM: Yeah, that was one of the, um,
DM: one of the, uh, souls that you rescued-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... from Apollyon's phylactery was from a golden city to the south.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: This is probably not the same golden city 'cause that...
DM: But it could be.
DM: I mean, the south didn't really get destroyed by-
Unknown: The Great War
DM: ... the Great War, so something that was-
Seeker: Oh, ancient could still be standing.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Whoa
DM: So Milo and Tilly made it-
Wellby: They did it
DM: ... to the south.
Kenzo: That's great. And we can see them through the eye?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So we can teleport there.
DM: You could.
Seeker: Wait, let's scrap all these other plans.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Let's go to the golden city.
DM: Yeah, let's do it.
Kenzo: Let's continue this conversation at a cafe in the golden city.
Kenzo: A little normal. Yeah.
Unknown: I mean, we could, but-
DM: You could
Kenzo: So, uh, how are we staying in touch?
Kenzo: Should we make some more sending stones, or what's the...
DM: This is the moment when Seeker brings out the four rings that him and Faldric have been constructing,
DM: each
DM: a shard of the rainbow prism.
Unknown: Oh, right.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: Which allows you to cast sending to each other
DM: and teleport to Vindrasharna.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Awesome.
Kenzo: It's the, uh, uh, Captain Planet rings.
Wellby: Yes.
Unknown: Love it.
Unknown: Thanks, Seeker.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Faldric, what are you doing?
DM: I mean,
DM: we're gonna, we're gonna take Vindrasharna to the Plane of Fire, right?
Seeker: We sure are. Got some work to do first, and then I'm gonna need your help.
DM: Yeah, I mean, we still have to invent
DM: a thing that protects us from fire.
DM: I'm gonna let you figure out the, like, magic weirdness of crossing planes.
Unknown: I'll figure it out.
DM: But, but yeah, we're gonna have the...
DM: I've been drawing some sketches actually.
DM: The ice shell-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... I think we can make it regenerating.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: So that it'll melt and regenerate at the same rate
DM: in the Plane of Fire.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Icy.
Unknown: Love it.
DM: We're gonna need to find some more, uh, eternal ice.
Unknown: Oh, where do we find that?
DM: I don't know. There's probably some in...
DM: Didn't you find all sorts of weird stuff on the circular island?
DM: Let's go there.
Unknown: Okay. Yes.
DM: At some point though, I'm gonna retire.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: But not yet.
Seeker: No, I need you for this.
DM: I mean, I was actually retired.
DM: It was too boring.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: So what makes you think the second one's gonna stick?
DM: Uh,
DM: it probably won't.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: There's too many interesting things to do to find out.
Unknown: That's the thing.
DM: 'Cause bird gives a little squawk and coughs a ball of flame.
DM: Yeah, yeah, we're gonna take you to the Plane of Fire, don't worry.
Unknown: Oh, yes.
DM: It's coming.
DM: But after that, there's like the Plane of Ice, and the Plane of Water, and the Plane of...
DM: Well, I don't really wanna take Vindr Shara to the Plane of Earth.
DM: That sounds tricky.
Unknown: Might be tricky.
DM: Air? We could go to Air.
Unknown: Definitely air.
DM: That sounds good.
Kenzo: Sounds like a packed agenda.
Unknown: How about Mechanus?
DM: Hm.
DM: Yeah,
DM: it's worth a try, Mechanus.
DM: I don't know how to get there, though.
Unknown: Have you got my sword?
DM: Well, we don't have a focus for Mechanus, do we?
Unknown: Or do we?
Unknown: Amulet?
DM: I mean, there's a lot of random stuff
DM: in the portable hole, so maybe we should dump it out and look.
DM: Maybe not right here. This is probably not the spot to do that.
Wellby: I think we probably, on the way down here, unpacked the portable hole-
DM: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... into Vindr Shara
DM: ... it's probably all in Vindr Shara hoard.
DM: Yeah, I'm cataloging.
DM: Maybe I'll find one when I get through all the random crap you guys collected.
DM: It's like a lot of random crap.
DM: There's like 4,000 rings.
DM: Did you know that?
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I did. Yeah.
Delwath: We took the giant hoard. We have like a lot of stuff.
DM: From Regebdos's hoard.
Delwath: We have like... Um, maybe, uh, I'm gonna, I'm gonna ask my sword, could you learn to be a focus?
DM: No, your for- your sword cannot learn-
Unknown: No?
DM: ... to be a focus.
Wellby: Can the Cloudcrick amulet?
Unknown: That's also amulet.
Delwath: That would be useful for, um, plane jumping Delwath.
DM: Oh, that's true.
DM: Maybe your sword could learn to be a focus.
DM: No, the Cloudcrick amulet is just enchanted with the magic.
DM: It's not a-
Wellby: Not a thing from there.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: I mean, it'll only be useful for the outer planes.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: should we talk to Dimitar one last time before we go?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: What's Dimitar up to?
Delwath: [laughs] I'm never gonna die.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh,
DM: oh, um, so Dimitar, uh...
DM: So you're gonna... Are you gonna...
DM: Oh, you have the eye. You have the, his throne wired up so you can-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... um...
DM: So the scene o- that you like take up the like, um,
DM: the
DM: bag of, of gemstones that let you see through the, um,
DM: see through the, the eye,
DM: and you look out
DM: at this
DM: absolutely-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... massive feast.
Unknown: Nice. [laughs]
DM: Like giant table laid out with all sorts of fish cooked in like 100 different ways.
Unknown: Oh, gosh.
DM: And Dimitar is walking along the top of the table,
DM: and he's eating each thing and, like, his...
DM: He's, like, really full.
DM: Like, it looks like he's, like, like, about to explode from overeating.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And he's like, "Nothing's ever gonna kill me."
DM: "I'm gonna try everything on this table."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Just walking down the table-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... taking a bite of each thing.
DM: And then he, like, starts to choke on some fish.
DM: He's like, "That can't kill me.
DM: I still enjoy life."
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And begins to walk down further.
Unknown: No way. [laughs]
DM: He's like, [coughs] something.
DM: Uh, and one of the other, um, dragonets is like, "No, no, no.
DM: We, we didn't cook that. I think it's poisonous."
DM: And he just takes a giant bite and he says, "Ew, that's gross.
DM: But it can't kill me."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And he gets down to the end of the table, and then he, like, falls off.
DM: And he bangs his head and he's like, "That can't kill me."
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: my God. [laughs]
Unknown: No, no, no.
DM: But, but I think I need a nap.
Unknown: No,
Unknown: no.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And then he sees that the throne is blinking, and he, like, slowly begins to crawl back along the top of the table.
DM: And he's like, "Hey, do you know nothing can kill me now?"
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: "Only sadness can kill me."
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: How, how'd you learn about all this, Dimitar?
DM: Uh, Ry told me.
DM: Well, his voice told me.
Wellby: Is there anything else, Dimitar, is there anything else that Ry's voice told you
Wellby: that, that you were supposed to tell us?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: No.
Delwath: That you're supposed to tell how powerful the Maeri sorcerer?
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Well, uh, but I...
DM: [sighs] Okay.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay. But wait.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
DM: I hadn't seen another one of my own kind for, like,
DM: ever,
DM: and there was one just flying.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Of course I was gonna follow where it went.
Kenzo: All that's totally fine, but then the part when you actually met the Dunmeri, like us-
DM: But, but you're not a sorcerer.
Kenzo: No, I'm not. I'm not
Delwath: I'm a sorcerer.
DM: But you're not Domari.
Unknown: Oh, no. [laughs]
DM: He specifically said a Domari sorcerer.
Unknown: Oh. [laughs]
DM: What?
DM: I didn't wanna mess up.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: You, you, you did great.
Unknown: You did good.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You did very good.
Unknown: Very literal, very literal, but-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... understood.
Unknown: No, well done.
Unknown: Yeah, good job.
Unknown: Good job. How's your empire doing?
DM: Um, they make me lots of food.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Uh,
DM: we're trying to invent some new games.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: We have the fish diving contest.
Unknown: Good.
DM: There's the flying fast into the mountain contest, but I'm the only one who can play that because everybody else dies.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So that one hasn't caught on the way I hoped.
Delwath: Do you have a fish eating contest yet?
DM: N- well, we tried that, but I win each time.
Unknown: Wait, wait, is that a bad thing?
Wellby: How, how many are left in your kingdom?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Oh, no, there's lots.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: And, and are you making sure everyone has enough food to eat and-
DM: Well, that's why we have fish diving contests.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm.
DM: 'Cause they, they catch the food.
DM: But also, there's, like, magic food.
DM: Nobody needs to-
Unknown: Oh, that's right. That's right
DM: ... like, they just fly over to one of the magic food places.
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: And you're taking care of the island as a whole as well?
DM: W- wait, was I supposed to?
Wellby: I think the island's yours now, isn't it?
Delwath: It's not. It doesn't really belong to you.
DM: Yeah, yeah. I, I just-
Unknown: You have a-
DM: ... I thought you said I'm taking care of it.
Unknown: Yeah, you're, you're a care- you're a steward.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: No, I thought it was mine.
Unknown: You, you... Caretaker, steward,
Kenzo: looking after it.
DM: I, I don't quite understand what you mean.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Like, making the- making sure nothing bad happens.
Wellby: The duty of the rulers to their subjects.
DM: No, I've never heard of that concept, but, but the whole, like, magic circle.
DM: Nobody can get here and...
DM: Wait, you killed all the bad guys, right?
DM: Did you kill all the bad guys? Did you leave any bad guys on the island for me?
Delwath: No. No. But you can't die.
Unknown: Well, you can.
Delwath: Go kill them yourself.
DM: But who's gonna hunt fish for me-
Unknown: Well, no, you can-
DM: ... if they all die
Unknown: ... kill the bad guys.
DM: Well, I don't really w- wanna do that.
DM: It doesn't actually seem that fun.
DM: I might not enjoy it, and then I could die.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, my God. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Look, um-
Unknown: Oh, my God
Seeker: ... there's, there's a forge there on the island, and we're, we're gonna need to spend a little time there doing projects.
Delwath: But we'll make sure there're no bad guys.
DM: Yeah. It's only 100 gold a day rent.
Wellby: Uh, we, we'll, we'll give you zero.
Unknown: We'll negotiate that.
Unknown: Um, is there anything we can do for the-
DM: But I'm, I'm mortal.
Delwath: I need an infinite amount of money.
Unknown: To do what?
DM: [laughs] Um, to, to-
Unknown: To what?
Delwath: How about we give you an island instead?
DM: To... No, it's the, the-
Delwath: We'll give you a magic island that produces food so you can live forever.
DM: But nobody's gonna do the fish diving competitions and make me all this food if there's not prizes.
Seeker: Now, Timitar, we have some incredibly shiny objects that you might desire.
DM: You have good prizes?
Seeker: We have prizes you would appreciate.
DM: Okay. Well, I'll take prizes instead of gold.
Unknown: Good.
Unknown: Boy, we have prizes.
DM: Okay. That's good.
DM: I have a lot of prizes, but somebody asked if my throne could be a prize, and then I had to say, like, "Obviously not," because are you the immortal king of a magical island?
DM: And then he said, "No, but I'll catch you some fish."
DM: And so then I said, "Great. You're awesome," and he went and caught fish.
DM: So everybody was happy in that story.
Seeker: Sounds like you were a wise and just emperor.
Unknown: Very good. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah. Very consistent.
Unknown: He's got it figured out. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah. Well, okay.
DM: It was kind of sad that Rye left.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: I hope he's happy where he went.
Unknown: I hope so too.
Kenzo: I mean, he, he, he kind of, you know, made his last,
Kenzo: his last words all about you.
Unknown: Doesn't that feel pretty good?
DM: Oh, that's nice.
DM: He didn't realize those were his last words.
DM: Aw, good old Rye.
Kenzo: [laughs] Did he do a good job serving you?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: He was great.
Unknown: Good.
DM: But, but, but, but, but wait, I'm gonna be older than him soon.
Unknown: What?
Wellby: What? Then he's gonna have to do what you say?
Unknown: What...
Unknown: How do you feel about that?
Delwath: I think... Did he always do, do what you said? But, you know, Varal will always be older than you.
DM: Oh, that's okay, 'cause I don't count gods.
DM: They're irrelevant. [clears throat] It's fine.
Kenzo: You were always Rye's boss anyways, right?
Kenzo: I mean, that's kind of the whole dynamic.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I mean,
DM: it's funny, that's how I remember it, but I've read some of the stories, and it's not how the, like, history comes across.
Unknown: Maybe you should write a new one.
DM: That's-
Unknown: Ooh
DM: ... like, way... I would get so bored.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Maybe you should have a contest for who can write the best history.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: Oh, I could hire somebody to write a history.
DM: That's a great idea.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: How much gold do you think it takes to hire somebody to write a history?
Unknown: I think you should-
DM: Like, a correct history
Unknown: ... one.
Unknown: Like, a correct history. [laughs]
Delwath: Well, no, I mean, if you hire the right person, like, I don't know, maybe we have somebody...
Delwath: We can find somebody. Maybe you could hire one of the, one of the people we have on Verdigrarna for only, like,
Delwath: 200 gold a day.
Seeker: I mean, create a residency program, really prestigious.
Unknown: You spin it right, they'll pay you to come.
Unknown: Don't, don't tell him that. [laughs]
DM: That's a great idea, Seeker.
Unknown: Oh, oh, so close.
DM: So wait-
Unknown: So close
DM: ... so wait.
Unknown: So close.
Delwath: No, no, Seeker doesn't know what he's talking about
Kenzo: 200 gold a day. That's all you'd have to pay
Delwath: Well, maybe eventually you can create a residency, but you have to, like, get f- get the initial-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... thing happening
Kenzo: You gotta get the first volume published Yeah, and you need, you need, you need to get the buzz.
Kenzo: You need to get everybody excited about it.
Kenzo: You know, you gotta get all the attention Get the influencers.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly
DM: Okay. I've never been great at math, so if you pay me 100 gold a day, and I pay 200 gold a day, I get 100 gold a day, right?
Unknown: No, we get 300.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: He goes and looks and he says...
DM: He, like, bellows out from the ground, "How much is 300 gold a day?"
DM: [laughing]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And, like, four dragonets fly over, and they're, like, talking a little bit.
DM: Do we need that?
Kenzo: [laughs] I'm not sure it's in our budget.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That's, like...
DM: Uh, that's not that much.
DM: You can afford that.
DM: But why?
DM: And they talk amongst themselves a bit.
DM: It's like...
DM: To Whispers Cry, "Wait a minute.
DM: I only pay you 100 gold a day."
Delwath: I'm not very good at math. Sorry. You might be right.
DM: That's fine. We can do that.
Unknown: Deal. [laughs]
DM: But it has to be a good book.
Unknown: Can you read?
DM: Obviously.
DM: I mean, I have magical.
DM: As long as it's in the right language.
Unknown: Well, I wrote
Unknown: it.
DM: Well, you have to write it in Common, otherwise my subjects aren't gonna know how to read it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Obviously.
DM: Maybe make a statue too.
DM: Like, most of what I've seen, I'm smaller than Ry.
DM: Can we make one where I'm bigger than Ry?
Unknown: Yeah, this, this sounds great.
Wellby: [laughs] Ry rides on your shoulder.
Unknown: [laughs] And then-
DM: No, like, you know, a nice big, like,
DM: dragonet protecting him.
Kenzo: And then the coffee book closes.
DM: [laughs] Yeah.
Kenzo: And then it says, uh, the correct s- [laughs] The, the correct telling-
DM: The correct history [laughs]
Unknown: ... of the Great War
DM: ... of the Great War.
Kenzo: The correct history of the Great War.
Kenzo: Dimitar with a little Ry on his shoulder.
DM: Yes. So Dimitar
DM: drifts off to his next task as the immortal ruler of the circular island.
Unknown: Awesome.
DM: I think that's a good ending.
Kenzo: That was perfect.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: I think so too. That was perfect.
Kenzo: Always need that coffee book. Correct history of the Great War.
Unknown: Introduce the ladder to Dimitar.
Unknown: What's that?
Delwath: Introduce the ladder to Dimitar.
Kenzo: Right. Oh, yeah. That's actually a great idea.
Kenzo: The two, the two major familiars of the, uh,
Unknown: campaigns.
Unknown: Wow, man.
Kenzo: Great job, guys.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Really good game.
Wellby: It was epic. Yeah, that was epic.
Kenzo: That was actually longer than our first one.
Unknown: Yeah, that's crazy.
Unknown: That is kind of crazy.
DM: That's true.
Kenzo: The first one felt so long.
Delwath: Probably fewer s- well, I don't know.
Kenzo: Did we play, like, every week? I can't even remember.
DM: We played almost every week, but not-
Wellby: We played almost every week-
DM: ... not during the summer
Unknown: ... but nobody was dating.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Now, 'cause... I don't know.
Delwath: When I was dating Caitlin, we would go out on Friday nights and play D&D.
DM: Yeah, yeah. And I-
Unknown: That's right. That's right
DM: ... I mean, I was dating what's her name then.
Unknown: Allison Frost.
DM: No, no, no. After I broke up with Allison, I was dating that girl who-
Unknown: I mean, not every week
DM: ... lived in Bedford.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I don't think any of you ever met her.
Unknown: No.
DM: Becky somebody, I want to say.
Unknown: Beckmalek.
DM: No.
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, I don't know if we pl- I...
Delwath: Probably some Saturday nights we probably did stuff with her or something.
Delwath: But we didn't, we definitely wouldn't-
DM: But we didn't play much over the summer, I don't think.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: No, we didn't.
DM: [coughs]
Wellby: And we would play longer sessions too, right?
DM: We played much, like-
Kenzo: Way longer sessions ... six or something.
DM: We'd start at 6:00 with our Nick subs, and we'd-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... play until midnight or 1:00.
DM: So we'd play for, like...
DM: But also, we spent a lot of time, like, writing and passing notes to each other.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: It was probably, it was probably a little more hours, the high school one, but-
Kenzo: I think so. It felt that way.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause we're also spent, we also spent a lot of time, like, just, like, world building and stuff- Outside of the...
Unknown: Yeah, like talking and, like...
Kenzo: I remember just spending a lot of time, like, thinking about and doing stuff related to Talgar.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like this, as adults, we spent, or you spent a lot of time outside, but, like, we're, we're just, like-
DM: Right.
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... we just, like, lock in for these hours, so.
Kenzo: Like, total Talgar hours in high school I think was probably a lot, a lot, a lot higher.
Unknown: Yeah. That's probably true.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Awesome.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Kenzo and the Heartroot Staff.
Unknown: Yeah, I know. I love it.
DM: Man, that natural 20 on your int check.
Kenzo: That, that, that was a, that was a glorious, epic way to end.
Kenzo: Beautiful way to end it.
Unknown: Yeah. That, that was-
Unknown: So good
Kenzo: ... that was really, really awesome.
Kenzo: That was incredibly satisfying.
Seeker: We had multiple kind of role reversals in that last little section.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Like
Seeker: Seeker going front and center to take all the damage.
Kenzo: Yeah. [laughs] Yeah, like, literally.
Kenzo: Yeah, you were the front line of the combat.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: And
Seeker: w- yeah, Wellby standing back and also the one to actually take all the damage.
Unknown: And then Kenzo making-
Kenzo: 'Cause he had to use his intelligence, his lowest score That's awesome
Unknown: Interesting
Unknown: That's great
Seeker: I did like the double Leviathan image
DM: It was good
Unknown: That was, [laughs] that was smart
DM: Yeah
Unknown: That was fun too
Kenzo: Yeah, that combat was fucking crazy.
Kenzo: That was like a properly-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... that was an insane combat
DM: Yeah. Yes
Kenzo: That was really insane.
Kenzo: That was really fun
Unknown: Just all the Lego props
Wellby: How many hit points did that ooze have to start out with?
Unknown: 1,000
DM: 1,000. Jesus
Unknown: Damn
Kenzo: But see, I really like though how, like yeah, the, the very ending required us to still do something creative.
Kenzo: Like, it wasn't just like-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... win.
DM: Right. Yeah
Kenzo: Just like beat the... 'Cause yeah, 'cause once it became clear that the minions weren't gonna die, it was like, oh fuck, how the fuck are we gonna kill-
DM: Mm
Kenzo: ... the thing in the middle?
Unknown: Yeah, that was great.
Unknown: It was really great.
Unknown: Yeah. [sighs]
Kenzo: [groans] So what are we, what are we doing next?
Kenzo: When are we, when are we D&D scheduled?
DM: I know.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Try to ask Adam something
Unknown: Oh my gosh.
Unknown: That's weird
DM: Oh, that feels weird
Unknown: Yeah, right?
Seeker: There's nothing coming up next
Unknown: Holy shit
DM: Well,
DM: we talked about a bunch of things.
DM: [sighs] I don't know.
DM: I'm sort of curious, like how
DM: frequently are people willing to make new characters?
DM: 'Cause that's kind of the limitation to-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... running a bunch of four session things
Delwath: I am happy to make as many new characters as you want
DM: Well, yes, I'm aware of that, Mike.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I like making new characters
Unknown: Mike has a lot of character ideas
Delwath: Tons of character ideas
Unknown: That's cool.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I, like, like I'm not sure like it's, it's-
Delwath: Although I will say, first level's kind of boring
Kenzo: Mm. We can start maybe higher level
DM: Well, I would do, I mean, the...
DM: We can like revisit the discussion of like what the next campaign should be.
DM: I would start, for the next campaign, I would start at one
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah. But-
DM: But I wouldn't run a short-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... a four session game, it's not worth running it, starting at first level
Delwath: You'd probably do third, fifth or seventh, depending on how, how high
DM: Yeah. I've done like start at two and level up after the first session and then do the rest of it.
DM: But that-
Delwath: But it's, that's really annoying actually mechanically because you're much better off knowing your subclass when you start.
DM: Yeah, that's true
Delwath: Because otherwise it's like, it's actually almost as much work to go from two to three as it is to make a new character.
DM: Yeah, true.
Delwath: So you're almost doubling the amount of...
Unknown: Oh, interesting
Delwath: 'Cause you get, third level is when you get your subclass and you may have tons of choices.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Right. So it's-
Delwath: So it's easier. I mean, you can do something where everybody actually knows their-
DM: You make a third... The way, so I ran a sh- a three session game like this where I had everybody make a third level character, then de-level it to second
Delwath: Yes, you can do that
DM: So that you'd, you'd have a-
Unknown: Something to work towards
DM: ... you'd like have a minute to get used to the mechanics of the character before you-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... get your subclass.
DM: And it gives you a l- nice little power spike in, in the little second book of the adventure.
DM: But three is fine too
Delwath: No. Well, that can work-
DM: It's fine
Kenzo: ... 'cause you make it up as a third level and then start it that way
Kenzo: Yeah. Unfortunately, like I think like realistically...
Kenzo: [sighs] I mean, over the holidays maybe.
Kenzo: I don't know. I'm just thinking like for me it's like, it's just like-
Unknown: It starts to be a busy time of year
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, it's just all, and like the, the spring too is like gonna be fucking bananas, so it's like the time...
Kenzo: Like I'm, I'm still down to still have the same like kind of rhythm
Unknown: Right
Unknown: But, but-
Unknown: But it's hard to make up characters
Kenzo: ... yeah, I wouldn't make up, I would do it like in game.
Kenzo: Like if we had a session where we all got together and then like we like made characters or something like that
DM: Well, you know, we could-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... we don't ha- If we're, if we're trying...
DM: Let's say we want to, let's say we want to do New Hampshire next, like late summer next year and do Francar, and then-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... sometime after that start a, start the next campaign, but not necessarily immediately after that.
DM: Like we could, we could have a rhythm where we do
DM: a sh- like a session that's like make characters, do a little world building
Kenzo: World building. I like that. Yeah
Unknown: Session zero
Unknown: Yeah
DM: We could just do like four session zeros over the course of the year where we do like characters and world building, but maybe a little role playing, but no
DM: mechanics-
DM: The adventure starts the next time
DM: ... and then the adventure starts the next time
Unknown: Yeah. Totally.
DM: Right?
Unknown: That's great. That's great
DM: Like, it doesn't have to be-
Unknown: That's great
Unknown: That's the practical schedule
DM: It doesn't have... People don't have to make characters in advance as long as we don't
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I think, I think-
Seeker: Well, it's, it's more fun to do it together anyway
Kenzo: I, totally. I, I think so too
Unknown: There's actually something-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... especially if you're only running three sessions or four sessions, it's actually kind of fun to make up a party together
DM: Right
Kenzo: Yeah. That's great
DM: Rather than working in-
Kenzo: And then we can like make up dynamics-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and like make up like-
DM: But also I do, I said, I mean, I do have two Malwar adventures that I wrote and I never ran
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: Which I would kind of like to run, and I like Malwar.
DM: And that-
Kenzo: Malwar's cool. Schwartz would have to make up a Malwar character, but that'd be fun for him
DM: No, Schwartz has a Malwar character
Unknown: No, he has a Malwar character
DM: You and Schwartz never played in Malwar at the same time.
Unknown: Two
DM: But he made a character
Kenzo: Oh, really? You guys, you guys did a Malwar adventure?
Delwath: I also didn't, I didn't play either, but-
DM: So, and Kate also really likes Malwar.
DM: She wants to play-
Kenzo: What, when, when did, uh, when did Schwartz do a Malwar adventure?
DM: So we've done four Malwar things.
DM: We did the, the Nantucket one and then the Nantucket follow-up, neither of which Schwartz was part of
Kenzo: It was just us
Unknown: It was the three of us
DM: Yeah.
DM: And then, no, in the follow-up, um, Schwartz's, uh, John Leeker joined us
Unknown: Okay
DM: And then we did one that was over, like it was over Thanksgiving or something when
DM: it was Kate, John,
DM: Schwartz, and maybe Mike.
Unknown: Oh, yes. I did
DM: I guess
Kenzo: I don't remember doing Malwar. Did you ever do that Malwar, Schwartz?
Delwath: I did a, I did a, I did that Malwar one time.
Delwath: That was, that was the one where...
Unknown: Yeah, I remember that one
Kenzo: I never did Malwar, Schwartz
DM: No, you, that's what I said, you never did.
Unknown: So there's four episodes
Kenzo: Yeah, but Schwartz has a Mal- Malwar character
DM: So one was, was-
DM: Kong, Mike, Eric.
DM: That was the one in Nantucket. Then Kong, Mike, Eric, John.
DM: That was the follow-up to the one in Nantucket.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Then
DM: Eric... No, you weren't there, Mike.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It was Eric, Kate-
Delwath: That was the follow-up then
DM: ... Kong, and
DM: John.
Unknown: And then one with Schwartz.
DM: And then there was one that was Schwartz...
DM: No.
DM: Schwartz, Kate, and Kong.
Unknown: What?
DM: You did play with Schwartz.
Kenzo: What, what was your Malwar character?
Wellby: Mm, he was an ex-Chardonian soldier-
Unknown: Oh
Unknown: ... who just got out.
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay.
Seeker: Wait, Eric was in, in that?
DM: Eric wasn't in that.
Kenzo: Oh. Well, 'cause yeah, babies probably.
DM: No, no, no. That was, I think that was right after you found out your mom had cancer.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, jeez.
Unknown: Man.
Kenzo: Yeah, we started this shit in 2020.
Unknown: Damn.
DM: This was 2021.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: So Malwar, Malwar was basically, Malwar was
DM: pre...
DM: Malwar was before you had...
DM: It was all pre-children for Eric.
Unknown: [laughs] Wow.
DM: It was, it start because it was all, all of the Malwar games were in, were like summer through winter-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... of 2021 basically.
Wellby: A lot happened in your life in the last five years.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Jesus.
Seeker: So much. It's been, uh, a lot.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Mm. A lot, a lot.
DM: But I'm not con- I mean, you know, it's been, like it's been four years since anybody played those characters, so we're not obligated to go back.
Kenzo: It's been four years?
Unknown: Since we did Malwar, yeah.
DM: It's tw- all of the Malwar episodes were 2021.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
DM: This is why I have detailed notes of everything.
DM: Oh, we did... There was one that we played like that spring when like I was traveling and Schwartz had COVID,
DM: and we like vaguely tried to play, but everybody was just exhausted, and we kind of gave up halfway through, and we're like, "We're all way too tired.
DM: Why are we doing this?"
Kenzo: Oh, you were in a hotel, right?
DM: I was in a hotel.
Kenzo: Okay, yeah, yeah. I kind of remember that.
DM: You were like-
Unknown: I don't remember that. [laughs]
DM: You had like just start- You were like on, had just started Paxlovid or something, and you were like, "I'm gonna try."
DM: Then like an hour in you're like, "I...
DM: No. Why am I doing this?"
Kenzo: I have a vague memory of that, yeah.
Delwath: We, when we... You were... Wait, were you here when we were talking about making up characters as part of this time rather than...
Delwath: No, no. We were just talking about how, like if we're gonna run a four session thing-
DM: Mm
Delwath: ... maybe the most fun thing to do, especially given time constraints and having a hard time, have people not having blocks of time, is just the first time we play all make up characters together.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: And we're all build.
DM: Oh, I love that.
Kenzo: Yeah. We do that for like a couple hours.
Unknown: So like make up a party.
Kenzo: Make up a party-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... set it up, and then, and then we play for like three or four sessions or whatever.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: And then we repeat.
Unknown: That'd be really fun.
Kenzo: Yeah, that, that sounds awesome.
Unknown: It sounds re-
Unknown: Yeah, sounds great.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Real question though is, uh, yeah, so like what are they gonna be?
Kenzo: I guess, but also like DM-ing.
Unknown: Like how do we handle the DM thing?
DM: Yeah. So this is the question.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like who wants to run something?
Delwath: I mean, I'd run something.
Kenzo: Dude, that'd be awesome. That'd be fun.
Kenzo: All these years, Mike, you know, you guys have even played shit that I DM'd back in high school.
DM: It's true.
Unknown: 'Cause there was that-
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... Who, who was it? Was it us?
Delwath: It was the four of us when Tim was dating Allison Prostok.
Unknown: Yeah, it was Tim-
Unknown: It was Cyberpunk.
Seeker: But wait. Yeah, but wouldn't...
Kenzo: But why was I DM-ing?
Delwath: Who, who, Tim? Wait. Did, did you-
DM: I thought Mike DM'd Cyberpunk DM.
Wellby: I DM'd Cyberpunk.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, you DM'd Cyberpunk.
Kenzo: Wait, did you run Cyberpunk sometimes?
Kenzo: No, no, no. I, I came up with another, uh, the, this own thing.
Kenzo: It was basically, it was kind of like, we only played a couple times, but it was based on like Dragon Ball Z basically.
Unknown: It was like-
Unknown: I don't, I don't-
Kenzo: I don't know if you guys remember this at all
Unknown: ... think I played this.
Unknown: Like, uh...
Unknown: Maybe.
Kenzo: It was definitely some combination of you guys that played it.
Delwath: It sounds not unfamiliar.
Kenzo: Yeah. And you, it all started 'cause you guy-...
Kenzo: Basically, like the kind of premise was you guys started with the fucking super powerful items that, but nobody knew that it was, and then you lost them in like the very, like the first, the first,
Kenzo: you know, thing that happened.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: Yeah, I have no recollection.
Kenzo: Yeah. Anyways, it was sort, it was still like a fantasy, like, you know-
DM: Right
Kenzo: ... foresty thing, and you guys were characters.
Kenzo: And they were basically like these little, like they were, they were basically like the Dragon Balls.
Kenzo: They were like these like s- like these powerful...
Kenzo: It was onl- we only did like a couple sessions and then life.
Kenzo: But I would love, I would love to play, uh, like a fantasy one.
DM: So Mike's gonna run something in Talgar, but maybe in back in history sometime.
Delwath: I mean, I don't...
Delwath: Like far back in history?
Delwath: Do you think it...
DM: Not necessarily.
Delwath: The least prep thing for me to do would just be to run something in 1720.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Where I have a ton of
Unknown: material for it.
Kenzo: All right, I have an idea.
Kenzo: Why don't we each go around and say the thing that, an idea that we would personally be most excited to play?
DM: Yeah. That's a great idea.
Kenzo: All right. I'll, uh, so mine I think-
Unknown: Oh, not to DM, to play.
Kenzo: Or, or just to play or DM, whatever.
Kenzo: Any- anything that we would want to do.
Unknown: To participate in.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, to participate in or to DM, whatever.
DM: You can say one of each if you want to say one of each.
Kenzo: Yeah. For me, I would be most stoked to play the, um, the like arcane, like weird, just, you know,
Kenzo: alternate Shemut winds-
DM: Right
Kenzo: ... like, and we're the rebels in some-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like cyberpunky, like, or steampunky, you know.
Kenzo: That would be like really fun.
Unknown: Some sort of alt timeline mashup.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I really want to run that, but I, I can't do that next.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: No, no, no. But, but just, I'm just saying that for me, I think that's like one I'd be like stoked to play.
Kenzo: That'd, that'd be really fun. I'd be super into that.
Wellby: I'd love to play before time be...
Wellby: Like, I would enjoy DM'ing something before time began, where it's more about like-
Unknown: Ooh.
DM: Oh
Wellby: ... it's less about like exploring a time or a place as exploring like an idea or a-
DM: You know what you should look at?
Unknown: ... concept or a... Huh?
DM: So, uh, um, there is a,
DM: there is a, a f- a var- like a variant set of Fate rules that are called-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... like Gods and Heroes or something that's basically like you play gods.
DM: I mean, I don't know if anybody has time to read another set of Fate rules.
DM: They're pretty easy to pick up as a player.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: They're a little bit more work as a DM to get the vibe.
Delwath: I mean, it's hard to run a D&D game in that context.
Wellby: Yeah, I don't think you-
Unknown: You could run like a-
Wellby: I don't think you could run D&D.
Delwath: But you could run like...
Wellby: You'd have to find a different system.
Unknown: That's okay.
Kenzo: Would be a lot of work.
DM: Well, most... D&D is one of the m- most difficult systems to prep games for of all the role playing systems that exist.
Unknown: So true.
DM: So if you could find something that was quick and easy to prep for.
Delwath: But there's also, there's actually a mechanic where you can just run rules like role playing where you just-
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Essentially.
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... you just take the D&D mechanic of a num- of a D20-
Wellby: Right. You can-
Unknown: Totally. Totally
DM: ... just a D20 system where it's basically just-
Delwath: Totally. And you just kind of beat-
Wellby: Kind of things like, like what if-
Unknown: ... arbitrary
Wellby: ... what if time had a spatial dimension and like you...
Wellby: Or what if things were circular, or what if,
Wellby: what if it looped around again and again, or what if every character who's being played was the same character at different stages of their own life?
Wellby: Or like,
Wellby: I don't know, things like that.
Delwath: It feels fascinating. It might be hard to like sustain for...
Wellby: Well, I think this what could make it a good like a two session-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... or a three session sort of a thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Like you sort of explore one-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... one idea or more.
Wellby: I also think like something Feywilds-
Unknown: Mm
Wellby: ... could be fun to run.
Wellby: Like something where...
DM: Oh, you should totally run a all Feywild game.
Wellby: Like that would be...
DM: I'll just give you a, a realm and you can go wild with it.
Wellby: I would have a good time with that.
Unknown: Ooh.
Wellby: I'd have a really good time with that.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: That would be easy to do just with D&D, right?
Unknown: Like we can just do-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... level five or level seven or whatever.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Entirely set in the Feywild.
DM: Everybody has to play a fey character or somebody like Mike's
DM: Trakoran soldier who got sucked into the Feywild.
DM: I really like, I really liked making up...
Unknown: Like Feywild was-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... amazing to invent, and each realm is its own little distinct piece, so you can totally just take a realm and you can make up whatever you want and it can be completely different.
DM: Well, there's a few basic rules, but other than the few basic rules.
Wellby: I read one time some...
Wellby: Maybe this is Neil Gaiman years ago, like distilled like here are 25 fairy tale rules.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
Wellby: And it was just like a list of-
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: And like to think of like creating that for each kingdom having its own-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... like set of rules.
Unknown: Well, like the-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... the key overarching rule of the Talgarian Feywild is the sun, the time-
Wellby: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... effect where it
Unknown: goes-
Unknown: Distance rather than time
Unknown: ... distance-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... rather than time, and also
DM: the sort of basic idea that the, a realm takes on the identity of its leader.
DM: But that actually gives you a lot of flexibility-
Wellby: Totally
Unknown: ... to make a realm however you want.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Who knows? The like the time of...
Wellby: So the location is the time of day.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Is also like the mood of the place.
DM: Well, that's... Yeah, that's more about the, the ruler.
Delwath: Although you can have, I mean, the same time of day can actually have different moods.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Well, like that, like that would be interesting conflict.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Right. Mm-hmm.
Delwath: It's just tricky. Some of the...
Unknown: I guess you could be...
Delwath: You can go north-south.
Delwath: There's a almost infinite space north-south.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: There's parts of the Feywild that are fairly crowded,
Delwath: but it's really easy to,
Unknown: to...
DM: There's a, there's a bunch... And there's actually, the Feywild's kind of fun 'cause there's a bunch of stuff like I made up for
DM: the, for Ulfgar's book, The Lore of the Feywild, that's essentially just a name.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And so it's just like an evocative name, and there's like no-
Unknown: Nothing
Unknown: ... nothing made up-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... but except the name.
DM: And so it's totally like you could just run wild with the name-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... and be like, whatever you wanna do with that.
Wellby: I also feel like the, the way like time and distance in the Feywild is complicated, like the, um,
Wellby: uh...
Wellby: Even if like the border, like the edges are accurate, like the space between any two borders could be like-
Unknown: Is not... Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... there could be a bridge over a river.
Wellby: That's the distance it is.
Wellby: But if you cross the river, it's an ocean wide.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Well, you sort of...
DM: I mean, you also... I mean, I, I don't know if this was too subtle, you kind of experienced that when you were on the cl- cloud spinner quest where,
DM: uh, it was harder to make progress going away, like in that realm that was the sort of everybody partying realm.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: It was hard...
DM: It was harder to travel going away from the party than towards the party.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: So distances were just-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... the same distance was longer or shorter-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... depending on which direction you were going.
Kenzo: So this is, this is like a, um,
Kenzo: a suggestion on your earlier kind of like, uh, like more abstract set of things.
Kenzo: I think you, you could also...
Kenzo: Like this is a non-Feywild idea, but it could be more like, you know, like you were saying like before, like whatever was happening before time, before there were rules or any kind of thing.
Kenzo: It could be something that's sort of like, like the setup is like there are two brothers
Unknown: and,
Kenzo: you know, it's like something really basic and then like you can like have like a couple of simple mechanics that are, you know, just like you're saying, it's like and they, they, they like,
Kenzo: they like walk down a path where,
Kenzo: you know, and you set up-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you know, so but, but that's, that's more like pre-ti- And then it's sort of like, you know, and we can play it, and if it, if there, if it like kind of catches into something interesting, then that can like feed into
Kenzo: the, like, you know, some of the, the we- 'cause you know, there's all this like, it's like we're, we're a limbo ca- You know, like all of the non...
Kenzo: You know, like the weird like whatever the fuck outside of the multiverse.
Kenzo: Like what is the thing we just played where there was a character that wasn't even from-
Delwath: The Far Realms?
Unknown: Yeah. The-
Seeker: Oh, I got a... I actually have a bunch of things I can talk to you about.
Kenzo: So anyways, you know what I'm saying?
Wellby: Yeah. There's good stuff there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. So but that can be more like abstract.
Unknown: I, I-
Kenzo: You don't have to worry about Feywild, and you can just do something really, really weird and out there.
Delwath: Mostly my idea for my next session-
Unknown: So
Kenzo: ... which I need to finish prepping, is a dragon fleeing the-
Unknown: You put that one.
Wellby: Yeah, you mentioned that.
Delwath: But I, but I was wondering if ...
Delwath: the burned forest would be a good place for a red dragon to have been coming from.
Delwath: That's why I wanted to know if you knew it was there.
Delwath: What I actually need, the, the, the mechanic I'm trying to do is, it's a two session arc.
Delwath: But the dragon was fleeing the Plaguelands, so I kind of want to set it up so that they kill the dragon in the first session, but then have to go into the Plaguelands and find its, its
Delwath: lair, 'cause they want its treasure.
Delwath: And its lair would have to be... Maybe not the burned forest, I think that's too deep.
DM: The burned forest is pretty deep.
Delwath: Yeah. It would have to be something less deep into the Plaguelands.
DM: I have a few Plaguelands notes.
DM: I'll try and push them to...
DM: Well, we can discuss on Discord.
DM: Yeah. Anyway, I, I like-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I like the...
DM: I would love to play in a Plaguelands.
Unknown: I would love to... I, I-
DM: That's awesome. You should totally do that.
Delwath: I, the experimental role playing is, I'm happy to play in it, but it's a little bit less what I'm excited about.
Delwath: But the Feywild-
Wellby: Yeah, Feywild would be good
Delwath: ... would be awesome. And I mean, the Arcane one would be fun too.
DM: Well, I'm, I'm really excited-
Unknown: I mean, either one
DM: ... to run the Arcane one, it just can't be the next thing we do.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. What about you, Eric?
Unknown: I'm still, I'm not sure.
Seeker: I love the, the cyberpunk and space opera type theme.
Delwath: And we don't have to run things in Talgar, also.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: We could just do a space. I mean, if-
Wellby: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... if the goal, I mean, we could just all, like, rotate.
Unknown: I mean, we could,
Delwath: three of us could all DM stuff, right?
Delwath: Three sessions isn't a huge commitment.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Like, it might be interesting to play, like, space opera or, like, planet hopping would lend itself to, like,
Wellby: like, an anthology campaign where it's, like, maybe the different games are thematically connected, even if they're not
Wellby: the same characters.
Delwath: Like the different sessions in a...
Wellby: Yeah, exactly. In-
DM: Yeah. I mean, but-
Wellby: Like, different episodes in an anthology show.
DM: Well, I would say, I mean, the tricky thing, the thing, the first thing with space opera is figuring out what, whether, what system you want to run.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And whether you...
DM: But there's some, so there's a few,
DM: I haven't read it, but there's one called, I think, Worlds Without Numbers, that's supposed to be, like, a really good-
Delwath: Is that, um...
Delwath: There's another system that-
DM: So it's based on the, like, Star Wars role playing game.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Which was, like, a D6 based system.
Unknown: Yeah. There, there is-
Wellby: We could play that
DM: ... But Worlds Without Numbers, the, the rule book is, like, three pages long.
Delwath: There is a system, actually, that-
DM: It's like-
Delwath: Actually, there's a system that might work really well for your pre-time.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: I forget what it's called. It's, um,
Unknown: Dungeon...
DM: Dungeon World?
Delwath: Dungeon World. Is it Dungeon World?
DM: That would, that's not a good pre-time thing.
Delwath: It's the one where it's just storytelling and you have actions you can-
DM: Yeah. Dungeon World is a sort of weird system.
DM: I-
Unknown: You know what it's a-
DM: Some people really like it.
DM: I've read, I read the rules, 'cause they're really short, and I found it to just be the worst combination of both worlds, right?
DM: It's not free form and the...
DM: Like, Fate I kind of like, although I don't fully, like I don't...
DM: We tried Fate once, and I don't think we fully got it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, I don't think Fate works great for Talgar because it,
DM: it requires... It might work for, like, pre-time stuff.
DM: Fate works much better when you're, when you feel like the world is totally flexible, that you can change any, like, because the whole-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: Mm
DM: ... story about, the whole way it works-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... is the players are supposed to have narrative control over
DM: changing the world.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And you can just use your abilities to be like, "This is here for me to use."
Delwath: That's perfect in pre-time.
DM: Which is, might work really well pre-time.
Unknown: Yeah, that's pretty sweet.
DM: The problem with Dungeon World is it,
DM: it, it has, you have, like, character sh- Like, you have a specified set of moves you can do.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You have character sheets like D&D, but then it's like this weird sort of
DM: players versus DM vibe, where the players do something and the DM has a list of counter moves that you can make to what the players do.
DM: I just, like, don't understand the vibe of why it would be fun.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: So I-
DM: But maybe you-
Wellby: I've listened-
DM: You've played Monster of the Week, right?
DM: Or you listened to it last-
Wellby: No, I listened to a,
Wellby: a actual play podcast which is based on, like, a variant of a variant of, uh, Dungeon World.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Where one of the moves is, um, like a spout lore move where any, which everyone has-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... where you're creating information about the world.
Wellby: And I think it depends so much on, like, the skill and the relationship between the players and the DM.
Wellby: There's a,
Wellby: a shared set of agreements about, like, what's in bounds and out of bounds-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... that never appears, like, in the text of that podcast.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: But they must spend a lot of time-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... thinking about it.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Because it feels highly collaborative.
Wellby: It feels not adversarial at all.
Delwath: I mean, it's, it's come up when I've read about-
Wellby: Hm.
Delwath: It's come up for me most often in the context of people who are like, "That's not a real game because it's collaborative storytelling."
DM: Right. Right.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: But we kind of like collaborative storytelling.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, that's actually-
Wellby: I don't have much patience for those people.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Wellby: A game is anything that's fun.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, there's a game design theory that says game has to include a certain am- Activities are anything that's fun.
Delwath: It doesn't have to be a game. I was talking to Eric
Delwath: about this. There's game design theory that implies that a game has to have a certain level of challenge.
Delwath: But it doesn't necessarily mean that it's a negative to say this doesn't fit as a game.
Unknown: It doesn't.
Delwath: I, I, that was a positive to me.
Delwath: My point was Dungeon World came across my radar positively because people who are sort of annoying about what's real games and what's fake games were negative
Unknown: on it-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... as too much collaborative storytelling.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: But I, I just, I like the f- I like the free form vibe better.
DM: Maybe I, I mean, maybe I need to read the rules more.
DM: I like, I like the idea, like Fate Light is, like, six pages of rules.
Wellby: Right. Mm.
DM: Dungeon World is, like, you have to learn a lot of rules.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: That's true.
DM: So then I'm like, why bother playing that?
Wellby: The understanding and selection of the moves is like-
DM: Yeah. Yeah
Wellby: ... that feels heavy.
DM: Right.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: So it's like, why would I want to play a, a rules heavy narrative game?
DM: If I'm playing a narrative game-
Wellby: Fair
DM: ... I explicitly want it to be rules light.
Unknown: That is-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: Yo, like D&D Beyond, I, I feel like I didn't really, really, really start to like really understand how to play D&D Beyond until like today.
DM: Right. [laughs]
Kenzo: You know what I mean? Like just like-
DM: You did a pretty good job using D&D Beyond.
Kenzo: No, that's what I'm saying. Now I-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... I was finally like understanding like bonus actions-
DM: And now you know what this character is. [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah, like fucking like bonus actions-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and reactions and all that shit, you know what I mean?
Kenzo: It took me like five years to like-
DM: Yeah, really. Yeah
Kenzo: ... 'cause before I would kind of like I'll just sort of like let you guys be like, "Uh, it's like a bonus action.
Kenzo: Okay. I don't know. Like what's a bonus action?
Kenzo: When can I use a reaction?" And now I do-
DM: Wow. Kate would be very happy to hear this, 'cause it...
DM: her least favorite part of D&D, D&D is the fact that there's bonus actions, actions, and reactions.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And they're all different things.
Unknown: Dude, that shit's confusing as fuck.
DM: Like, why are they fucking different things?
Kenzo: Dude, they're just, they're so confusing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And when can you use which in which situation-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and what is what, and like you guys are masters of that.
Kenzo: You actually have that really good understanding well over, over all s- sure as hell.
Wellby: It took me so long. It took me till like Yuri to understand the action economy and be like-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... "I have 11 things I can do, and four of them only go in this category-"
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly
Unknown: "... and six of them go in that."
Kenzo: Like, like it literally was like today.
Kenzo: I think like today I-
Unknown: It's like a potion paste
Kenzo: ... I think I finally, I finally got it.
DM: But my point is-
Unknown: That there's just too many fucking-
DM: The larger point is like I'm fi- I'm, I'm happy.
DM: Like I will obviously keep playing D&D.
DM: I'm not... I do not think that this group should attempt any other...
DM: to learn anything else where the rule book is more than two pages long.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Dude, I'm so with you.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: I'm so-
Unknown: That's a, that's a good point.
DM: Right? D&D Plus.
Kenzo: You, you, you are reading the room well.
Unknown: You read the room well.
DM: Like anything that has a rule page, a rule book-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... that we can read in the first 30 minutes-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... of the session-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... and know how to play-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... by the end of those 30 minutes.
Kenzo: Totally. I, I-
DM: That's the maximum capacity
Kenzo: ... I am so, so with that.
Seeker: One, one thing I wonder about is if I were to do a space opera or some other,
Seeker: um, interesting theme that I was DM'ing, how to bring in
Seeker: some c- a combination of a rules light system and the storytelling mechanics that are like a little bit bespoke each time that you've done, 'cause I like that stuff so much.
Unknown: Like-
DM: But-
Seeker: Something that combines
Seeker: literally like world building, idea generation-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... with gaming.
DM: So a, some of the, I don't know, I don't know the rules of the rules light systems well enough, but some of them support that much more naturally than D&D does.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So you don't have to do as much scaffolding around the rules as I do in order to make that work.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: But you can also actually just explicitly...
Delwath: There's no actual...
Delwath: I don't... Well, I mean, I don't feel like our enjoyment of Limbo would have been less if we hadn't been making rolls at all,
Unknown: for like-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Delwath: ... the, the creative narrative part, right?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Like there wasn't actually...
Delwath: Because we're playing D&D and 'cause Tim sort of felt like we should, I guess, or whatever, like there's a certain mechanic, but if you're running a space opera game with a narrative, with a creative challenge
Kenzo: like that, it doesn't have to have a roll at all.
Unknown: But-
Unknown: But I was thinking like the-
Unknown: Yeah. That's great
Wellby: ... like that can also be a place where the, the roll preceding the narrative-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... works better. So it's like if it's a, you know, failure, partial success, success is what the roll is, and then narratively the task is like what does that look like?
DM: Right. But, so this-
Wellby: So I know I failed. What does my failure look like?
DM: But so like I said before, I don't remember if everybody was here, part of what it goes back to is, so in D&D there's this tension between character skills and player
DM: skills.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And one of the reasons to make rolls is to
DM: reward people's character building choices that give them very high bonuses to skills.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Right.
DM: If you're playing in a system that doesn't have that, then rolls are less meaningful because...
DM: Like for the storytelling mechanic in the Limbo-
Seeker: It should work well if you tell a good story, yeah.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So like the only reason I made you make rolls was so that the people who had really good skills didn't have to tell as good stories as the people who had
DM: bad skills.
Wellby: But the, the roll and then describe achieves the same outcome.
DM: Yeah, yeah. It achieves the same outcome if...
Unknown: If, if-
DM: Well, no, it doesn't actually, because then it,
DM: it eliminates player skill.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Sort of. That's its own reward, but-
DM: Well, well-
Unknown: I think so the, the-
Delwath: But it depends on what you're trying to do
Wellby: ... the, the player skill is like the, the pleasure of creating something interesting for everybody in the scenario.
DM: Right. But in the Limbo challenge, the player skill-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... was saving a monk and getting through.
Delwath: It, it, it depends on how much you as the player care about beating the challenge versus telling a story.
Unknown: Oh, right.
Delwath: Right? Like in the Limbo scenario, it depends would you get as much satisfaction from telling the story about how Wellby failed to save a monk?
Wellby: I w- so for me, I would.
Unknown: You, yes.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But, but it, but-
DM: But other people-
DM: But I'm like the point
DM: ... yeah, yeah. [coughs]
Delwath: Yes, right. It, it, it's, there's a, there's a difference between like-
Kenzo: Let's see. But, but this is sort of like just like I think the, you know, the, the whole like thing I was sharing about like the, the YouTuber like kind of-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like, you know? And it's like even the thing I like ran with like Jen-
DM: Yeah. Yeah
Kenzo: ... and a friend where the die rolling is just like, oh, like can you hear it or not hear it?
Kenzo: And if you can't hear it... Or you can hear it, oh, you hear this.
Kenzo: Or you can't hear it, oh fuck, then I need to figure out how to get closer-
DM: Yeah. Yeah
Kenzo: ... so I can hear it, you know?
Unknown: It's just-
Unknown: So it's like-
Seeker: ... to create interesting dynamics that are outside of someone's decision making.
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's like-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... it replaces the notion of simulation.
Unknown: But also-
Seeker: It just like creates a little bit of unexpected twists.
Delwath: Well, there's, there's that-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... for sure, and there's also the idea that every
Delwath: failure is just a
Delwath: new opportunity to come up with a new idea, like what Kong was saying, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Like if you can't hear it-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... you gotta try something else.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: And so like-
Unknown: So just use some chance-
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly
Unknown: ... to drive that some of the time.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right. Yeah.
Kenzo: But that's like really generative and super fun.
Kenzo: It's like, you know, like just... Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So.
Seeker: And then the storytelling mechanics themselves are very naturally fantasy oriented, because it's like you imagine something and it just becomes real-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... in certain settings that are like very imaginary.
Seeker: But there's a sci-fi version of that too, like-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: Eric, Eric, I'm sorry I missed, because I was in the bathroom.
Kenzo: But like what, so like is the thing that you are most, what you most care about or are m- most interested in to do a space opera?
Unknown: Or is it-
Seeker: I obviously have been interested in that in the past, I think 'cause I- You know, read a lot of sci-fi.
Unknown: I just enjoy that stuff.
Seeker: So that's one thing. Another one is, of course, like
Unknown: the portal to-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... from into-
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... our wor- into Earth-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: ... from Talgar, and then something chaotic happens.
Seeker: But it has... One thing I like about that, like we did in the cyberpunk one, is that the, the world building part is kind of grounded in...
Seeker: Like, one time we went to Dunkin' Donuts, and then you can imagine that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: And it has all kinds of things-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... that you can then manipulate in that world based on what you already know about it to be true.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: Uh, and so it feels like a fun kind of playground.
Seeker: So we could take, like what was the, you know, map of Lexington Center in 1990, and like, what were the stores, and like we could go in each one and like-
Kenzo: Dude, the like Pewter Pot.
Unknown: That's fun.
Unknown: Chadwicks.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: What was the Banana Buster?
Unknown: Reenactments that-
Unknown: Belly Buster. Belly Buster
Unknown: ... we did at Chadwicks.
Kenzo: Belly Buster, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: All this, all this stuff.
Unknown: Chadwicks.
Seeker: And we just happen to have that in common-
Unknown: I know
Unknown: ... which is kind of funny, too.
Unknown: Like,
Unknown: um, so-
Unknown: Coffee connection
Unknown: ... and then, and then c- Yeah, exactly.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Steve's Ice Cream.
Unknown: Steve's.
Unknown: Collide that with-
Unknown: Holy shit
Seeker: ... a creature is wreaking havoc-
Unknown: Steve
Unknown: ... in the library or whatever.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Right, right.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: And then do we play Talgar characters arriving in Lexington?
Seeker: Do we play ourselves at age 11?
Unknown: Do we-
Delwath: I, I actually don't love the play yourself in a D&D game or in a role playing game personally.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, I'm happy to do it if other people want to, but like that is definitely not my favorite.
Wellby: Like I play myself every time.
Unknown: I play exactly. [laughs]
Unknown: Right, right.
Unknown: So you'd rather play a-
DM: Well, it works, it works much better if it's in the other direction, if it's you going into a fantasy world.
Unknown: Which we did once and I liked.
Unknown: We did, and I liked.
Kenzo: [laughs] That's true. It's like u- us playing ourselves in high school.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah. Like what's the point, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: To be honest, yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, I... The idea of playing a Talgar character
Delwath: in Lexington sounds kind of more fun to me-
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... than playing myself in Lexington.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right? But-
Unknown: And then would we encounter,
Seeker: as Talgar characters, these high school kids?
Unknown: I don't know.
Seeker: But then the DM would have to play those, so maybe they have vanished or something.
Unknown: Well, I mean-
Unknown: Anyway
Delwath: ... it doesn't have to be like...
Delwath: It depends on what you're trying to do with the story.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Like-
Kenzo: Well, where I kind of felt you were going was sort of like, oh, like if you go to Chadwicks, and then like you ordered the Belly Buster, like whoever these characters are, if they're fantasy or sci-fi, whatever.
Kenzo: They order the, the Belly Buster, and then they eat it, and then suddenly they realize that they can grow 10 feet tall or...
Kenzo: You know what I mean? That like just now these weird things start happening to them because of the thing that they ordered on the menu or-
Delwath: I mean, when, when, when Tim did the We Went to Talgar, I mean, the mechanic was that-
Unknown: You all start to gain the powers of your characters
Delwath: ... we all start to become our,
Unknown: our characters.
Unknown: [laughs] That's right.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: And so we started to gain sort of the-
Kenzo: That actually is crazy, 'cause then it's like you can ca- sleep on your teachers and like, I don't know.
Unknown: Right. Yeah.
Delwath: Right. I mean, there's another mechanic where it's like...
Unknown: Yeah. And it,
Unknown: it-
DM: But yeah, I don't really have any interest in role playing myself at 13.
Unknown: No, no, no, no. That doesn't make sense.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: But E- Eric, are you...
Kenzo: Like I'm cur- Like are you...
Kenzo: Like two questions. One is like, is there like a particular type of like story that you're interested?
Kenzo: And then two is like, is there a particular type of like game that you're y- or like style of
Kenzo: like role playing-
Unknown: Which one?
Kenzo: ... that you'd like to DM?
Unknown: I'm not sure. So for the,
Seeker: the story, a couple years ago I did write down some notes, I'll have to pull them back up again, about like what
Seeker: some crisis could be where like
Seeker: some evil creatures from Talgar appear in Lexington, and then like you're a party that appears also from Talgar, and you're like, "What are we doing here?"
Seeker: And then like some bad stuff's happening and you're like, "Okay, we can help."
Unknown: Like,
Unknown: so
Unknown: a short.
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: I like that. I don't know if we could use D&D mechanics for that.
Unknown: Yeah, it's well adjusted.
Delwath: D&D mechanics would work fine for something like that.
DM: If you're doing Talgar, if you're doing fantasy characters in the modern world, you should just run D&D.
Seeker: It's just gonna have like the Lexington Police and Fire Department.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, that's fine.
DM: D&D has firearms rules.
DM: We can use the standard firearm.
Unknown: Like that's not our problem.
Unknown: But what, what's the-
Unknown: Well-
Wellby: ... like tone of that, like that you imagine?
Unknown: Yeah. I can't tell if the tone-
Unknown: Like I-
DM: ... is like cosmic horror or like-
Wellby: I'm imagining like action comedy.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, action comedy is probably-
Wellby: Like, uh, you have to go...
Wellby: You have to get like town meeting to vote to authorize you to-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: To fight the enemy-
Unknown: Right. Is it-
Wellby: ... or you have to like-
Seeker: Right. Is it like stealth action adventure or more like goofy sitcom?
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Or something in between? I don't know.
Seeker: And it... Or is it more about like visiting a bunch of nostalgia moments with-
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: Or something too.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: I, I think I'm just a- attracted to that one by like the, the, the richness of the world, it being rich in a completely different way, 'cause we just have like shared reference.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: [coughs] And then the kind of collision with Talgar is fun, like-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... the, the trick is to make it like not completely chaotic.
Seeker: Like how would you build up the complexity a l- from a little bit at a time, like...
Unknown: Yeah. That, that-
Unknown: That's the premise
DM: ... that's a little bit trickier to...
Unknown: That's a,
DM: that's a s- I think that's a slightly tricky...
DM: It, it's definitely possible to come up with a way to run it, but it's g- it would require a little bit of thought to make that-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... into a satisfying story.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's another thing.
Delwath: It's definitely
Delwath: Right. I mean, there's a lot of things you can do with it, right, in terms of, like,
Delwath: small things leaking.
Unknown: You could do...
Delwath: You could even do something where,
Delwath: you know, Lexington is leaking into Talgar.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Whoa. What would that be like?
Wellby: Or the gentrification.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: There's, there's a neighborhood in Talgar that starts going up.
Unknown: [coughs]
Delwath: I mean, not really, but that's like-
Kenzo: That like Chardon High is like super competitive and has like, you know...
Unknown: Or just-
Unknown: The, the-
Delwath: The actual feywild domain that's just Lexington
Seeker: Or a several mile across
Unknown: chunk of
Seeker: earth just is dropped into
Unknown: Dunmore or something.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Yeah, I mean, that's similar to what we...
DM: That, that's kind of like the original idea.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Actually, that's true.
Unknown: One, right?
Delwath: I mean, you could also do... I mean, it...
Delwath: Like if you go for like the horror aspect too, right?
Delwath: Like, you could also go for like, well, what would it be...
Delwath: I mean, 'cause the way you could play it, like Stranger Things-esque, right, where it's like-
Unknown: Yep. Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, people just start getting killed and like
Delwath: There's like, okay, well, if actually a group of orcs like showed up in Lexington, it would be super terrifying.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: They're like these monsters, right?
Unknown: I don't know.
Unknown: Hm.
Delwath: It seems like one that needs a fair bit of...
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: You'd have to have the energy to actually-
Unknown: The time, yeah
Delwath: ... the time to come up with something, right?
Kenzo: Is, is there a system that you, you like, Eric?
Seeker: Oh, for DMing? I don't know.
Unknown: Yeah, I don't know enough about...
Seeker: Like I, I can look at the one that you mentioned, which was-
DM: Worlds Without Numbers, I think it's called.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I, I think it's called that.
Kenzo: You know, one thing we could do for one of these sessions is, um, we could just like,
Kenzo: like just prototype a couple of systems, just like fuck around for like 15 minutes or whatever, just see like, hey, what is this like?
Kenzo: And then kind of be like, "Uh, this kind of sucks.
Kenzo: Oh, this is kind of interesting." You know?
DM: I think it's hard to get a sense from only that, but I-
Unknown: I suppose that's true.
Delwath: And somebody needs to know, like it's actually really tough to be a DM, doesn't it?
Unknown: So I think it...
DM: Somebody can teach it, but it's different, yeah.
DM: I think it's fun, but it has to be something where... Like I like the, you have to be able to learn to play in 30 minutes without any prep because I think that's like a bar to me.
Unknown: Yes, agree. Super agree.
DM: But the d- the whoever's running that session-
Kenzo: Needs to know it, yeah
DM: ... has to have read through the rules in advance.
Unknown: Right, right, right.
Unknown: And have had time to look at it.
DM: And then our like session zero for that little mini arc is-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... everybody learns the rules, and we make characters.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: And we like-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... learn enough about it.
DM: And then you could... You really gotta give it like two sessions before you know if you like the system.
Seeker: Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: That's true.
Seeker: So there's Worlds Without Number,
Seeker: which is compatible with Stars Without Number,
Unknown: which is the sci-fi one.
DM: Yeah, maybe. I don't know if this is exactly what I was thinking of, but...
Unknown: What about you, Mike?
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: what do you want to play or DM, or both?
Unknown: I,
Delwath: honestly, mostly like...
Delwath: I'm more interested in like places in more a traditional...
Delwath: I think if I was running something, I'd wanna run just like a, you know,
Delwath: regular D&D arc, but
Unknown: somewhere,
Delwath: somewhere new in Talgar.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: New-ish at least.
Kenzo: Yeah. Like where?
Unknown: Uh, I don't know.
Unknown: Like,
Delwath: not wildly new.
Delwath: I like, I don't wanna like make up a brand new, like the Golden City or something.
Delwath: That seems too... I actually like there being exotic places-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... that are just not really ever like developed.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But like somewhere we haven't really...
Delwath: I don't know, like
Delwath: I haven't really thought about it. I don't have a specific idea.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I mean, the easiest thing for me to run would be reuse prep that I do for the, my, my current game.
Unknown: Where's your current game?
Unknown: Sambarra.
Kenzo: Sambarra. When is it set?
Unknown: 1720.
Unknown: And when is that?
DM: I mean, we've not played anything in Sambarra.
Unknown: I know.
Kenzo: It's set, it's set when? What-
Unknown: 1720.
Unknown: That's-
Delwath: So it's 30, 20 years.
Unknown: 30 years.
Kenzo: Oh, so it's right when, when, uh, Rye steps on the
DM: Yeah, it's im- it's in the, it's immediately after what I talked about.
Delwath: It's actually a plot point in my...
Delwath: There's a re- there's a dragon fleeing the...
Delwath: My next adventure is a dragon that's fleeing the Plaguelands because Rye's limbo wave caused all this trouble, and the dragon's running away
Unknown: from the ooze.
Kenzo: Wow, that's cool.
Kenzo: The ooze that we just killed.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Whoa. [laughs]
Seeker: That's awesome. I, I just found my notes for Seeker's cursed RPG, which we never got to do, but...
Kenzo: Oh my God, I wanna play Seeker's game.
Delwath: [laughs] I, that would be fun.
Delwath: We should have Seeker as DM.
Kenzo: Seeker should be the DM.
Unknown: Yeah, so we talked about...
DM: Eric and I sort of bounced around ideas on and off for a while about it.
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: And we could never really...
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: It's too hard to work it in.
DM: It's too hard to work something in, and it was never really clear exactly what it would be.
Unknown: Well, the idea in this
Unknown: set of notes is about
Seeker: just after he was cursed.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Running a game
Seeker: that, where his frame story is one thing, but the actual underlying motivation was that he was gonna try to turn everybody else into ice.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Um.
DM: I, I really enjoyed how you played that, Eric.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: The Seeker cursed.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, that was awesome.
Delwath: As I said, the other thing in Talgar I would really like to either play or run is something set during the Downfall Wars.
Unknown: Right. Set-
Kenzo: Oh, the Khar?
Unknown: The Khar.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. That was cool. We were pretty stoked about that last year.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But I think that needs a little bit more than three sessions.
Unknown: [clears throat]
Delwath: There's kind of a lot of development.
Unknown: Maybe not.
Delwath: I don't have any ideas for like a, a three session arc that would work in that timeframe,
DM: or even what type of game it would be, right?
Delwath: Is it like heroes or is it like-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... third level characters like just-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... trying to survive? Wait, was it, I guess maybe Eric and I were talking about this when we went down to the beach this morning, like
Delwath: it's just the world, the world is falling apart.
Delwath: It's total disaster and chaos.
Kenzo: I just, I don't know. I'm not, I'm not as into dark role playing given the darkness of the world.
Unknown: It's like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... I don't wanna run in a, I don't wanna run like a, I wanna play in a world where the-
DM: ... everything's falling apart and it's all disaster at every turn.
Kenzo: Free Rad, man. Free- check out Free Rad.
Unknown: It's a good
Kenzo: peaceful D&D.
Unknown: How about you, Tim?
DM: Well, I wanna run the arcane thing.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hell yeah. Hell yeah, dude. I'm so, I'm so down for that thing.
Delwath: I mean, that's a world where everything's do- but it's fun.
DM: That sounds fun anyway. That's...
DM: What?
DM: Isn't that a world where everything's doomed and falling apart?
DM: True.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But it still sounds super fun.
Delwath: Actually, I wanna run that. That, I wanna play in that too.
Kenzo: Well, I j- I just like that, I just like that you know all the places.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: But then it's like-
DM: Oh, right
Kenzo: ... oh fuck, everything's like totally different in these like weird, cool, interesting ways.
Unknown: So-
DM: I mean, the other thing's-
Kenzo: It's like there's like the adventure itself, but then there's-
Kenzo: What do you, do you wanna play? Is there something you wanna play, in Talgar I mean?
DM: No. I mean, yeah, I'd be happy to play.
Unknown: There's nothing that's like-
DM: But nothing that's like-
Unknown: ... specific
DM: ... specifically jumping out.
DM: Um,
DM: the two things that I've had in mind are, like, throughout this campaign, I've just invented names of a lot of random historical events
DM: that I know nothing about because, like, I'm, I've been, I've been curious for like four years, like what the plague trees were in that, I forget what I called
DM: it.
DM: Like, there was the, when you were doing the werewolf arc-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... there was the, a series of other bad things, things that, um, the guy was researching,
DM: and one of them was,
DM: uh,
DM: the defeat of the plague trees.
Unknown: That's fun.
DM: I don't know. It sounds, it's like a cool name.
DM: I know nothing about it, and I'm, I mean, I'm obviously never gonna make up...
DM: I'm not likely to develop a whole lot of
DM: history that's irrelevant to any-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... actual event.
Unknown: When was the plague trees?
DM: 1600s.
DM: I, there's just like a bunch of those scattered through my notes that are just like random little...
DM: The Summer of Red Storms.
Unknown: [coughs] When was that?
DM: That was 1709.
Unknown: In Denmark?
DM: Oh, that I have a secret about.
DM: I have a l- well, that secret's wrong, actually.
DM: It's sort of wrong.
Unknown: Was that in Denmark?
DM: Yeah, that was the Summer of Red Storms.
DM: I don't really wanna do it.
DM: No, that wasn't in Denmark.
DM: I don't know. So I'd be, I'd be
DM: sort of interested to run something like that if there was like some
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: How long a break from DMing do you want?
Delwath: I mean, it sounds like we could actually run a year.
DM: I mean, if Schwartz actually is like, "Can I run something?"
Delwath: And Schwartz runs two things and Eric runs one or two things, that's like practically a year right there.
DM: Yeah. I mean, other than the arcane thing, I don't, I don't have anything I like-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... super
DM: would be sad not to run.
DM: Although I would like to, I would like to
DM: maybe
DM: try some
DM: different tone, different like style things.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Like, like most of what,
DM: most of what we've run, like this campaign and also Malwar, and most of what I've run has been sort of,
DM: I don't know, how would I describe it?
DM: But like-
Kenzo: Like the kind of classic-
DM: Classic
Unknown: ... like fantasy
DM: ... fantasy. And I'm, I'm, I'm less interested in running the sort of
DM: like,
DM: uh, other style, like other vibes and, or like, like doing like,
DM: you know,
DM: swords and sorcery style or something like that necessarily, um,
DM: as of like changing the setting, but just like the vibe of the camp, like running something that's like-
Unknown: Mm.
DM: I, like we tried to do this a little bit in one of those Toland arcs where like it wasn't, you're not like the heroes out to save the world.
DM: You're like basically bumbling.
DM: You just stumble onto adventure, and it's like much more sort of,
DM: the vibe is different, right?
DM: It's like oriented not around everybody's motivated to be.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Well, it's almost like, like your cyberpunk, you know, adventures were super like that.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: There was just like, the vibe was so different from Talgar.
Unknown: It was just like-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... it's almost like nihilistic character.
Delwath: There's actually something kinda cool about a idea of a session zero collaborating to make up the party.
Delwath: If you have
Unknown: a...
Delwath: You don't necessarily even have to know what the adventure is for session zero if there's a DM.
Unknown: I'd actually-
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I would actually have a ton of fun with that.
Delwath: I would, what I would r- I would actually have a ton of fun with just
Delwath: we do a session zero,
Delwath: and we just figure out where the hell in Talgar it's gonna be and what the vibe's gonna be-
DM: Mm.
Unknown: ... collaboratively.
DM: Nice.
Delwath: And then I'll just make something up and run it.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Let's do that next.
Unknown: Off that.
Unknown: That'd be really fun.
Unknown: We can do, we can do that next.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I love it. Yeah.
Kenzo: That's a good next thing we do.
Unknown: All for it.
DM: Mike's like, "Can I really-
Unknown: Let's see
DM: ... do we really have time to do this?"
Delwath: When would that be? Uh,
Delwath: um, maybe.
Unknown: Yeah, maybe.
Unknown: Well, I mean-
Unknown: I guess, no, I could do that.
Kenzo: But just to take the pressure off too. It's like, yeah, we-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... d- don't, zero prep. Just like-
Kenzo: ... we roll up and then we just, we do the-
Delwath: I mean, a session zero would be easy.
DM: Session zero is zero prep.
DM: You do have to sort of prep something Yeah.
DM: What happens next for Mike?
Kenzo: Well, you know, honestly, and we still have until tomorrow and I- we can kind of do session zero now even, like, you know, between like-
DM: Oh, that's true
Kenzo: ... you know, 'cause we have to fucking like a bunch of hours in the...
Kenzo: We gotta be on the ferry and-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Then we have the ferry and the car. We have-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... we have a bunch of cleaning up to do tomorrow.
Unknown: Of course.
DM: So everybody's gotta get... I mean, it's not even that late.
DM: It's only 11:30.
Delwath: The, the problem is I, so I run a game with my college friends once a month.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: [laughs] I have a lot of prep to do for my November 7th game.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Mm.
Delwath: Is the only problem with...
Delwath: W- honestly, if we...
Delwath: Depends on when we're trying to play next.
Delwath: That's gonna be a two session arc, and I'll have no basic prep to do for-
DM: Well, Kong's about to go to Paris.
DM: When are we gonna... When are people free next?
DM: I don't have my phone right here, so.
Unknown: November.
DM: Well, yeah, but November is only a week away.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I'm, my life gets much more chill after, uh...
Kenzo: Actually, my whole November. This month is fucking bananas.
DM: So this one or-
Kenzo: But November is actually quite chill.
DM: You're, you're... Wait, you're playing on November 9th?
Unknown: November 9th.
Kenzo: Yeah. After November 9 is great.
Delwath: Uh, but I would...
Delwath: I mean, if we, if we,
Delwath: if we didn't do something until the week, I can't...
Delwath: That's such a confusing... Do you have a m- Oh, you can do go to month view.
Kenzo: I, I would lean, though, whatever we do next for it to be different in like some pretty radical ways from what's been
Delwath: I mean, if we were doing a session, if we...
Delwath: I don't think I could prep.
Delwath: I mean, I don't think I'd need to do a ton of prep.
DM: Right.
Unknown: But I'd need to do some prep.
DM: I mean, honestly, I kinda liked the vibe of the f- the Stone Titan, the original very first one we did.
Unknown: Crunk?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: The Legend of Crunk.
Seeker: Oh, and Horatio Hornblower, my mage.
Unknown: But-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Who died, I think, heroically.
Unknown: No, we all survived.
DM: No, you survived.
Unknown: Oh, no. You might have died.
DM: No, you, I think you got your brain eaten by a mind flayer.
Unknown: You might have.
DM: But I enjoyed it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [smacks lips] [sighs] You know, okay.
Kenzo: So just thinking about... 'Cause I was just like sitting here thinking like, "Man," like, "what would I like to explore?"
Kenzo: Now that I think about it,
Kenzo: I think now that I finally understand D&D better, like the rules and stuff like that, I actually think I would be down to play like a different character class to like...
Kenzo: That is medium powerful, just to like have fun with like knowing how to do different shit-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... with like-
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... like actually one character class that I, I...
Kenzo: 'Cause you know, I've now played like a, like a spellcaster from high school, and then this one's like a very tough one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I think I wanna play like a druid.
Kenzo: I think that would be cool.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause like, 'cause like that like-
Unknown: Druid
Kenzo: ... I like the ranger one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause I was like the animal-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... kinda ch- you know?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And I got a cat now and stuff.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: You know what I mean? This was like-
Kenzo: Yeah, druid would be fun
Kenzo: ... I think like a, like a druid like character would be cool.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Like, 'cause you can cast spells and like do a bunch of, you know?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I'm trying to think of what I would, what character I would like to do next.
DM: So this, this is what I...
DM: Well, let me just say, what I think we should do, I would propose we alternate
DM: like Talgar, non-Talgar.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: I like that.
Delwath: Or at least Talgar non-traditional.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So like Arcane would count as non-Talgar.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, true.
DM: Um, but Feywild I would probably count as Talgar.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Maybe not.
Delwath: No, I think Fey- I think-
DM: There's also canon versus non-canon
Delwath: ... I think, I think it's, I think we're alternating canon and non-canon.
Kenzo: Canon and non-canon.
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But I think Feywild is probably canonical unless you wanna go-
DM: No, I want Schwartz to contribute to Talgarverse.
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah, why wouldn't the Feywild be canonical?
Delwath: And honestly, the Before Time stuff could be canonical too, 'cause it's before time.
DM: Yeah, so everything-
Unknown: Anything can happen
DM: ... is both canonical and non-canonical.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Kenzo: Well, you, we could also decide too, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... if it's like weird and does, it's just totally out there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But, but, or if it's like-
Delwath: You could, you could, you could decide when you get to a Feywild thing-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... whether you actually want it to count.
DM: So, so here, so I think Mike, it would be great if Mike does something first, and we can just make up, we can ha- we can schedule a session zero.
DM: We can start chatting about it now, but we can schedule a session zero, and we'll just do some world bu- That's nice too because we can like all have like
DM: updated these session notes.
DM: I'm probably gonna spend the next month...
DM: It'd be great if I have like a couple months where I don't have to do any prep.
DM: I'm gonna like go back and fill out a ton of this stuff-
Unknown: Oh, my gosh
DM: ... for Talgarverse and things like that.
Delwath: But you need to keep making...
Delwath: So that's one thing, like I can't make session notes like Tim makes.
DM: I'll keep doing session notes.
Delwath: Like I don't have the setup with the Zoom recording and the AI transcription and all of that stuff.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I can't commit to doing that.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Delwath: I don't write s- I mean,
Delwath: I, I have session notes from my game, but one of my players writes it.
Seeker: But your s- your session notes are now partly generated, right?
DM: They're, they're... [sighs] So I have a script that auto-generates the session notes, but I basically always just rewrite the narrative because I don't like-
Unknown: Mm
Unknown: How it does it
DM: ... how it does it. But that-
Seeker: Have you tried using your own examples as few shot examples in the prompt?
DM: I, I do, and it's-
Unknown: It's still not good enough?
DM: It, yeah. I, I need to fiddle with the settings 'cause I actually think using the, the new mo- the like GPT 5 is actually-
Unknown: 5 is really good at that.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean-
DM: So I gotta look. It's like there's some, there's some tr- But it actually doesn't take that long if it generates, 'cause it...
DM: So it makes bullet points for me, and it fills in all the like, you know, metadata headers, and it generates a narrative.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And it generates summary points.
DM: And it's actually pretty easy to just go through the narrative and just like rewrite it.
Unknown: You just fix it up, yeah.
DM: I just fix it up, right. It takes way...
DM: It's like editing takes way less time-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... than actually writing from scratch, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's cool.
DM: So like the script, this, once I run the script, it takes me like half, 20 minutes to like go through and edit the session notes.
DM: But yeah, I'll still write session notes.
Delwath: But I could, I could to- Like, yeah, I could totally do something.
Delwath: I would probably do something like either fifth or seventh level, depending on where it was.
DM: Cool.
Delwath: That's like a good level.
DM: Yeah, let's do, let's...
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I would say like fifth. Just-
Unknown: Fifth's a good level
DM: ... you know, get people that p- everybody can try out like different classes and stuff.
DM: Fifth is a good level. That's enough-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... complexity that it feels interesting-
DM: ... but not so much that-
Unknown: Two cast third level spells.
Delwath: Fifth is a good level.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Maybe I could try out being a rogue.
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. It's like I, like now I feel like I know how to play D&D-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... after, after 40 years.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: And now I'm like, "Okay, cool. Yeah, like it would be fun to just like, like try a few-"
Wellby: Just play some D&D.
Kenzo: Yeah, just play a few different things.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So that's one part. 'Cause like it's weird, like for me at least, like from a Talgar like storytelling part, I'm like really sitting with it.
Kenzo: I don't think there's any particular thing where I'm like, "Oh man, I would love to-"
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know? I'm kind of just like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like the thing I'm most interested in, in is the, is the weird like-
Unknown: Arcane
Kenzo: ... yeah, the arcane thing. There's something about that feels like oh, that'd be really fun.
Delwath: I would wanna do like, uh, like, uh, I don't know.
Delwath: I, I actually don't know what vibe I'd even wanna do.
Delwath: I mean, probably not something like steering away from like heroes saving the day.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: [gasps]
Delwath: But like...
DM: So but here's the thing. If we have, if Mike
Unknown: does
DM: a Talgar, a like Talgar canon, like we'll figure out the party,
DM: how do you feel about doing space opera after that?
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: My gut reaction is not to commit to it 'cause I just-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... am worried about the like having-
Unknown: Too much stuff with the-
Seeker: ... energy. But I want to, so I don't know.
Delwath: We should give Eric a chance to like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... you shouldn't try and commit right now.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I think you should have a chance to think about it and like fig- like in the background, like
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... figure it out.
DM: I mean, I could do, I could do, I could do arcane after that, or you could do pre-world stuff after that.
Unknown: Yeah, or Feywild or whatever.
Unknown: Or Feywild.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Feywild might be interested in a non-D&D system.
Unknown: Would that-
Kenzo: I think that'd be great.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, we could try that.
Seeker: Deep in the halls of the dwarf kingdom.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: So like a-
Unknown: Mm
Seeker: ... underneath, under the mountains.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: That's almost verges on like horror stuff though, because it, it'd be all dungeon.
DM: Oh, I would actually love to run that.
DM: I would love to do an all dwarf Underdark adventure.
Unknown: That's what I'm talking about.
Unknown: I think that would be really fun.
Seeker: And it could be like in a early,
Seeker: early history of Talgar time, so shit's a little different.
Delwath: Actually, I would also enjoy...
Delwath: Well, you can run it if you want, but I just have this idea in my head of like a almost horror style.
DM: 'Cause there's all sorts of aberrations and like-
Delwath: Like, like, like-
Unknown: Like we had one-
Unknown: ... Underdark
Unknown: ... we had one moment-
Delwath: Doesn't have to be all dwarf
Seeker: ... at Raven's Hold of that stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Of touching on it, and it feels like there's a lot down there.
Unknown: That's interesting.
Kenzo: Do you guys remember, I'm having like a, like a, like a, like a super like hardcore flashback to high school.
Kenzo: There was one session that we did where when we were like very, very powerful, and that's basically what happened.
Unknown: We went-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... super deep.
DM: Shamat was trying to find the seven firstborn dwarves.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. And we, but it was like, I remember, I remember just like my, my recollection of it, like I remember at the time being so like mind blown, 'cause I was like, "Holy shit, this is crazy."
Kenzo: And like I don't remember ex- but like I remember like us going deep, deep, deep, deep, and it was like, it was like psychedelic and fucking crazy, and there was, it was just like all like these weird...
Kenzo: It was almost like all these different dimensional sh- things and planes and stuff, but like all underground.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Like super deep underground.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But it was like mystical and weird and,
Kenzo: and I remember it was like sort of like, "Oh, shit.
Kenzo: Like we wanna go and explore that sometime later."
Kenzo: And then, you know, we never did.
Seeker: We, at some point, Tim and I, we also discussed like, well, what is,
Seeker: if you go, speaking of going downwards in Talgar, what, what do you reach if you go high enough in the air?
DM: Yeah. We never actually decided.
Seeker: And I love that question.
Unknown: [laughs] So it's not space opera.
DM: Maybe that's what the ladder's gonna figure out.
Seeker: It's like some kind of like a-
DM: The ladder can fly. It doesn't need to be there.
Unknown: Right. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Some kind of pre-Copernican strange-
DM: Yeah. Well, I mean, so Isaac-
DM: ... like sphere theory ... yeah, there's the outer shell.
Unknown: Yeah. Isaac run-
Unknown: We bump into it
DM: ... Isaac's, the campaign Isaac's running is like a Spelljammer campaign, right?
DM: It's like they have a spaceship.
DM: They fly around to planets, but it's all D&D.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: And it seems pretty fun, actually.
Unknown: I was just thinking-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... what if there's like, uh, what if there's like just some other creatures off on some outer...
Kenzo: Yeah, that idea. Like outer sphere in Talgar.
DM: Well, eventually you have to figure out what the moon is.
Delwath: I know. I, I probably need to figure out the moon at some point.
Kenzo: Well, not, I probably have a year, but in a year I, one of my players-
Unknown: Oh
Kenzo: ... is a lit- a sorcerer who, who gets his power from the moon.
Seeker: Anybody read, um, probably not, Tatyu: Grimm's World.
Unknown: It's a wonderful-
Unknown: No
Seeker: ... lesser known by Werner Bini, who wrote-
Unknown: Which book?
Unknown: I read it
Unknown: ... Deepness in the Sky.
DM: Yeah, I read it. It is Tatyu: Grimm's World.
Unknown: I haven't read that one.
Unknown: Oh, I didn't read that.
Unknown: It's, it actually has like a...
Seeker: It, it, anyway, it has funny self-referential stuff, but it also has a
Seeker: creative notion of like what's on the moon.
Unknown: Anyway.
Kenzo: Eric, I, I think like, like yeah, doing like an outer space thing would be fun.
Unknown: That'd be-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... like really cool.
DM: But we also don't... I mean, if Mike's willing to do the next thing, we don't have to...
DM: We can sort of see how everybody feel, see how long that goes and see how everybody feels.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like it could be anywhere from two to four sessions.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: It's fine.
Unknown: Plus the session zero.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So like three to five sessions.
Unknown: That's like,
DM: like five sessions is like two and a half months on average for us, so
DM: you know, that's November, December.
Unknown: Yeah, like January.
Unknown: January.
Seeker: So dw- so Dwarves in the Underdark is one.
Kenzo: I wanna play a druid.
Kenzo: I don't know how a druid ended, end up in the, in the, uh, in the caves with the dwarves.
Kenzo: We can figure it out.
Unknown: Well, maybe that's-
Kenzo: That's where, that's where we're set
Seeker: ... that's the Cloudtops adventure.
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: Cloudtops?
Seeker: One where we explore like what happens if you keep going up in Talgar.
Delwath: Right. I don't really wanna run that though, 'cause I don't wanna make up what goes, what happens when you keep going.
Unknown: Okay. Kong wants to be a druid.
Kenzo: That's the only thing I know right now, but I mean, I could be d- I could be something else too.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: No, you should be a druid.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I'm, I'm into that idea.
Seeker: Who, who would end up on that adventure?
Unknown: Which adventure?
Unknown: Oh, going up
Delwath: The cloud tops? I'd play it.
Delwath: That would be great.
Unknown: Like maybe that's what I should do.
Kenzo: There you go. You could run it. I...
Unknown: Yeah. You should totally.
Delwath: You could, you could just run a non-canonic, I mean or it could be canonical depending on-
Unknown: I wanna talk to Tim about it
Unknown: ... what you guys decide.
Kenzo: Yeah. That's like a sort of outer space, but a sort of space opera without needing to like figure out a new system and like-
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. It could be D&D, but there's like just some new novel structure of the physics of the world-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... that we can invent.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: For what stars are [laughs] and what planets are-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... and what the moons.
Kenzo: I would totally play. That would be super fun to play.
Seeker: Like what's up there? What do you end up encountering?
Unknown: [coughs]
Delwath: Yeah. I just, I just don't want to run it.
Unknown: What do you wanna play, Schwartz?
Unknown: I mean, characters.
Unknown: Well, you're ac- you'd be academics-
Unknown: You gotta character? I don't know
Unknown: ... doing an experiment-
Unknown: Well, I don't have a-
Unknown: ... with a hot air balloon.
Wellby: I don't have a strong sense of that yet.
Delwath: What would you play, Tim?
Unknown: That's a good question.
Wellby: I feel like Wellby is like a very, s- like sensible, grounded character.
Wellby: I think I wanna play someone like who's more obsessive or like more...
Unknown: I dunno.
Delwath: What, but also like what- Less sensible ...
Unknown: what vibe? A test pilot?
Seeker: Yeah. Yes. A hot air balloon test pilot, say?
Unknown: [laughs] My God.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Absolutely. Because-
Delwath: Eric's like, "Let's just get right to the spirit.
Delwath: Would you wanna run a, a ToG-
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: ... do you wanna, uh,"
Unknown: "do like,
Delwath: do that next?"
DM: I don't know. See, my problem is I, I find it hard to make up a character without the content.
DM: Like- Right ... I would...
Unknown: I have
DM: like lots of ideas for characters- Well- ...
DM: but they would all- Depend on the con- ...
Unknown: come from a certain place.
DM: Like I would make up characters by first, like where and how are they from, and then I invent from there.
DM: I mean- But just from a mechanical point of view, I would,
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: I don't know. I like bards.
DM: I might play a bard, or a sorcerer, or a paladin.
DM: Those would probably be my three top choices.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: But the vibe would depend on what the
Unknown: game was. Right.
DM: I don't, I'm not really committed to a character idea so much as...
Delwath: I mean, vibe wise, like,
Unknown: there's like
Delwath: more in the kind of,
Delwath: there's like, there's like the vibe of like, um,
Unknown: more
Delwath: open world text. Like, like make up a party and then- Right ...
Delwath: just like you guys are somewhere, and what you do, like open worldy kind of vibe.
DM: Although that could be hard to sust- Like- That's tough.
Unknown: I mean, I thought- It's tough for short ...
DM: so I actually thought about that, like one strat- one thing I thought about doing was turning Mawar into like a hex crawl, basically.
DM: Where it's like there's little ruins around, and you have a treasure map, and everyone w- somebody wants to, you like get a party together and you're like, "Let's go investigate these ruins."
Unknown: But
Unknown: I don't,
DM: I decided that wouldn't work super well with this group.
DM: It's just like, um-
DM: I mean, two, it's like classic dungeon crawling D&D.
DM: It's like not really our vibe.
Kenzo: Yeah. I agree.
DM: Like we didn't do that even during the classic dungeon crawling days of D&D, so why should, why would we wanna do that now?
Delwath: There's like, um,
Delwath: there's like, I mean, uh, there's, there's an idea of like underdark horror, like kind of
Unknown: escape from the...
Delwath: I've always, I always have liked the, I've never run one actually, but I always kind of liked the idea of running like an escape adventure where basically-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Just like run away from something really scary ...
Unknown: you're like
Unknown: somewhere-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... and have to get out.
Delwath: Like the whole point of the adventure is just to find your way
Delwath: back to the surface.
Unknown: So there's like a pacing thing.
Unknown: You've gotta like
Seeker: go quickly. There's a lot of maps.
Delwath: Yeah. But it doesn't have to be entirely escape from a...
Unknown: I mean, it could be
Delwath: you're being hunted by s- Like there's all kinds of...
Wellby: I don't have an exact idea. Yeah. There's a quality of a chase.
Wellby: There's a feeling of the chase which is not just mechanical.
Wellby: Yeah. Like it's, it's felt.
Wellby: Yeah. It's not just how far ahead are you, roll the dice.
Unknown: Right. Right.
Delwath: But it's not necessarily like you're escaping from a monster, right?
Delwath: Like you could do something where you're in some dwarven cavern, deep in the under- or some cavern deep in the underdark.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And you don't really know which way is up or down,
Delwath: right? And you have to find clues.
Unknown: Yeah, that would be fun.
Delwath: I've been meaning to make up more of the underdark 'cause I have a whole arc planned in my game that I'm running with my other friends that's gonna go to the underdark.
Delwath: What do you think of an escape the underdark?
DM: I mean, that's a very classic D&D premise.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That would be fun.
Delwath: We've never really run so- I mean,
Delwath: I've always liked the idea of running an escape type.
DM: I mean, this is what... So the, the, the one, the one shot I ran without, the only ToG game I've ever run without any of you was for, um,
DM: uh, two friends of mine from work.
DM: Well, now no longer, you know, postdocs and stuff who had gone other places, and then a friend of one of them, and then John.
DM: I don't know how I ended up with that group and none of you, but it was basically this.
DM: It was, I had written an adventure that I was looking for people to play that was,
DM: uh, you s- I always wanted to do a you start in a prison with no equipment.
Unknown: Ooh.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: And that's kind of what I- And it was really, it was fun actually ...
Delwath: teacher driven. You start in a prison with n- not a prison, but start somewhere.
Unknown: No, it was fun.
Seeker: And you just have to like find or steal whatever you can get.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So they started, they were locked up by goblins.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: And like the first session, they basically
DM: ... gathered equipment.
DM: Two of them ended up playing artificers, so I had to make a lot of random tools lying around.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And
DM: it was, it was a lot of fun, I think.
Delwath: Like, see, I like the vibe of something like that combined with, like, a little bit more of a horror, but like a fifth or sixth level so you can take it
DM: a little bit more in a dangerous direction.
DM: That was, that was...
DM: I made that, the one that I did it, they started at second level, and then they leveled up to third when they got all their equipment.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So that was after the first session, and then there was two more sessions.
DM: That was in Western Saimia.
Delwath: Yeah, I remember making it to-
DM: So they made it to-
Unknown: Western where?
DM: Across the Green Sea from Toland, or across the Western Gulf from Toland.
DM: I don't know. For that, for, like, an underdark new, like escape the underdark without any equipment, I would probably play...
DM: If it was sixth level, I'd play a bard, 'cause I've always wanted to play a valor bard, but they don't get extra attacks till sixth level, so I think it would kind of be boring to play one at fifth level.
Delwath: Actually, sixth level's a good level, 'cause you have your sub cl-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... a lot of people get a subclass thing at sixth level.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: S- Seeker was a bard.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But he was a home brew bard with-
DM: Well-
Unknown: ... int
DM: ... the only, there was only one, it was, the only change, Seeker was a College of Creation bard, so everything, all the, like, ladder-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... all the performance and creation stuff was not home brewed.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But I just switched it to be int.
DM: You a- actually st- he started out as charisma, but, but like by session five I was like, "You're, like, you are not playing this like a high charisma.
DM: Are you sure you don't wanna be int?"
Unknown: I didn't realize-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... you started charisma. Really? I didn't realize that.
DM: Well, it was really early on. We retcon, we retconned the ability scores-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... and just switched them.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: I think I was... But I, I feel like I identify Seeker more as, like, an artificer or like a-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... right? Like a-
DM: Yeah, well, a College of Creation bard-
Unknown: Bard is-
DM: ... almost a better artificer than an art...
DM: From college-
Unknown: Oh, is it?
DM: ... it's an artificer.
Unknown: Ah, okay, okay.
Delwath: But College of Creation's very much about cr- I mean, it's very-
DM: It's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... yeah.
Kenzo: Got it. Got it. Okay. Okay.
DM: And then we re-flavored a bunch of stuff as runes instead of...
DM: Like, the original College of Creation is the, instead of the,
DM: the inspiration is, like, the, you know, song of creation or something like that-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... instead of, like, runes.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. Right. Bards are usually literally musicians.
DM: Right.
Seeker: But Seeker was just interested in geology.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: But, but it was actually-
Unknown: It all worked, which was good
DM: ... it was a, it was a very easy re-flavor.
DM: The, um,
DM: Kenzo's subclass was actually the hardest to design.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: What's Kenzo's subclass?
DM: It was totally home brew. It was unrelated to anything.
Unknown: What did you call it?
DM: His... Well, Awakened Soul, right?
Unknown: Ah.
DM: 'Cause he was the
DM: awakened... I mean, that was the Bishma Order.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But it was tricky because,
DM: um, like, I ended up redesigning it a couple times as we played, 'cause, like, when you started, you were like, you kept, you, you know, you liked the, like, Fist of Planar Power.
DM: You wanted to use all the, like-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... um, you know,
DM: cool, like, martial artsy things.
DM: But then, like, by mid-level you were really into the, like,
DM: sensing things vibe.
Unknown: Right, right, right.
DM: And so I, like, shifted a lot of the later level stuff to be-
Unknown: Right, right
DM: ... like the, like the aura sense, the, like, Commune-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... Extend Care aura thing was, wasn't originally part of the subclass, but I redesigned it into that when you-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So I basically made each,
DM: I made each ability as you reached that level.
DM: [laughs] I was basically like, "What is-
Unknown: Oh, that's awesome
DM: ... what does Kong want now?"
Seeker: And the Soul Sight thing is a standard mechanic?
DM: No, no. That I made up. That actually stuck, right?
DM: So I originally designed it the, the things that s-
Delwath: I didn't realize Soul Sight's not a standard mechanic.
DM: No, no, no.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: But it, it seems, like, incredibly important.
Unknown: Like,
Seeker: most of my decisions about which spell to cast depend on-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: So, um-
Unknown: ... which save is weakest in the-
DM: So-
Unknown: ... that day
DM: ... there are a few classes that...
DM: So Hunter Rangers can do that as a standard thing.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: There's a... And I think there's, like, Battle Master fighters maybe have an ability to do that, but it's not a standard.
Seeker: It, it's one of the things where, like, like you always wanna have more of, like, "I combine this ability of mine with this ability-
DM: Right
Seeker: ... of yours if we do it the right way."
Seeker: And the, the Soul Sight is one of those that, like-
DM: Well-
Seeker: ... that knowledge unlocks our abilities.
DM: Yeah, totally.
Unknown: Which-
DM: Well, I think actually the way that things played out in later parts of the campaign where you had Wellby and Kenzo both having really high initiative-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... and the ability to swap.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. Yes.
DM: And then both of them having abilities-
Unknown: Benefits, yeah
DM: ... that were useful to go-
Unknown: For later-
DM: Well-
Unknown: ... turns, yeah
Delwath: ... I liked that ability so much I stole it.
Delwath: One of my players in my other game is a bard
Delwath: who is also multi-classed as a warlock, and has this, like, Far Realms-
Unknown: Right
DM: ...
Delwath: his patron is, like, this Far Realms creature, but actually it's not evil or strange or anything, it's just really curious about Talgar.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So it's, like, some weird Great Old One, but not, like, with an evil vibe at all.
DM: With just a, like-
Wellby: Like a Great Old One.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But, like, inscrutable.
Delwath: Still the same inscrutable, like, I...
Delwath: But, like, just, like, "I'm really curious."
Delwath: So he has all these lore abilities, so I gave him a-
Unknown: Like a Soul Sight ability?
Delwath: It was when you use a bardic inspiration die for an attack roll or a saving throw, you can also learn one of the resistances, immunities-
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: That's cool
Delwath: ... or strongest or weakest save against your target.
Unknown: That's awesome that-
Unknown: Weird
Kenzo: ... that you home brewed that. I mean, that, that's so-
DM: But I originally, I originally started to make it, like, a, a sort of, um,
DM: you know, where you had a lot of extra abilities that,
DM: that keyed off-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... who you had ...
DM: soul sighted, so it was like a sort of, you know, mark a bad guy and then-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... focus down the bad guy that you marked.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But like that only, that worked 'cause like originally you were like wanted to have like sort of anime abilities, right?
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Like a long time ago.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Like when you first were making up the character.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, although actually you, Kong, when we were discussing your backstory, you were like,
DM: you know, "I wanna be like a wandering monk who like gets more powers as I acquire more parts of Rai."
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. I remember that was the first seed of the whole thing was like, like a, like a-
DM: It was-
Kenzo: Even when we were trying to figure out what this campaign was about.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: It was like, oh, like that would be a fun hook.
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: To like have like these like pieces of Jade that were connected to the whole thing.
Unknown: We don't know what they mean.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: But see, again-
DM: That's cool
Kenzo: ... kudos, kudos to you though, Tim.
DM: It worked out well. [laughs]
Kenzo: That, that was a good thing. But, but again, kudos to you, man.
Kenzo: Like I, I really feel like it was like really f- like, you know, just even the things like, you know, with the staff.
Kenzo: It's like, oh cool. It's like, hey, like I want to have like a cool staff, and like I want it to be from that tree.
Kenzo: And you'd like figure out how to make it so like we could get the...
Unknown: You know?
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And then it was like, oh cool.
Kenzo: Then we made up all these like classes of Ki, and then like the whole...
Kenzo: All of that, like that whole like again like kind of figuring out how to bri- connect the storytelling into the game mechanics.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: It was like so fun for like... 'Cause then it was sort of like once I like te- like I, David, but then also Kenzo, would be like, "Oh cool.
Kenzo: There's that cool thing. Like how can I figure out how to turn that into a cool Ki that I can stick into my staff?"
DM: Yeah. Right. Yeah.
Kenzo: And then every time like we met any cool thing, it's like, "Oh cool.
Kenzo: Like how do I get some storm giant Ki?"
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: And then you could figure out, you know.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like that was a great like...
Unknown: That was like, that was really fun.
DM: Well, that really started with the Kenzo one-shot.
Unknown: Right.
DM: With the Kenzo solo adventure with the-
Kenzo: Is that when that started? Getting the weird Ki?
DM: Yeah, 'cause I made up a bunch of...
DM: I, that was like early Midjourney, and I was playing around.
DM: I like made a bunch of like watercolor sketches of all of these weird lizard folk-
Unknown: Right, right, right
DM: ... clans. And you were like really into the, um...
DM: I think it might have been your idea actually.
DM: Like, 'cause there was like one that was, um,
DM: it was like the lizard folk clan-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... where they were like communing with the dead through this plant.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And you were like, "How?" Like, "I gotta get some of that for me," right?
DM: "There must be some like Ki associated with it or something."
DM: I was like, yeah, there probably is.
Kenzo: Okay. So, so real world, like I literally had like eaten ayahuasca for the first time, and I was like, "Oh, I wanna-"
DM: Oh, yeah
Kenzo: ... I, I wanna include all of this into D&D.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh, yeah. No, that, that must've been when church happened, right.
Kenzo: That was, that was literally what happened, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause that whole one shot was like after, yeah, after about that I first started.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: I was like, oh yeah, I wanna bring all this crazy fucking-
DM: Yeah. So you were like, "There's gotta be some ability I get.
DM: Like, can I get some Ki from this?"
DM: And so then I was like, "Yeah, sure."
Kenzo: No, but that was, that was like really great.
Unknown: And the
Seeker: everyone doing their own side arcs was because of my-
Unknown: Yes
Unknown: ... of D&D awards.
DM: Yes. Yeah.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: But you actually played in more of the side arcs than some other people.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Delwath: But, but I can see, I mean, it's so much nicer to feel no pressure to have to play.
Unknown: Yeah. Good, right.
DM: No, Eric played in...
DM: Oh, no. Yeah, Eric played in three.
Delwath: Did he? 'Cause nobody else played in three, right?
Unknown: 'Cause I know-
Kenzo: I didn't gue- I guested in yours.
DM: Me, Clay, Kate played in three.
Kenzo: I did not play in yours or yours.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: None of you played in mine.
Delwath: Kate played in three. Oh, Kate also played in three.
Kenzo: Did you guest in mine?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I think you did, yeah.
Delwath: It was just the two of you.
DM: You two. The Kenzo's was just you two.
Unknown: Right.
DM: I was an NPC to help you out.
Kenzo: And then I guested in yours.
DM: And then Seekers was the last one we did, and you played the first session.
Unknown: And I played the second.
DM: And Mike pl- Mike played the second session, and Isaac and Kate played both sessions.
Kenzo: Yeah, I remember that. Yeah.
DM: And-
Seeker: And now Izzy has done some follow-up on the-
DM: Yes
Delwath: ... In the Fade Wild.
DM: Izzy is now world building
DM: the Tower of Fade Wild.
Seeker: We've returned to the Crystal Mountain one more time.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Oh, cool. Right.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: That was the one I didn't play. Yeah.
DM: Right. And then-
Delwath: And then I played in one of Schwartz's, but not both.
DM: You played in one of Schwartz's but not both, and Eric played in one of Schwartz's but not both.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And then
DM: John and my friend Phil played in both.
DM: But actually, the m- the, the mirror realm was one of my favorite.
Wellby: That was really fun.
DM: And actually, did you notice the Easter egg in the
DM: Limbo notes?
Delwath: I did, even though I didn't play in that adventure.
Unknown: Um, uh-
DM: Aaron, The Wanderer, was one of the people quoted in one of the pieces of research.
Wellby: Oh. I did see that, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's
Unknown: cool.
DM: Research about how to
DM: get to other planes, planar connections.
Delwath: Okay, so I have a good idea for a, for a-
DM: Okay
DM: ... thing. But the problem is, the problem with an escape
Delwath: the, the thing scenario is how did you get there?
DM: Well-
Unknown: That's what I don't know
DM: ... when I ran my escape the thing, I made them all make up how their characters got trapped.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But it was... So the, the re- the logic was there was like a gang of
DM: goblins that were kidnapping prisoners for like the main boss, who was a-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... mad scientist who was turning people into stone.
DM: So everybody just have had, had to have gotten caught somehow by the goblins.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Being trapped in the underworld is a-
Delwath: Well, my new, my other idea actually instead of the Underdark would be, um,
Delwath: in the far north
Delwath: of the Sambaran Highlands up by like those, the, like the back, back-
DM: Oh, that's a good place. We're caught by the Necromancer cult or something.
Unknown: Not quite.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Sort of. Um, but-
DM: This is gonna be a little tricky.
Delwath: No, no, no. Uh, well, you might...
Delwath: It's hard to run something for Tim with,
Delwath: uh, too many secrets, but that's okay.
Delwath: Um, no, it would be like the headwaters of the Volta.
DM: Okay.
DM: Right. So like far in the north, like up-
DM: I like the, I like the escape from prison sort of thing.
Kenzo: So here's another thing too, especially if it's something that maybe is like lower prep for you, but-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... it, it might be harder for Tim.
Kenzo: This is like a kinda maybe a little cheesy, but it's sorta like, I actually like it a lot also in like movies and other things where it's like the characters, like yeah, you wake up in a
Unknown: dungeon-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... but you don't know why you're there, or like, you know, like we don't know why we're there, you know?
Kenzo: And then it's sort of like you kinda like piece it together a little bit, and then, you know what I mean?
Kenzo: So it's like, it's like a, you know, you're, you're kinda discovering-
DM: So-
Unknown: ... the world totally
DM: ... okay, it is super derivative, but I would argue, like maybe we start the next campaign three like that.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That's like a better-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... start for a full campaign than it is a start for-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... a three session game.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 'Cause in three sessions you don't really have time to figure out the mystery.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: And it also, I think-
DM: Mm
Delwath: ... it's a cool idea also, but it,
Delwath: one of the appeals is like collaboratively making up how everybody ended up-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... somewhere, and you use that-
Unknown: Right, right
DM: So this is jumping ahead, but, and it's, it's a fairly derivative way to start a campaign, but
DM: I don't really care. I think derivative...
DM: I mean, this, this campaign started in a tavern.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: So we gotta stick with-
Unknown: Totally
DM: ... is everybody makes up their own backstory with their own goals,
DM: and like you have some backstory developed that has some ideas.
Seeker: And then you, you all start
DM: s- in a, some confined space-
Unknown: Place
DM: ... like a prison or on a ship or something.
DM: You don't know how you got there.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And like you're forced to
DM: interact with each other.
Delwath: So my favorite crazy hook of games I've ran, this wasn't in Talgar, um, but a while ago I ran a game that started with the PCs being
Delwath: summoned by a high level wizard to go on a quest.
Delwath: So like they were just teleported to the, like the first adventure.
DM: Yeah, that's like the...
DM: So Schwartz was the only one who pl- played in the Rizvan one-shot.
DM: And it was like that was the Rizvan one shot with the,
DM: the dwarven gods summoned everybody-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... to come help Rizvan.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. No, that-
DM: That one was fun
DM: ... I, I mean, starting a long campaign where they really have no idea-
DM: So I had this idea, like the beginning of the campaign is you're in the brig of a ship.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: You don't know how you got there.
DM: And you wake up-
Unknown: That's great
DM: ... to the sound of the waves-
DM: ... rocking back and forth.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And that's the like opening scene.
Kenzo: That's great. I love shit like that.
Kenzo: It's like really fun, 'cause then you're just like-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... "What the fuck is this?"
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like it's like a... Like that, that's like a,
Kenzo: you know, deep into plot twist stuff where you're just like, uh-
DM: Right.
Unknown: Wow
Kenzo: ... this is very surprising and interesting to like learn what the hell's going on.
Unknown: One,
Seeker: one of my ideas for the space opera RPG was just inspired by, it's called something like a johatsu scam.
Seeker: It's something that has happened in Japan where there are these services that help you disappear basically.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Ooh.
Seeker: Where you're like, "I want to leave my life."
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Like it's not viable for me-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... to quit my job and get a divorce or whatever.
Seeker: I'll just pay you some money and you'll relocate me with a new identity.
Seeker: But some of those services unfortunately
Unknown: are fraudulent.
Kenzo: Yeah, of course. Yeah.
Seeker: And so there are people who
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: ... you give them money to disappear and then they're like...
Seeker: Anyway, so you could make up your own backstory about why you needed to like leave your life.
Kenzo: That's cool. I love that.
Seeker: But now you're thrown into this situation where you're trapped somehow.
Kenzo: I mean, but I think also cool is if that actually worked.
Kenzo: Like if you are, if there is some situation where it's like there, you know, it's like the agency is successful in doing that, and then you are just this like, you know,
Unknown: you know.
Unknown: New life.
DM: Right.
Seeker: Well, no, but that's how you end up on like a-
Unknown: Like a mining station
Kenzo: ... really dangerous space colony
Unknown: Yeah. Got it, got it.
DM: I, I mean, do we wanna do a whole year of starting in prisons games?
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: We could.
Unknown: It's working.
Kenzo: Well, I, I like just like the waking up and you don't know where the fuck you are or what the hell is going on.
DM: Yeah, but I-
Kenzo: Like that, that's like a cool-
DM: Well-
Unknown: I like that
DM: ... I really seriously might, I mean, that might work really well for cam- the start of campaign three.
Unknown: Love it.
DM: But
DM: I'm not ready yet to figure that out.
Delwath: I have an idea that sort of you don't know exactly where you are, but you do know...
Delwath: I haven't quite figured it out, so I can't say the details yet.
Delwath: But you'd have to know
Kenzo: what you were trying to do and generally where you are, and like had been-
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: But I kinda like the idea of running something kinda far away from,
Unknown: like
Delwath: not, like you're not just in a town, right?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: You're like
Delwath: out in the far north somewhere with, you know,
Delwath: not a lot of people around.
Delwath: And so how did you end up there?
Unknown: I don't...
Delwath: There would presumably have to be some sort of like quest that, or goal that you previously had that's now been thwarted because something went horribly wrong, and now you're stuck
Delwath: trying to... And then the, the
Delwath: actual adventure starts after the horribly wrong thing.
Delwath: But you'd know what the horribly... We'd have to make up what the horrible...
Delwath: Like the idea would be like in session zero you'd make up like why were you here, what were you trying to do.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: How did it go horribly wrong, so you sort of know you ended up in this bad situation that you then have to get out of.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: That's kinda my idea at least.
Kenzo: Yeah, one tension that's kinda interesting is like I don't know if it's hard to do, if it's harder to do plot twists in a collaborative thing.
Kenzo: Right? 'Cause like then it's sort of like...
Unknown: 'Cause the plot, the-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... the plot twisty thing feels more like, yeah, like the DM just knows and then like springs on everybody, and they're like, "Yeah, right."
Delwath: But you can do plot twist. I mean, you can do plot twists.
Delwath: It's a little bit harder
Delwath: to plot twist Tim.
Kenzo: [laughs] In Talgar it's, it's probably impossible to plot twist Tim.
Delwath: I mean, it's hard to do like the Tim level like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... it turns out-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... like Paulion and Shemot were having an...
Unknown: You know?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But it's fine. It's easy to do. I mean, it's not...
Delwath: It's perfectly possible to do 'cause the collaboration is just coming up with like-
Kenzo: Right, the context of it
Unknown: ... the backstory and the context. Right?
Kenzo: Yeah, totally. Totally. Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Unknown: I get it. Yeah.
Delwath: And it's easy to actually set, like in this con- Like, so, okay, let's say in this i- this idea I have,
Delwath: the idea is that
Delwath: you would... We would need to collaboratively figure out why a group of four adventurers was in the mountains,
Delwath: in the, the big mountain chain, the Sentinels, but in the northern section of it, like in northern Zimbara.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And you would be... To have to...
Delwath: You'd be doing something there and be on some sort of adventure, and it's gone horribly wrong, right?
Delwath: And then some event, I haven't quite figured out the event, but some event happens during it going horribly wrong.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: And then you're now in a situation.
Delwath: You don't know how you... I mean, you don't know the cause of the event or how you got there or like...
DM: I'm imagining like an avalanche.
Delwath: So like you could... I mean, this probably wouldn't be exactly an avalanche, but
Delwath: why are you on a mountain?
Delwath: I don't know. We collaboratively make that up, and then there's some sort of avalanche, and you find yourself in an ice cave,
Delwath: like with no... Like a perfectly s- Again, an example, but a perfectly spherical ice cave.
Delwath: And how did you get here from the avalanche?
Kenzo: That's great. That's great.
Delwath: You were unconscious for 10 minutes, and you woke up here.
Kenzo: I really like shit like that.
Kenzo: That's like, like stuff that's just kind of imaginatively awe-inspiring and like really confusing.
Kenzo: It's like shit like, um...
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: Yeah, you're like traveling in this like mountain, and then you see crash into the side of the mountain like a ship.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: You know? And you're like-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... what the fuck? Why is there a ship there?
Kenzo: Or like, yeah, you're in the middle of the forest, and then there's a clearing, and then, yeah, there's like six perfectly floating orbs of like...
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... you know? And it's just like, what the fuck is this?
Unknown: What is it?
DM: Why is there a statue with no eyes and a crown?
Unknown: S- Uh, yeah.
Unknown: S-
Delwath: Right. A statue with no eyes and a crown?
Delwath: Why was there a statue with no eyes and a crown?
Unknown: That's Rogar.
DM: Rogar.
Delwath: Oh, right. Right, right, right.
Kenzo: That, well, the Rogar arc was, was-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... that was, that was gre-
Kenzo: That was really great
Kenzo: ... that whole thing with that shit-
Unknown: It was so fun
Kenzo: ... was like so fun, you know?
Unknown: So I, I-
Unknown: It's just like, what is this weird...
Unknown: What the fuck is this?
DM: That was, that was, that was actually your first like, "We're just going on this stupid side quest for no reason whatsoever," side quest.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, the lightning storm.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Wandering in the lightning storm.
DM: It was like, we should really go back and tell Carowa that we killed the demon, and there's no more gnoles.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But there's a lightning storm, so let's go see.
Wellby: No, it's like, it's, it's gonna take so long to go to Carowa and then come back again.
Unknown: Once we get to Carowa-
DM: No, that's, that was exactly your logic
Wellby: ... we're in the neighborhood.
Unknown: We may as well.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Like-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... who knows when the next
Kenzo: Actually, I forgot, I forgot the very first T-shirt that we have not made yet, which is the side quest is the main quest.
DM: Yes.
DM: But you actually stopped-
Delwath: We did kind of stop going on side quests
DM: ... doing side quests.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like, once you sort of locked into the, we gotta find the pieces of rye-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you kinda stopped going on side quests so much.
Seeker: Yeah, we became disciplined and efficient.
Unknown: That's right. [laughs]
Wellby: Y- you kinda did actually.
Unknown: More so.
DM: Although I guess the whole, um,
DM: Chardin thing was a bit of a side quest.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I, I think we still did a lot of side quests.
Kenzo: Eric, this is off tangent. It's super random, but like the things that you do with, um, Izzy, like all the storytelling stuff, do you like record or capture any of those things?
Seeker: I have like maybe 60 or 75 to 10 minute recordings of those.
Unknown: Amazing.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Amazing. I... You know, as we were just talking about this, I just had this memory like I totally forgot about this, but when I was like...
Kenzo: When my sister and I were little kids,
Kenzo: my dad used to tell us stories from like, like basically like Chinese fantasy, like historical Chinese fantasy stories, like classic
Kenzo: stories. But my sister and I were the main characters in the stories.
Unknown: That's cool.
Kenzo: And yeah, he used to... And I don't really remember them very...
Kenzo: My sister remembers them a little bit, but there actually were like tape recordings someplace of some of that stuff.
Unknown: Oh. Oh, wow.
Kenzo: Which is like, you know, since lost, you know, for sure.
Kenzo: They're like lost, but I, I totally had forgot about that, and I was like, oh man, you know, like what a gr- Like, that would've been a neat thing to have like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you know. So anyways, I'm glad that you're recording those 'cause I'm sure she'll trea- you know, she'll treasure that.
Seeker: I, I just typed in Seeker into my,
Seeker: uh, voice memo app 'cause it has the transcripts,
Seeker: and it pulled up two, Moles on the Plane of Fire and Crystal Mountain Rescue.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: I think the Plane of Fire one was actually pretty cool.
Kenzo: She'll love those. She'll, she'll really treasure those some point later in her life.
Unknown: Let's see.
Unknown: Where is Chardinva?
DM: So I have another question.
DM: Okay.
DM: Lots of conversation about the things that everybody likes.
DM: What fell flat?
Wellby: Some of the combats that seemed to be there just for the sake of having combat.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: That didn't feel like they advanced a narrative, like where there wasn't narrative stakes attached to them.
Wellby: I'm thinking in particular of the, um,
Wellby: man, one in the Feywild with like the wolves or the things that were running along,
Unknown: which just sort of-
Delwath: Oh, Tim threw that in for me.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: 'Cause I made up those dusk hound creatures
Wellby: It just sort of felt like-
Unknown: But-
Wellby: ... we know what the outcome of this is gonna be-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... before we start.
Wellby: It doesn't change the story.
Unknown: Yeah. I think, I think-
Wellby: The dusk hound creatures were very nice.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: The... Sorry. Which?
DM: The Feywild-
Unknown: One of the combat ones
DM: ... thing was a little complic- Yes.
DM: I was trying to do some-
Unknown: But like that's the most obvious one-
DM: Like it was compli-
Unknown: ... like of that category
DM: ... yeah, yeah. No, I, I know what you're saying. The Feywi- I...
DM: The thing I...
DM: The Feywild arc would've been much clearer if I had just not tried to involve the gleam shaper and all of Mike's Feywild-
Unknown: ... plots as well.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: I'd just done the...
DM: But it's fine. No, that's... Yeah, I, I-
Kenzo: But I, I think building on what you were saying, like I, I think for sure like the biggest thing was just combats that felt like
Kenzo: we're just like going through the motions of this combat.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: And like,
Kenzo: it's funny 'cause I feel like, I feel like the, this past year
Kenzo: maybe, like the combats have been way more interesting.
Kenzo: Like I forget when it kind of started where like our combats started like kind of locking in and were like so much more creative and like fun.
Kenzo: And part of it may also for me, for me personally just like learning a little bit more about like the, like really more understanding the D&D rules to be like, "Oh, okay cool.
Kenzo: Here are the kind of more interesting things that I can do than are just like rolling the same shit over and over again," you know?
Seeker: For me it's more, it's like once you have a grasp on the rules you can start, begin to understand what the strategy actually-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... is like to try-
Unknown: ... to make it work better for you.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Which also took me a long time.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. But, but I think, but it's like that I think though, 'cause there, there definitely were like I feel like quite a, like just combats where it just like felt like okay we're just kind of going through the motions.
Unknown: You know?
DM: Well part of that for you is that the 20 f- the old version of the monks were really pretty flat.
Unknown: Like-
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... you have a, like you just...
DM: And it was about a year ago, it was in Colorado that we rebuilt everybody's characters with the new rules.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Mm-mm.
DM: And that opened up a ton of, like the carrying people with Step of the Wind, it used to be a thing.
DM: You used to only be able to make two attacks not three.
Unknown: It like-
Kenzo: Well, but then also like the different strikes with the different things, that was more interesting.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But...
Delwath: I would say in general some of the mechanics didn't always work out as well as the
Delwath: feeling or inspiration behind them.
Delwath: I mean, like the...
Delwath: I mean, I was just thinking even from this weekend, the mechanic of rolling.
Delwath: I know you have reasons for doing it to give the high skill people-
Unknown: Rolling for the... Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But I felt like sometimes the
Delwath: skill mechanics were a little bit
Delwath: unsatisfying. Like it just didn't...
Delwath: I mean part of it's just a problem with D&D in general.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? But it didn't always, which I feel like you solved by papering over instead of solving.
Delwath: Which works. Papering over problems works well.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: That's paper, papering, papering over.
DM: There's the skill, D&D doesn't have a very robust skill system.
Delwath: Like I felt like a lot of times making skill checks felt a little bit
Delwath: either pointless or
Delwath: not, didn't add a lot to the game.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: Right? And so Tim often solved that by like-
Unknown: [coughs]
Delwath: ... introducing a creative narrative element before the skill check.
Delwath: So like this weekend like-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... the monks like before you make a skill check you tell a story about what you're gonna do.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Which added a lot of enjoyment, but I felt like rolling the die actually didn't really-
DM: Yeah. Well I will say there is, there are times when
DM: I'm trying to set up a scenario where it's like, okay, well if you fail a skill check
DM: it's like the, did the squirrel hear the-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... tree or not?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But you all respond with, "Okay, now we have to try much harder with 17 different other ways to pass the same skill check we failed."
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: That's interesting.
DM: It's like especially with persuasion, like there's always somebody else who can give you the information.
DM: Like if you fail sometimes people just don't wanna talk to you.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But like you were very rarely would just accept that and move on.
Unknown: It was like always
DM: we must be able to convince them so- Like let's, like so then it ends up in this spiral where it's sort of like-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... you keep chasing a dead end.
Wellby: I think also for things that didn't work, I think it worked so much better when you started saying like, "You have 15 minutes," and then we are rolling initiative.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Like that just-
Unknown: Yeah, just time pressure
Wellby: ... very time bound.
Unknown: It's really good for us too.
Wellby: Super helpful.
Seeker: So, so this is a, I don't know exactly what to say about this.
Seeker: Um, there are many entities and elements in Telgar that are like really unique and like contribute to like the tone and feel
Seeker: and style of Telgar, but there are a few things where I'm like, why is this here?
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: uh,
Seeker: I guess it's just especially I'm thinking about werewolves and vampires.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: And maybe a few other things that are like that that felt like they are...
Unknown: Not that they don't belong-
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: ... but that they-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... are just kind of like a-
Unknown: A lot of baggage
Seeker: ... an, an existing archetype plunked down
Seeker: into Telgar without it being made uniquely Telgar.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: And I can understand how that would happen.
Unknown: You're like-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... oh, I just need a new creature type-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... but there's a bunch of existing ones.
Delwath: I, I do think you sometimes from a world build perspective are a little bit committed, overly committed to D&D.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: In that you're like, wow, I wanna find a place for this D&D monster instead of being like, well it just doesn't exist.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? Like I think part of that's just 'cause there's actually a lot of interesting D&D monsters, and also it's hard to home brew stuff.
Delwath: And it's boring to fight the same thing over and over again.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Unless you put a lot of effort into actually making variations on the same thing so it's interesting.
Delwath: So it's very tempting to be like, let's just take more D&D.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah. But like-
Delwath: But I think sometimes there's like a bit of a-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... the world would sometimes benefit from a little bit more exclusion.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: The werewolves worked for me but it felt-
Delwath: But I actually liked the werewolves personally
Wellby: ... it didn't feel like werewolves.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It felt, I don't know, like culty and-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Wellby: ... diseased and-
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Vampire I see where you're going.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Like the vampire did feel a little bit like vampires are a cool villain.
Wellby: Just plumed.
Unknown: Let's plop them in.
Wellby: Just straight down the middle.
Delwath: Although actually I like the way Tim set up the vampires too to be honest.
Delwath: 'Cause it felt like
Seeker: So there was some unique flavor to them that made them more Talgar in each case.
Delwath: Yeah. The werewolves, I mean, maybe it's just because werewolves have come up repeatedly in world building conversations Tim and I have had as like-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... the creatures of Pandemonium and tied into like-
Delwath: ... the planes. And I actually find that very unique as a flavor.
Delwath: Like, werewolves are not traditionally
Unknown: flavored-
Wellby: Extra planar
Delwath: ... as an extra planar.
Unknown: Ah, okay. Okay.
Unknown: Like,
Delwath: so like, I actually really like the Talgar werewolves as this like-
Kenzo: It, it's almost like calling them werewolves, just call them something else.
Unknown: Then, then it's like-
Unknown: Yeah, they probably could use a different name.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right. Because they're not really...
Delwath: I actually envision them as like this like curse from Pandemonium.
Unknown: It's like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... it's a curse.
Delwath: I mean, I like the, like I actually really liked, but I don't know how much of that came up in game versus how much of it ca- But it came up in the game.
Wellby: Some of it came up in the game.
Kenzo: No, I felt, I felt like the werewolves were, like, very unique.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And yeah, like the culty thing-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and the cleanse and all that stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But you just don't have to call them werewolves.
Kenzo: They can just be something else. They're just, you know, whatever.
Unknown: Maybe that was the only problem I had.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I actually was just like, couldn't get past my-
Wellby: Similar with-
Unknown: ... prior knowledge
Wellby: ... the vampire, was it Ivan somebody or rather?
Wellby: Yeah. Like the...
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Well-
Wellby: No, seriously
DM: ... so, so honestly, that was just lazy.
DM: So I used a stat block from this book, Flee Mortals, that has a bunch of,
Unknown: like, named villains.
Unknown: Right, and you just renamed it.
DM: And I just, I was like, I keep, kept thinking I should rename this, I should rename, like-
Delwath: Honestly, the vampires should, you could r- you could even make this work.
Delwath: The vampires should be tied in somehow to the magic that makes Ersk-
Wellby: [coughs]
Delwath: ... its own unique place.
Unknown: And then these like side effects-
Wellby: The side effect of Ersk
Unknown: ... of Ersk.
Wellby: Yeah, I like that
Delwath: Right, like it's true, the vampires did not feel very
Unknown: unique.
DM: But he, I mean, he like what that is basically the story, right?
Wellby: Like he-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But it... That's true. I mean, actually, that was the story of the vampire, but it didn't really...
Delwath: It did feel a little bit like we're going to Ravenloft.
Delwath: Oh, that fey was really cool, and it was a super fun adventure 'cause we dropped the poison troll in the midst of the vampires and like-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: There was actually some fun stuff going on.
Wellby: That was a good time. [laughs] That was a good time.
Unknown: It w- it was, yeah.
DM: Right. It's tough. So a lot of that is like, I actually use bits and pieces of published adventures quite a lot.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: I just like take a room out of somewhere-
Wellby: Yeah
Unknown: ... or something like that.
Seeker: It makes sense. It's like, this is how you do it.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: I use like, I mean, the, the Ash Queen was, that's like another boss from this Flee Mortals book.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Unknown: But like that, the giant
Unknown: centipede thing,
Unknown: surely you made that one up.
Wellby: That was awesome.
DM: Oh, yeah. The, the Chaos Phalanx centipede.
Wellby: Yeah, the Chaos Phalanx centipede.
Wellby: That was, that was fucking awesome.
Unknown: It's like you've never heard of anything like that.
Unknown: It's super interesting.
Wellby: That was so cool.
Seeker: Creates all kinds of interesting like creative problem solving, and like it's an amazing mental image.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Like there's so many things like that, so I don't wanna state that critique about-
DM: Yeah. Yeah. No, no, no. But I know what you're saying, and I think like there is a, there is a sense that Talgar is like stitched together from some things that I spend a lot of time
DM: crafting, and some things that I grab 15 minutes before the session starts and stick them in just from how they're grabbed.
Wellby: To your credit though, like it's hard from this side of the table to
Wellby: see a lot of, most of the time, to see the difference between that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It feels seamless.
DM: I, but I think what Eric, I think I see Eric's point that I, I mean, I actually dis- the like, the kanthrops, that was all completely, like I made that up quite early on because
Unknown: I originally intended-
Wellby: We do that first, right?
DM: ... that you would go to Toba first.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Right. Right, right.
DM: And do the va- do the, do the cult, and the cult had traded the scepter of command to-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... Agata, so you would learn that they had the scepter of command and traded it,
DM: and then go to Agata, and then from Agata learn that Grash was out there looking for stuff, right?
DM: You did it in the exact opposite order.
Wellby: We opted to be more efficient with our gas miles.
Unknown: Exactly.
Kenzo: Yeah. That's totally, I mean, it's, uh-
DM: But yeah, the, I mean, the vampire thing, like there are times of that, and it's nice that you can't always tell, but sometimes it does, it i- it does co- like it is apparent that there's
DM: things I just, I didn't have time to completely re-flavor.
Delwath: But I don't know, I was thinking of like kobolds.
Delwath: I mean, kobolds are kind of a cool race, but like we actually never encountered them in this game, right?
Delwath: But we heard rumors of them.
Delwath: But they're kind of like, do they need to exist?
DM: I mean, they do now. We've used them in other games, but
Unknown: that's-
DM: Yeah. I, I used them a lot in Isaac's game, and Isaac and his friends really liked them.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Hm.
Unknown: So they're a big part of that game.
DM: Yeah, I mean, not everything has to exist.
Unknown: It's just,
Unknown: I don't know.
Wellby: I, at a certain point, I exceeded my ability to keep track of the NPCs on Vindasharna.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But Tim, Tim and I talked about that.
Unknown: I was like-
Wellby: And I, I know, and they were all listed, and I would go back and I would read them every few sessions, and I just, I couldn't make them stick in my brain.
Unknown: Well...
Unknown: Same. Yeah. It's...
Wellby: Which isn't like a, a bad thing.
Wellby: It just...
Wellby: Like we had a, like the relationship with Faldrik was so fun.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Like he was such like a clear personality.
DM: You know what? The thing that didn't quite work, so,
DM: so Kong and Kate both had like apprentices.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: So I think had some-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... like Amal and, and Kathra-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... like Kate's.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But the other ones were sort of supposed to be other people's apprentices.
Wellby: I mean, I remember feeling-
Unknown: But ended up-
Wellby: ... Kathra was a person?
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Well, but, but-
Unknown: Is that-
DM: But it wasn't sp- you weren't supposed to know, you weren't supposed to care about Kathra, right?
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: It was the, what a original vibe was supposed to be like, there was like Faldrik, who was like, I guess originally like with Seeker, but like basically was the main personality.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: And then other peop- everybody could have like one or two.
Wellby: Yeah. That makes sense.
DM: But some of them just didn't land, right?
Unknown: Like-
Kenzo: The elven, the elven gardener
DM: ... the elven gardener and the,
DM: and the Dennerkai
Unknown: Didn't, yeah
DM: Never really
Kenzo: Oh, there was a Dennerkai?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I totally forgot about that.
Unknown: Yeah, but we totally forgot about it.
Wellby: There were so many people.
Unknown: It, it kind of makes sense that you-
DM: There were a lot
Unknown: ... [laughs]
Unknown: We picked up a whole crew.
Unknown: We collectively-
Unknown: It was cool
Seeker: ... try stuff, and then some things kind of like-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Are...
DM: But, but I liked Amal.
Unknown: Amal was great.
DM: I think Amal was great. And Kate, like Kathra.
Delwath: Yeah. But Faldric also took up a lot of the creative
Delwath: space. Like, Faldric was a compelling enough character that I feel like we just kept going back to Faldric as the-
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Well, 'cause Faldric-
Unknown: 'Cause he was real fun.
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... Faldric just worked.
Unknown: Right?
Wellby: He was just like... I, I feel like- If, if we have 20 minutes of NPC interaction in a given session, like-
DM: As we had, yeah
Unknown: It's kind of-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... we, I think we just kept...
Delwath: Which is fine. It was enjoyable.
Delwath: I mean, we were all enjoying Faldric, so like why...
Delwath: And it's not like we were spending-
DM: Right. But you also, you, you guys like going to new pl- at least in this campaign, you really like going to new places, so you very rarely revisited NPCs.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Oh, yeah, yeah.
DM: So you wouldn't come back. Like in Mike's game, they're like based in a town.
Unknown: So there's lots of interaction there.
DM: And they like constantly go back to the same town.
Wellby: Oh, interesting. Interesting.
DM: Right? And so even if you only interact with the NPCs for 10 minutes in a game, once you do that in 15 sessions, like that's a lot of interaction.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Right. Where I remember like going back to Chardin was like, "Oh my God, we're going back?"
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: "To Chardin? We know people there."
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: Well, the other thing with Faldric too is I think Faldric hit like a certain archetype that I've realized about our
Kenzo: characters or our, our, the way...
Kenzo: Like, we need like that like sarcastic, irreverent...
Kenzo: It's like the Dimitar of like-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Yeah
Kenzo: ... of this campaign was Faldric.
Kenzo: Like, that was like the NPC who was just this like funny, like, you know, like just doing weird, like crazy shit.
Kenzo: And like it was kinda like, you know, comedic, like, but also, you know, really funny and, you know.
Kenzo: Like we need that to like balance out the serious, like we're trying to save the world-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... energy, you know?
DM: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Okay. Well, Ladder served that role a little bit.
Kenzo: Ladder also was that.
Delwath: Ladder did serve that role quite a lot.
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
DM: Ladder.
Wellby: Ladder was great.
Kenzo: Ladder was super great. But also Baxter, shouts to Baxter.
Wellby: Yeah, early on Baxter was big.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, Bax-
Unknown: What did it with Baxter over time, though?
Unknown: Why was that?
Unknown: I guess-
DM: It become-
Wellby: It's hard to start getting attached
Unknown: ... it's just too, too, you're too powerful
DM: ... he di-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... like no, 'cause Bax, he was just too-
Wellby: He had like 20 hit points or something, like.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And once you can fly, it's really like-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: Exactly.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know, if you, if you had, uh, if you had really wrangled a fly, that could've been a cool, you know.
Unknown: Let's
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... I think, I actually think when we re- when we meet Wellby again for the-
Unknown: Yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... Wellby's getting ride to fly
Unknown: ... Wellby will have a fly.
Kenzo: For the, for the Francar arc, Wellby's gonna be riding a fly.
Kenzo: Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Let's... Yeah.
Seeker: That makes a lot of sense.
Delwath: I mean, we have a bond with stone animals, right?
Delwath: The triceratops.
Wellby: I wonder if there's some way to like make Baxter an obsidian Baxter someday.
DM: Oh, you totally could.
Unknown: Oh, obsidian Baxter.
DM: Totally.
Unknown: Oh, my God.
DM: That would be awesome.
Kenzo: Obsidian Baxter.
Seeker: Just come talk to us on the circular island.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Dimitar will only charge you 12,000 gold a day.
Kenzo: But then just charge Dimitar [laughs]
Wellby: Exactly. Exactly.
Unknown: 1,300 gold for-
Wellby: My consulting fee.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right.
Seeker: His accountants are not very good.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: They did figure out that 200 minus 100 was 100, not 300.
DM: To give them some credit.
Unknown: It took four of them. [laughs]
DM: It took four of them.
Wellby: Three is bigger than two.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But we'll be all right.
Unknown: Look at this fish.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Huh.
Unknown: Obsidian Baxter.
Kenzo: Would Obsidian Baxter would be powerful
Unknown: or just made out of obsidian?
DM: It would just couldn't die.
Delwath: No, no, it just couldn't die.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
Wellby: I think that's just to sort of have like the, the set of different animals to be used in different circumstances.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Right. And that... Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, you rode the wyvern for a little while?
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That was cool.
Wellby: Obsidian wyvern.
Wellby: I like the, like the cowardly wyvern dynamic there, though.
Wellby: That was fun.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: I mean, I do like this, the like going back to the same, like have, like really having a home base kind of vibe.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: So this is the thing. Tolan was kind of our home base, but I don't think we actually had that type of NPC, like check back in with the-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like that didn't really happen. You know, even though we knew some people, we didn't-
DM: Well, you did... The first time that we went to Tolan, we spent a ton of time interacting with NPCs.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: But we didn't, but then-
DM: But then when you went...
DM: You never went back. You went back to Tolan for like extended downtime, but not for any sessions after that.
Delwath: But what I've also found is for like to develop relationships with NPCs, it works better if you're interacting with the NPC
Delwath: every session or every other session.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Not like checking, 'cause you sort of lose track.
Unknown: Exactly.
Unknown: Like even in, in my game-
Kenzo: Exactly. Totally. Exactly
Delwath: ... I've had, I probably have 50 NPCs that I've made up in the town that the PCs are based in.
Delwath: But even though they meet NP- the same 50 NPCs, we've played 25 sessions, there's like six of them or eight of them that they actually know and c- like, and it's random.
Delwath: It's the whatever ones they connected with.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? But so I tossed out 40 NPCs, and each of the players is connected with one or two of them.
Delwath: So then they check back in.
Delwath: They're like, "How are these guys doing?"
DM: Right.
Delwath: Like it, it sort of turns into kind of these characters that...
Delwath: But it actually works better if that's like an opportunity almost every session-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... to connect with your various NPCs.
Delwath: And they're reacting to the events in the world.
Kenzo: Well, but, but also that the NPCs actually have like some type of what, even limited like functional role.
Kenzo: 'Cause like Faldric was flying the ship.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: So we always were like, "Oh, fuck.
Kenzo: Fuck. Where'd, where did Faldric take the ship?"
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: So it was like, it was always kind of like Faldric had that role.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know? So there was like a reason why we'd be...
Kenzo: 'Cause like you wouldn't go back to the town just to like check in on the tattoo artist just to check in.
Kenzo: It's like, oh, fuck, like we want Darkseid now in the tattoo, so now it's-
Delwath: Well, but if you live in Tolan, you might start, uh, you might end a session or start a session with, like if the structure of the game is like you're based
Delwath: in- ... Tolan-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... and you are tracking down some necromantic guild, but you're, every session takes place in Tolan.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: You're much more likely to be like, "Oh, well, I'm gonna develop a relationship with this tattoo artist and check in with her frequently about-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... various contexts in Tolan."
Delwath: Right? Even if it's not, it's just a more of an opportunity for-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... um, like one of the,
Delwath: one of the NPCs in my other game is like, uh, the temple administrator of-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... the little, the temple, and like, there's constantly reasons to be checking in with her, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... like she's not powerful or that important, but like she's a little bit of hub of gossip and it's like-
Delwath: ... it's constantly sort of an opportunity to be like, "Oh, let's go check with Elmore about..."
Kenzo: I have one. Philosopher's Guild, I think if there were like a clear spokesperson that we were interacting with more, and I think there was one, but that could, that was an opportunity where, 'cause like we were going back for research-
DM: Sorry, Delia was the sage was how you met the philosopher-
Unknown: Right
DM: What I actually loved the Philosopher's Guild was just a-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... super mysterious.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I love that too.
Kenzo: I love that too. I love that too.
DM: Yeah. So fun.
Kenzo: But, but my point, but you know what I said, but like that was like we were, that was like a thing where we were constantly checking back.
Kenzo: So even if there were like a weird interface or like a thing where it's just like every time you wanna interact with the Philosopher Guild, like you send a thing and then they just send back like, like a five color, like a thing that's like...
Kenzo: Or, or whatever, you know?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Then it's like, oh shit. Like, you're, you get excited to interact with it because there's some kind of a, you know-
Delwath: I think just the structure of the, the structure of the campaign made it hard to develop too many-
DM: Yeah, 'cause we were always..
Delwath: Yeah. 'Cause we were always...
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: And I actually think
Delwath: that Vindrasharna probably would've worked better if there had been like
DM: only three or four named NPCs.
DM: Yeah.
DM: But you guys kept like wanting to collect people.
DM: Yeah, we collected.
Delwath: We... No, I know.
DM: I mean, that is on us.
Delwath: There's, there's, there's absolut- And actually Tim at one point said, "You can't keep making up NPCs.
Delwath: There's too many. Nobody's gonna remember them."
Seeker: And he was right. [laughs]
Delwath: That's not what I mean. [laughs] Um, but it, it's tricky because what's nice about a town is you can have 20 NPCs and you can naturally
Delwath: which, what, whichever ones are interesting be the ones that you keep-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... developing. With, with Vindrasharna, it's like-
Kenzo: They're all traveling with us, yeah
Delwath: ... it's too big and too small at the same time.
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Right? Like, it doesn't make sense for there to be 50 people in Vindrasharna, of which we only know five of them well.
Delwath: But it's hard to make up the five that we'd be interested in upfront-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... 'cause you might just guess wrong about who's gonna connect with the party.
DM: Well, that's kind of what happened, right, is like some NPCs-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... people connected with, some people didn't, and it just, it's how it happened.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's fine.
Kenzo: I remember there was this one stretch where we were like super fucking stoked about trying to design Vindrasharna.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And figure out what rooms they were in and blah, blah, blah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: You know?
DM: That was like right after you got it.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. 'Cause like, so this, here's another like, that's kind of fun.
Kenzo: It's like, it's like obviously we were very plot motivated here, so there was a lot of just like shit that we had to do that felt really urgent.
Kenzo: But in a more laid back, more one shotty version where we're just like, like if there were some stretch where we were actually just like living on Vindrasharna and just like having...
Kenzo: If, if this were like an episodic TV show-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... you know what I mean?
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Then it would be like you could actually develop Vindrasharna more, so it's like, oh, we're all hanging out in the plastic ball pit room that we like do whatever in, you know?
Delwath: Part of the challenge is that stuff doesn't necessarily make for a super compelling game session.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: It's like in the abstract it's really fun to think, oh, it'd be cool to like develop Vindrasharna more, but like in the moment, do you really wanna...
Delwath: Is that really what you wanna spend the whole game session doing?
Kenzo: Right. Right.
Delwath: Because it's not necessarily that...
Delwath: It's, it's more asynchronous abstract.
Kenzo: Y- you know what that is? Developing Vindrasharna is like the digital version of us, like, of like Schwartz like building that.
Kenzo: It's just like, it's just like a fun thing that you wanna have fleshed out-
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... but you don't necessarily like need it in the game.
Unknown: It, it works-
Unknown: Like actively, you know?
Delwath: ... much better in groups that have more, that commit more, that just have more time-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... outside. Like, like I gave my other group a, the, they, they have a bastion now at, they're only eighth level, but they have a bastion, which is one of the towns, and like one of my players has like
Delwath: gone crazy with it and is like mapping out the whole town.
Delwath: He just sent me an email yesterday like where he, he's, um,
Delwath: he has access to a CAD program, so he like made the walls of the town and-
Unknown: Oh my God.
DM: There's 3D modeling? Nice.
Delwath: Doing 3D models and like sketching out.
Delwath: They need to, they need money so they can build stone walls, so they're building wooden walls right now, but he's designing it so they can put in stone walls in the future.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. I love that.
Delwath: And like, but you have to have time to do that.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Exactly.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: Exactly.
Delwath: And like we could have done stuff like that with Vindrasharna, we just didn't I think.
Unknown: Yeah. We were just-
Delwath: None of us are like-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... have the-
Delwath: ... time really to spend on that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
DM: Well,
DM: none of them.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: But-
DM: They spend play... But not on that, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Mike and I always know when each other has slow days at work because our Town Guard Discord chat goes crazy.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: That's awesome.
Kenzo: That's great. That's super great.
DM: But I'm, I mean, I'm, I,
DM: I'm like totally happy with the sort of...
DM: I don't, I think that stuff...
DM: I don't think it actually made any difference to how Vindrasharna felt when-
Unknown: No. No, no
DM: ... at the table that you-
Unknown: Not at all. No
DM: ... nobody bothered to design it out in detail.
Delwath: No, no, no. No, Vindrasharna became very, it, it became-
DM: Although I will say-
Unknown: ... iconic
DM: ... this weekend nobody was really drawing anything 'cause we're all like playing with Legos.
DM: But
DM: in one of the past weekends when-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... I forget who-
Wellby: Yeah, that was really fun. A few, like...
Unknown: No, but this was like-
Unknown: On the cape
DM: ... on the cape run.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Or maybe it was in New Hampshire, like-
Kenzo: Cape I remember drawing a lot.
Delwath: But when were you... Somebody was drawing a lot of art of Vindrasharna.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: With the tree
Unknown: Yeah, I, I drew some cool stuff.
Unknown: I drew-
DM: Eric, I think, drew some stuff.
Kenzo: Well, but Eric also this, this whole session, you should see all the f-
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Eric's made a fucking shit ton of sick like Midjourney art.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Th- this whole weekend it's been like-
Delwath: That Lego one, that was really impressive.
Unknown: That was really impressive.
Unknown: That was crazy.
DM: That was just cool, right?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Eric, you always do that.
Unknown: Eric, you always do that, yeah.
Wellby: I love Lego, Lego. I love these mini figs.
Delwath: You need to make a like Lego AI.
Kenzo: Schwartz, yeah, shout outs for the mini figs.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: The mini figs, this was so fun.
DM: Yeah, that was really fun.
Unknown: That would be, that'd be cool.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: We need a like-
Unknown: Lego Talgar
DM: ... we need an art book for this campaign.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Kenzo's staff has to get slightly bigger.
DM: [laughs] And like-
Kenzo: More unhinged.
Unknown: Kenzo's staff, more unhinged.
DM: More unhinged. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But like, you know, subtly. Like you gotta pretend from the shot like it's not getting bigger.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: What time do we need to get up tomorrow?
Unknown: It is nice weather.
DM: Um, so-
Delwath: 12:30, 12. We need to leave the house at like 1:45.
DM: We need to get a cab.
Delwath: We need to get a cab. We probably need to leave the house at like 11:45.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: We need to clean up.
DM: The main thing, the main thing that-
Unknown: Laundry
DM: ... will take time is we need to wash the sheets, which means people need to be out of bed-
Unknown: Yeah. Right
DM: ... in time for us to-
Delwath: We need to wash the sheets, dry the sheets, and put the sheets back on the bed.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: What, what time does that mean we need to be up by?
Unknown: Like...
DM: 8:30?
Delwath: 8- well, one, the first lo- we can do two loads.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: The first-
Delwath: My mom said it was okay if we left one set of sheets in the dryer.
Kenzo: Like if we left half the sheets in the dryer,
Delwath: as long as half the sheets were made back on the bed.
DM: Cool.
Delwath: So like, I don't know, 8:30-ish,
Delwath: but it's probably okay if it's a little later than that.
DM: Well, it'll take...
DM: Yeah, it'll take like two hours to do a wash and a dry if we do the quick wash.
DM: Yeah. So 8:30, that's 10:30.
DM: So if some people can get up at 8:30 and just immediately strip the sheets and like toss them down the stairs.
Kenzo: Who's been waking up early? I know I'm the last one.
Seeker: I, it was so weird, I slept until 9:00 today, which is kind of bad because I need to go back-
DM: [coughs]
Seeker: ... immediately to getting up at 6:00 with [laughs] Monday, so.
DM: Yeah,
DM: well, yeah.
Delwath: Um, I mean, I'll be up by 8:00.
Unknown: Need to do that.
Delwath: I, well, I got, I slept till like 8:30 this morning, but I-
DM: I slept till 9:15 this morning, but I'm gonna, I'll set an alarm for 8:00.
DM: I'll be up.
Unknown: Yeah, I'll do that.
DM: I'll be up. I, I'll deal with some cleanup.
DM: Like we don't need to do any of this tonight.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: I'll deal with some of the cleanup there, and one of us needs to go to the dump.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: How late were you, how have you been getting up?
Wellby: I got up early on Friday.
Wellby: I got up at 10:30 today.
Unknown: That's great.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Yeah. I mean, I really wanna fall asleep.
Kenzo: I've just been like, I've been sleeping for like an hour, and then like waking up, and then just being awake for like two hours, three hours, and then falling back asleep.
Kenzo: It's been very frustrating. I'm gonna sleep out there.
Delwath: Wait, you were in Europe before this, and then you're going back to Europe?
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, I was in California and then Europe.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: I flew from fucking California to Europe, and then to here, and now back to Europe tomorrow.
Kenzo: I fly to Paris tomorrow.
DM: Yeah. That's rough.
Kenzo: I'm, I fucking am so tired.
DM: Do you wanna...
DM: These always put me to sleep.
Unknown: Ooh. Do you want-
DM: Like can- like CBD cannabis.
DM: The C... When it's not CBD, it's the one that makes you fall asleep.
Unknown: CBG.
DM: CBG.
Unknown: Sure.
Unknown: CBG.
Kenzo: How many, how many did you take? Take one of these?
DM: I usually do one or two.
DM: I don't know. How many do you have? I want one.
DM: How many are left?
Unknown: There's three in here.
DM: Okay. You can have two if you want them.
Unknown: You sure?
DM: Yeah. I just need one.
Unknown: All right. Thank you.
Kenzo: Give this a shot. [bottle clinking]
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: So are we doing the like prison thing next?
DM: I think we should do that.
Unknown: I love it.
Unknown: Why not?
DM: Um, we can...
DM: I don't wanna get up like-
Unknown: We can schedule tomorrow
DM: ... I don't wanna get up tomorrow.
Unknown: We can schedule tomorrow.
Seeker: But it's the, the Underdark prison thing?
Delwath: Well, I'm thinking
Delwath: far north of Sambara,
Delwath: icy mountains.
Delwath: Still in mountains, not necessarily all the way in the Underdark.
Unknown: All right. All right.
Delwath: Right? Something in like the cold northern vibe.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Beyond the Great Wall?
Unknown: Ice cave situation.
DM: Hmm?
Unknown: Beyond the Great Wall?
DM: No.
Unknown: But what is beyond the Great Wall?
DM: West of the Great Wall.
Kenzo: There's a great wall.
DM: Yeah, there's a great wall up there.
Kenzo: Is this like GoT?
Unknown: There's a great, we have a great wall.
Delwath: Yeah, it was inven- it was created during Vim- no, no, it's always been there.
Delwath: It was rediscovered during Vimfr- no, wait.
Delwath: What was the story with the Great Wall? Anyway, I don't want to touch the Great Wall.
DM: Tim has some idea about the Great Wall.
DM: It's... The, the Great Wall pre d- I made it up before,
Unknown: what's his name? Who wrote...
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, it's-
Wellby: George RR Martin. Yeah.
Delwath: Tim made it up in like 1993.
DM: I made it up in like 1992.
DM: I just drew a huge wall on a map in Talgar, and I was like, "There's some great wall up here."
DM: Cool.
DM: And it sort of drifted around a little bit in the lore, but, um, it played a prominent role in the war that wa- so there was the drag- there was that
DM: dragon, Vimfrost, that...
DM: Remember the Frost Giant arc where the-
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... there had been a dragon that died like a 150 years ago, and then the spawn of that dragon were like taking over the north, and so the giant was, um...
Delwath: Here, the map doesn't come up well on my phone.
Unknown: Uh, here we go.
Delwath: [clears throat] So like up here.
Delwath: Oh, you know what? Aha.
Delwath: That's what I'm gonna do. You have no idea where that is, right?
Unknown: Oh, we're all in there. Oh my God.
Unknown: No. There. It's gonna be there.
Unknown: Did you photograph that yet?
Delwath: There is a giant crevice-
DM: No, I'll do it in the morning
Delwath: ... in the map of Talgar that Tim has no idea where, where-
Seeker: We need those. What?
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: Sounds cool.
Delwath: It's gonna be something in this crevice.
Unknown: A crevasse?
Delwath: Yeah, like a huge, like a Grand Canyon ty- type thing.
Seeker: Oh my God. It's, but it's like many miles deep or somewhere in there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, north, it's in like the northern Sambara like...
Seeker: This sounds good.
DM: So like fifth or sixth level?
Unknown: Sixth level.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Then it will be a bard. [door squeaking] [door closing]
Delwath: And we'll have to come up in session zero with why you-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... why you are... I'll, I'll come up with a little bit of background, but why-
DM: Oh, I gotta talk to Kate about if, what she wants to do.
Delwath: Oh, yeah. Does she wanna play?
DM: I don't know. I think she has sort of mixed feelings about
DM: what she wants to do next.
DM: I mean, it's a little tricky to always be trying to like write her in and out of a campaign.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Right?
Kenzo: Well, these are just like kind of one-shotty, like four-session or three-session.
Unknown: Well, these are easy for Kate to play in.
Delwath: Yeah. These are easy if she wants to play with you.
Wellby: I feel like you did it really elegantly through this campaign, though.
Wellby: Like, it felt like there's sort of natural reasons to come in and out.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, I know. I think it, um,
DM: she, she, I mean, she definitely doesn't wanna play in a full five-year campaign.
DM: She doesn't wanna commit to a full five-year campaign.
Unknown: Yeah. Mm.
DM: Although I'll discuss. Maybe she's changed her mind.
DM: She just doesn't like staying up.
Delwath: Yeah, I know. 'Cause she is wise instead of foolish.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] True. True. True.
Delwath: I mean, I don't really like staying up either, I just like playing D&D till dark.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um.
Wellby: Oh, speaking of that.
Delwath: Yeah, I think it's time for bed.
DM: I think that's a good place to end.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. I mean,
DM: yeah